<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>


    <!--Canoptek-->

    <string name="obelisk_node_control_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="obelisk_node_control_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever this operative would perform a mission action (excluding **Retrieve**, Approved Ops 2025), if it
requires this operative to control an objective marker, you can instead determine control from one of
your **OBELISK NODE** markers (see Obelisk Node Matrix faction rule). Whenever this operative would
perform the **Operate Hatch** action, you can open or close a hatchway thats access point is within 1\"
of one of your **OBELISK NODE** markers instead. Note that you must still fulfil the **Operate
Hatch** actions conditions.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="geomantic_disturbance_usage"><![CDATA[
        1AP
    ]]></string>

    <string name="geomantic_disturbance_description"><![CDATA[
Select a point on a terrain feature; that point must be visible
to and within 8\" of this operative. Separately roll 2D6 for
each operative within 2\" of that point. If the result is higher
than that operatives remaining wounds, inflict damage on it equal to the difference.\n\n

This operative cannot perform this action while it has a Conceal order, or while within control range of an enemy operative.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="canoptek_control_usage"><![CDATA[
        1AP
    ]]></string>

    <string name="canoptek_control_description"><![CDATA[
**SUPPORT**. Select one friendly **CANOPTEK CIRCLE
CANOPTEK** operative visible to and within 6\" of this
operative. Alternatively, you can select one friendly
**CANOPTEK CIRCLE CANOPTEK** operative that is
visible to this operative and within your **OBELISK NODE
MATRIX** (**SUPPORT** does not apply to this selection). That
selected operative can immediately perform a 1AP action
for free; it cannot move more than or be removed and set up
more than 2\" during that action.\n\n

This operative cannot perform this action while within control range of an enemy operative, or while counteracting.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="molecular_breach_usage"><![CDATA[
            1AP
    ]]></string>

    <string name="molecular_breach_description"><![CDATA[
**SUPPORT**. Select one friendly **CANOPTEK CIRCLE**
operative visible to and within 6\" of this operative.
Alternatively, you can select one friendly **CANOPTEK CIRCLE** operative visible to this operative
and within your **OBELISK NODE MATRIX** (**SUPPORT** does not apply to this selection).\n
\n
-The next time the selected operative performs an action in
which it moves, do not move it. Instead, remove it from the
killzone and set it back up wholly within a distance equal
to its Move stat (or 3\" if it was a **Dash**) horizontally of its
original location (in a killzone that uses the close quarters
rules, e.g. Killzone: Tomb World, this distance can be
measured over and through Wall terrain and the operative
can be set up on the other side). Note that it gains no
additional distance when performing the **Charge** action. It
must be set up in a location it can be placed, and unless it is
the **Charge** action, it cannot be set up within control range
of an enemy operative\n\n

This operative cannot perform this action while within control range of an enemy operative.
    ]]></string>


    <string name="overcharge_usage"><![CDATA[
        1AP
    ]]></string>

    <string name="overcharge_description"><![CDATA[
Select one other friendly **CANOPTEK CIRCLE CANOPTEK** operative visible to and within 3\" of this
operative. Alternatively, if this operative is within your
**OBELISK NODE MATRIX**, you can select one other
friendly **CANOPTEK CIRCLE CANOPTEK** operative
within your **OBELISK NODE MATRIX**. Until the end
of that selected operative’s next activation, add 1 to its APL stat.\n\n

This operative cannot perform this action while within control range of an enemy operative.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="cranial_overload_usage"><![CDATA[
        1AP
    ]]></string>

    <string name="cranial_overload_description"><![CDATA[
Select one enemy operative visible to and within 3\" of
this operative. Alternatively, if this operative is within your
**OBELISK NODE MATRIX**, you can select one enemy
operative within your **OBELISK NODE MATRIX**. Until
the end of that enemy operative’s next activation, subtract 1 from its APL stat.\n\n

This operative cannot perform this action while within control range of an enemy operative.
    ]]></string>


    <string name="reanimate_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="reanimate_description"><![CDATA[
Once per turning point, when another friendly **CANOPTEK CIRCLE** operative would be incapacitated,
if that operative is visible to and within 6\" of this operative, or
if this and that operative are within your **OBELISK NODE MATRIX**, you can use this rule, providing
neither this nor that operative is within control range of an enemy operative. If you
do, that friendly operative is not incapacitated, has 1 wound
remaining and cannot be incapacitated for the remainder of the
action. After that action, that friendly operative can immediately
perform a free **Dash** action, but must end that action within
this operatives control range or within your **OBELISK NODE MATRIX**.
Subtract 1 from this and that operatives APL stats until the end of their next activations respectively, and if this
rule was used during that friendly operatives activation, that
activation ends. You cannot use this rule if this operative is
incapacitated, or if it is a **Shoot** action and this operative would
be a primary or secondary target.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="nanoscarab_beam_usage"><![CDATA[
        1AP
    ]]></string>

    <string name="nanoscarab_beam_description"><![CDATA[
Select one friendly **CANOPTEK CIRCLE** operative
visible to and within 6\" of this operative. Alternatively, if this
operative is within your **OBELISK NODE MATRIX**, you
can select one other friendly **CANOPTEK CIRCLE**
operative within your **OBELISK NODE MATRIX**. The
selected operative regains up to 3D3 lost wounds. It cannot
be an operative that the Reanimate rule was used on during
this turning point.\n\n

This operative cannot perform this action while within
control range of an enemy operative, or more than once per turning point.
    ]]></string>


    <string name="aggressive_defence_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="aggressive_defence_description"><![CDATA[
If this operative is incapacitated by an enemy operative within 2\" of it, before this operative is removed
from the killzone, roll one D3: on a 2+, inflict 1 damage on that enemy operative.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="expendable_construct_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="expendable_construct_description"><![CDATA[
This operative is ignored for your opponents kill/elimination op (when it’s incapacitated, and when
determining your starting number of operatives). It is also ignored
for victory conditions and scoring VPs if either require operatives
to \‘escape\’, \‘survive\’ or be incapacitated by enemy operatives
(if it escapes/survives/is incapacitated, determining how many
operatives must escape/survive/be incapacitated, etc.).
    ]]></string>


    <string name="a_ceaseless_scuttling_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="a_ceaseless_scuttling_description"><![CDATA[
As a **STRATEGIC GAMBIT** in each turning point after the first, if you have less than three
non-incapacitated friendly **CANOPTEK CIRCLE WARRIOR**
operatives, you can set up another one ready and with a Conceal
order wholly within your drop zone (you can select its weapon options as normal).
    ]]></string>

    <string name="dimensional_banishment_usage"><![CDATA[
        Special Weapon Rule
    ]]></string>

    <string name="dimensional_banishment_description"><![CDATA[
After this operative uses this weapon, if you inflicted damage or retained any critical successes, if the
target was not incapacitated, roll 2D6: if the result is higher than the targets remaining wounds, the target is incapacitated (taking
precedence over rules that prevent incapacitation, e.g. Medic!, **FELLGOR RAVAGER** Frenzy) and your opponent cannot place a
Reanimation marker (**HIEROTEK CIRCLE**) for that operative, if relevant.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="weapon_sentinel_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="weapon_sentinel_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever your opponent is selecting a
valid target, if this operative has a Conceal order, it cannot use
Light terrain for cover. While this can allow this operative to be
targeted (assuming it is visible), it does not remove its cover save (if any).
    ]]></string>

    <string name="canoptek_steadfast_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="canoptek_steadfast_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever determining control of a marker, you
can treat this operative’s APL stat as 3. If you do, this takes
precedence over all other rules, meaning any changes to its APL
stat are ignored for this
    ]]></string>


    <!--Faction Rules-->

    <string name="obelisk_node_matrix_lore"><![CDATA[
Obelisk nodes are concentrations of Necron technology,
hubs of energy and data streams. Whether raised
up from their sites of ancient burial, formed from
restructured local matter or phased into place from a
pocket dimension, these angular nodes can empower
a Cryptek and their servants. Impelled into positions
where they can connect in a matrix of power, they aid
the Crypteks ambitions whilst hampering their foes.
]]></string>

    <string name="obelisk_node_matrix_description"><![CDATA[
As a **STRATEGIC GAMBIT** in the first turning point,
place your three **OBELISK NODE** markers wholly
within your territory. As a **STRATEGIC GAMBIT**
in each turning point after the first, you can
move each of your **OBELISK NODE** markers up to 3\" horizontally.\n
\n
Your **OBELISK NODE** markers control other
markers within 1\" of them that no enemy
operatives contest (treat your **OBELISK NODE**
markers as friendly operatives for this purpose).
If more than one player would use their **OBELISK NODE** markers to control the same marker, no
**OBELISK NODE** markers control it.\n
\n
Whenever one of your **OBELISK NODE** markers is
within 6\" horizontally of another of your **OBELISK NODE** markers, those markers and the area
between them create an **OBELISK NODE MATRIX**
above and below (in other words, their height
in the killzone is irrelevant). If all three of your
**OBELISK NODE** markers fulfil this, it creates a larger combined **OBELISK NODE MATRIX**.\n
\n
Whenever a friendly **CANOPTEK CIRCLE** operative is within your **OBELISK NODE MATRIX**:\n
\n
• Weapons on its datacard have the Accurate 1 weapon rule.\n
\n
• Add 1 to its APL stat (to a maximum of 3).
]]></string>

    <!--Equipment-->

    <string name="matrix_manipulator_lore"><![CDATA[
With a flick of their digits, a skilled Geomancer can use
this enhanced geomantic manipulator as a surrogate obelisk node to extend the matrix.
]]></string>

    <string name="matrix_manipulator_description"><![CDATA[
Once per battle, during a friendly **CANOPTEK CIRCLE** operatives activation or counteraction,
you can use this rule. If you do, until the end of that activation/counteraction, a friendly
**CANOPTEK CIRCLE GEOMANCER** operative is treated as your fourth **OBELISK NODE** marker.
]]></string>

    <string name="awakened_obelisk_nodes_lore"><![CDATA[
Seeded into place and activated long ago, these obelisk
nodes have absorbed huge stores of local data, ready to
gift their controller with a superior edge when the time is right.
]]></string>

    <string name="awakened_obelisk_nodes_description"><![CDATA[
After revealing this equipment option, roll one D3.
You can use the Animate Obelisk Nodes firefight
ploy for 0CP a number of times during the battle
equal to the result.
]]></string>

    <string name="nanoscarab_caskets_lore"><![CDATA[
These small devices appear to release wisps of spectral
vapour. In truth, they are clouds of tiny repair constructs
that seal rents in living metal.
]]></string>

    <string name="nanoscarab_caskets_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever a friendly **CANOPTEK CIRCLE** operative is activated, it regains up to D3 lost wounds.
]]></string>

    <string name="phase_shifter_lore"><![CDATA[
The bearers form flits between dimensions like a
phantom, rendering it exceedingly difficult to land a telling blow upon them.
]]></string>

    <string name="phase_shifter_description"><![CDATA[
Once per turning point, when an operative is shooting a friendly **CANOPTEK CIRCLE GEOMANCER **operative, at the start of the Roll
Defence Dice step, you can use this rule. If you
do, worsen the x of the Piercing weapon rule by 1
(if any) until the end of that sequence. Note that
Piercing 1 would therefore be ignored.
]]></string>



    <!--Ploys-->
    <!--Strategy ploys-->
    <string name="hypershielding_lore"><![CDATA[
Quantum energies radiate from the matrix, triggered
by warding protocols. The haze consumes solid shot in
bursts of viridian light and refracts energy blasts, while
its wavering veil confounds targeters.
]]></string>

    <string name="hypershielding_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever an operative is shooting a friendly
**CANOPTEK CIRCLE** operative, if your **OBELISK NODE MATRIX** is intervening, or that friendly
operative is within your **OBELISK NODE MATRIX**,
you can re-roll any of your defence dice results of
one result (e.g. results of 2).
]]></string>

    <string name="transdynamic_amplification_lore"><![CDATA[
Curving into arcane lenses that compress slivers of
reality, the shimmering matrix magnifies the potency of
the Necrons horrifying energistic technologies.
]]></string>

    <string name="transdynamic_amplification_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever a friendly **CANOPTEK CIRCLE**
operative is shooting, if your **OBELISK NODE MATRIX** is intervening, or the target is within your
**OBELISK NODE MATRIX**, that friendly operatives weapons have the Ceaseless weapon rule.
]]></string>

    <string name="cryptogravitic_repulsion_lore"><![CDATA[
The universes fundamental forces have long been
mastered by the Necrons. As their foes advance,
thudding waves and twisting eddies of gravity amongst
the obelisk nodes repel potential trespassers.
]]></string>

    <string name="cryptogravitic_repulsion_description"><![CDATA[
Once per action, the first time an enemy
operative would move within your **OBELISK NODE MATRIX**, the distance is treated as an additional
1\". Note this means if that enemy operative
does not have sufficient move distance (e.g. it’s at the end of its move), that operative cannot move
within your **OBELISK NODE MATRIX.**
]]></string>

    <string name="souldrain_lore"><![CDATA[
A lifeless chill creeps into the hearts of those who would
dare to breach the Necrons realm – an enervating
leeching of strength and vitality that leaves them easy prey.
]]></string>

    <string name="souldrain_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever an enemy operative is within your
**OBELISK NODE MATRIX**, or whenever it is fighting
or retaliating against a friendly **CANOPTEK CIRCLE** operative that’s within your **OBELISK NODE MATRIX**, subtract 1 from both Dmg stats
of that enemy operatives melee weapons (to a minimum of 2) until the end of the activation/counteraction. Note this means if the enemy
operative moves through your **OBELISK NODE MATRIX**, apply this change at the end of that
move action until the end of the activation/counteraction.
]]></string>



    <!--Firefight ploys-->
    <string name="shield_flare_lore"><![CDATA[
With a flash, snipers bullets are swallowed in
microdimensions; blades pass through suddenly phased
matter; slivers of time are erased and rewritten, the
strike never connecting after all. The matrix’s energies
deny the Necrons verminous foes of the smallest victory over their betters.
]]></string>

    <string name="shield_flare_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy when an attack dice inflicts
Normal Dmg on a friendly **CANOPTEK CIRCLE**
operative. If your **OBELISK NODE MATRIX** is
intervening, or that friendly operative is within
your **OBELISK NODE MATRIX**, ignore that inflicted
damage. Note your opponent determines
intervening (i.e. where on their operative’s base to draw the targeting lines from).
]]></string>

    <string name="animate_obelisk_nodes_lore"><![CDATA[
Heeding some hidden command, looming obelisk nodes
surge into new positions of cosmic conjunction.
]]></string>

    <string name="animate_obelisk_nodes_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy when it is your turn to
activate or counteract with a friendly operative.
Move any number of your **OBELISK NODE**
markers instead. They can move up to 6\"
horizontally combined, and distances are always
rounded up to the nearest inch (so if you move
a marker 1.5\", it’s treated as moving it 2\"). For
example, you could move one marker 6\", three
markers 1\" each, or any combination that does not
exceed 6\" in total. You can also move them 0\" (to
effectively skip an activation). In any case, your
opponent activates as normal afterwards.
]]></string>

    <string name="nodal_response_lore"><![CDATA[
Eldritch pulses of artificial thought thrum through the
obelisk nodes as they adjust the flow of energies and
data in response to rapidly changing situations.
]]></string>

    <string name="nodal_response_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy during a friendly **CANOPTEK CIRCLE** operatives activation, before or after it
performs an action. You can either change one of the strategy ploys you used during this turning
point (only pay additional CP if that ploy costs more), or use a strategy ploy now (pay its CP cost
as normal).
]]></string>

    <string name="sacrificial_thrall_lore"><![CDATA[
Canoptek constructs are programmed to shield their master at all costs.
]]></string>

    <string name="sacrificial_thrall_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy when a friendly **CANOPTEK CIRCLE GEOMANCER** operative is selected
as the valid target of a **Shoot** action or to fight
against during the **Fight** action. Select one
other friendly **CANOPTEK CIRCLE CANOPTEK**
operative visible to and within 3\" of that first
friendly operative to become the valid target or to
be fought against (as appropriate) instead (even
if it would not normally be valid for this). If it is the
**Fight** action, treat that other operative as being
within the fighting operatives control range for
the duration of that action. If it is the **Shoot** action,
that other operative is only in cover or obscured if
the original target was.\n
\n
This ploy has no effect if it is the **Shoot** action
and the ranged weapon has the Blast or Torrent weapon rule.
]]></string>

</resources>