<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>


    <!--Blades-->

    <string name="defence_tactics_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="defence_tactics_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever this operative contests an objective
marker or one of your mission markers, or whenever it is shooting
an enemy operative that does, this operatives weapons have the Balanced weapon rule.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="exarch_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="exarch_description"><![CDATA[
This operative can perform two **Shoot** or two **Fight** actions during its activation.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="shimmershield_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="shimmershield_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever an operative is shooting a friendly **BLADES OF KHAINE** operative that is visible to and within
2\" of this operative, ignore the Piercing weapon rule. This
operative only has this rule if you select the shimmershield weapon option.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="banshee_mask_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="banshee_mask_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever this operative is fighting, worsen the
Hit stat of the enemy operatives melee weapons by 1. This is not cumulative with being injured.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="mandiblasters_usage"><![CDATA[
           Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="mandiblasters_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever this operative performs the **Fight**
action, at the start of the Roll Attack Dice step, you can use
this rule. If you do, inflict 2 damage on the enemy operative in that sequence.
    ]]></string>

    <!--Faction Rules-->

    <string name="aspect_techniques_lore"><![CDATA[
Aspect Warriors are trained in myriad killing techniques,
parrying blows and acrobatic movements. These are as
breathtaking to behold as they are lethal to their foes.
]]></string>

    <string name="aspect_techniques_description"><![CDATA[
Each **ASPECT TECHNIQUE** is in a category: Dire
Avenger, Howling Banshee and Striking Scorpion.
Each **ASPECT TECHNIQUE** can only be used with
a friendly operative that has the matching Aspect
keyword, and each will specify when it can be
used and what its effects are. In addition:\n
\n
• You cannot use more than one **ASPECT TECHNIQUE** per activation or counteraction.\n
\n
• You cannot use each **ASPECT TECHNIQUE** more than once per turning point.\n
\n
• If every friendly **BLADES OF KHAINE** operative selected for deployment has the same Aspect
keyword (e.g. **STRIKING SCORPION**), you cannot use each **ASPECT TECHNIQUE** more than twice per turning point (instead of once).
]]></string>

    <string name="the_woe_lore"><![CDATA[
Howling Banshees are woe given form. Emitting sonic
screeches from their helms, they hurl themselves into
the stunned foe, the lightning speed of their swordplay
cutting through the enemy before a blow can be landed in return.
]]></string>

    <string name="the_woe_description"><![CDATA[
Use this **ASPECT TECHNIQUE** during a friendly
**HOWLING BANSHEE** operatives activation,
after it is performed the **Charge** action and
incapacitated an enemy operative during the
**Fight** action, and is no longer within control range
of enemy operatives. That friendly operative can
immediately perform a free **Charge** action using
any remaining move distance it had from that
first **Charge** action. That operative can perform
two **Charge** actions during its activation to do so.
The operative cannot have performed any other
actions during this activation (but can do so after
resolving this **ASPECT TECHNIQUE**).
]]></string>

    <string name="rain_of_tears_lore"><![CDATA[
Howling Banshees dive in and out of combat with
infuriating speed and agility, making it almost
impossible for those few who survive their most brutal
attacks to strike in return.
]]></string>

    <string name="rain_of_tears_description"><![CDATA[
Use this **ASPECT TECHNIQUE** when a friendly
**HOWLING BANSHEE** operative is fighting, after
you strike with a critical success, if the enemy
operative is not incapacitated. End that sequence
(any remaining attack dice are discarded) and
immediately perform a free **Fall Back** action
up to 3\" with that operative (then the **Fight**
action ends). That operative can do so even if
it is performed an action that prevents it from
performing the **Fall Back** action.
]]></string>

    <string name="acrobatic_lore"><![CDATA[
When Howling Banshees traverse the battlefield, little
slows them down. With effortless grace they leap and
flip over intervening obstacles, landing with peerless
poise and balance to drive their blades into the foe.
]]></string>

    <string name="acrobatic_description"><![CDATA[
Use this **ASPECT TECHNIQUE** when a friendly
**HOWLING BANSHEE** operative performs an action
in which it moves. Until the end of the action, that operative:\n
\n
• Can ignore all vertical distances whenever it drops and climbs.\n
\n
• Can move through enemy operatives, move within control range of them, and during
the **Charge** action can leave their control range (it must still end the move following all
requirements for that move).\n
\n
• Cannot move more than its Move stat if it is the **Charge** action.\n
\n
]]></string>

    <string name="scream_that_steals_lore"><![CDATA[
Any hope the foe has of retaining the upper hand over a
Howling Banshee is lost the moment the leaping Aspect
Warrior activates their Banshee mask. Their senses
overwhelmed, the enemy are all but helpless against the
merciless melee attacks that follow.
]]></string>

    <string name="scream_that_steals_description"><![CDATA[
Use this **ASPECT TECHNIQUE** when a friendly
**HOWLING BANSHEE** operative is fighting or
retaliating, at the start of the Resolve Attack
Dice step. You can resolve one of your successes
before the normal order. If you do, that success must be used to block.
]]></string>

    <string name="shriek_that_kills_lore"><![CDATA[
Those Howling Banshees who have learned how to focus
their vocal chords correctly can emit a shriek so piercing
and deafening that it can not only stun a foe, but liquefy their brain.
]]></string>

    <string name="shriek_that_kills_description"><![CDATA[
Use this **ASPECT TECHNIQUE** when a friendly
**HOWLING BANSHEE** operative is performing the
**Shoot** action. Until the end of that action, that operative can use the following ranged weapon:
]]></string>

    <string name="the_slicing_hurricane_lore"><![CDATA[
Trained to embrace supreme tactical flexibility,
Dire Avengers are capable of unleashing clouds of
razor-sharp shuriken while moving to secure ground or
slipping out of reach of the foe.
]]></string>

    <string name="the_slicing_hurricane_description"><![CDATA[
Use this **ASPECT TECHNIQUE** when a friendly
**DIRE AVENGER** operative is performing the
**Reposition** action. That operative can perform
the **Shoot** action during that action (it must do so
in a location it can be placed, and any remaining
move distance it had from that **Reposition** action
can be used after it does so). You must select its
shuriken catapult, shuriken pistol or twin shuriken
catapult for that **Shoot** action.
]]></string>

    <string name="death_thousand_blades_lore"><![CDATA[
Dire Avengers can unleash great deluges of
monomolecular shuriken from their weapons. These
lethal volleys echo the Death of a Thousand Blades –
the punishment that Khaine meted out upon traitors,
cheats and others he deemed unworthy of a clean kill.
]]></string>

    <string name="death_thousand_blades_description"><![CDATA[
Use this **ASPECT TECHNIQUE** when a friendly
**DIRE AVENGER** operative is performing the
**Shoot** action and you select a shuriken catapult
or twin shuriken catapult. Until the end of that
action, that weapon has the Torrent 2\" weapon
rule, but you cannot select more than one secondary target.
]]></string>

    <string name="vigilance_of_the_avenger_lore"><![CDATA[
The noble warrior who is tasked with punishing the
unjust and the criminal must be ever vigilant. Their eyes
must be keen and their aim must be true.
]]></string>

    <string name="vigilance_of_the_avenger_description"><![CDATA[
Use this **ASPECT TECHNIQUE** when a friendly
**DIRE AVENGER** operative is performing the **Shoot**
action and you select a shuriken catapult or twin
shuriken catapult. Until the end of that action,
that weapon has the Lethal 5+ weapon rule.
]]></string>

    <string name="unstinting_immovable_lore"><![CDATA[
Dire Avengers wear armour fashioned from
psycho-sensitive thermoplas scales that are reactive
to impact. When suffering a blow, the armour stiffens
to spread the energy across the wearer. On top of this
flexible suit, these Aspect Warriors wear bone-like
plates over the most vulnerable areas of their body.
]]></string>

    <string name="unstinting_immovable_description"><![CDATA[
Use this **ASPECT TECHNIQUE** when an operative
is shooting a friendly **DIRE AVENGER** operative,
and you have rolled two or more fails. You can
discard one of them to retain the other as a normal success instead.
]]></string>

    <string name="raging_heat_lore"><![CDATA[
The flames upon shrines of Asuryan possess a searing
heat and never burn out, even if they dwindle. Thus
does the Dire Avenger strive to imitate these flames,
equally dangerous to the foe regardless of the injuries they sustain.
]]></string>

    <string name="raging_heat_description"><![CDATA[
Use this **ASPECT TECHNIQUE** during a friendly
**DIRE AVENGER** operatives activation. Until the
start of that operatives next activation, you can
ignore any changes to its stats from being injured (including its weapons stats).
]]></string>

    <string name="patient_blow_lore"><![CDATA[
Carefully concealed in cover or in shadows, Striking
Scorpions stalk their oblivious prey, manoeuvring
around their targets in complete silence to select the
optimum position to launch their killing strike.
]]></string>

    <string name="patient_blow_description"><![CDATA[
Use this **ASPECT TECHNIQUE** when a friendly
**STRIKING SCORPION** operative that has a
**Conceal** order performs the **Reposition** action.
During that action, that operative can move
within control range of enemy operatives (it
cannot end the move there), and you can inflict
D3+2 damage on one enemy operative it moved
within control range of after it is moved.
]]></string>

    <string name="strike_and_fade_lore"><![CDATA[
Masters of the hit and run attack, Striking Scorpions
withdraw from combat as suddenly as they strike,
disappearing into shadow like murderous spirits.
]]></string>

    <string name="strike_and_fade_description"><![CDATA[
Use this **ASPECT TECHNIQUE** when a friendly
**STRIKING SCORPION** operative incapacitates
an enemy operative while fighting or retaliating,
and is no longer within 3\" of enemy operatives.
**Change** that friendly operatives order to **Conceal**
and it can immediately perform a free **Dash**
action, even if it is performed an action that
prevents it from performing the **Dash** action.
]]></string>

    <string name="scorpion_eye_lore"><![CDATA[
A Striking Scorpion’s shuriken pistol has a viewfinder
psychically linked to its bearer. With it, the Aspect
Warrior can see through multiple spectra as well as
swiftly identify friend from foe.
]]></string>

    <string name="scorpion_eye_description"><![CDATA[
Use this **ASPECT TECHNIQUE** when a friendly
**STRIKING SCORPION** operative is performing the
**Shoot** action and you select a shuriken pistol.
Until the end of that action, that weapon has the Seek Light weapon rule.
]]></string>

    <string name="merciless_strikes_lore"><![CDATA[
When Striking Scorpions launch their assault, they
attack with relentless ferocity, landing blow after blow
to grant the enemy no moment or reprieve.
]]></string>

    <string name="merciless_strikes_description"><![CDATA[
Use this **ASPECT TECHNIQUE** when a friendly
**STRIKING SCORPION** operative is fighting, the
first time you strike with a critical success during
that sequence. Until the end of that sequence,
that operatives melee weapon has the Shock weapon rule.
]]></string>

    <string name="one_with_gloom_lore"><![CDATA[
Years of strict training render Striking Scorpions capable
of blending uncannily with the shadows, waiting for the
perfect moment to attack their unsuspecting foes with
terrifying accuracy.
]]></string>

    <string name="one_with_gloom_description"><![CDATA[
Use this **ASPECT TECHNIQUE** during a friendly
**STRIKING SCORPION** operatives activation. Until
the start of its next activation, while that operative
has a **Conceal** order and is in cover, it cannot be
selected as a valid target, taking precedence over
all other rules (e.g. Seek, Vantage terrain) except being within 2\".
]]></string>


    <!--Equipment-->

    <string name="rune_prophecy_lore"><![CDATA[
Affixed to an Aspect Warriors armour by a powerful
seer, this warp-charged rune provides the bearer with a
sliver of its creator’s prophetic vision.
]]></string>

    <string name="rune_prophecy_description"><![CDATA[
Once per battle, after rolling off to decide
initiative, you can add D3 to, or subtract D3 from, your result.
]]></string>

    <string name="rune_shielding_lore"><![CDATA[
Shimmering with empyric energy, this rune flares
brightly when it suffers impact from an enemy weapon, turning aside bullet, bolt or blade.
]]></string>

    <string name="rune_shielding_description"><![CDATA[
Once per battle, when an attack dice inflicts
Normal Dmg on a friendly **BLADES OF KHAINE**
operative, you can ignore that inflicted damage.
]]></string>

    <string name="rune_foresight_lore"><![CDATA[
The bearer foresees the battle to come, anticipating the
movements of the foe and positioning their warriors with uncanny guile.
]]></string>

    <string name="rune_foresight_description"><![CDATA[
When this equipment is revealed, roll one D3. In
the Strategy phase of the turning point equal to the result, you gain 1 additional CP.
]]></string>

    <string name="wraithbone_talisman_lore"><![CDATA[
Grown from living wraithbone material, this talisman
lends the bearer strength and determination in the midst of battle
]]></string>

    <string name="wraithbone_talisman_description"><![CDATA[
Once per turning point, when a friendly **BLADES OF KHAINE** operative is shooting, fighting or
retaliating, if you roll two or more fails, you can
discard one of them to retain another as a normal success instead.
]]></string>



    <!--Ploys-->
    <!--Strategy ploys-->
    <string name="forewarned_lore"><![CDATA[
Aspect Warriors go to battle armed with the foresight of their Craftworlds seers.
]]></string>

    <string name="forewarned_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever an operative is shooting a ready
friendly **BLADES OF KHAINE** operative, you can
re-roll any of your defence dice results of one result (e.g. results of 2).
]]></string>

    <string name="ruthless_poise_lore"><![CDATA[
Centuries of combat experience coupled with lightning
reactions and exceptional grace render Aspect Warriors utterly lethal.
]]></string>

    <string name="ruthless_poise_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever a friendly **BLADES OF KHAINE**
operative is fighting a ready enemy operative,
that friendly operatives melee weapons have the Ceaseless weapon rule
]]></string>

    <string name="khaine_vengeance_lore"><![CDATA[
The Aspect Warriors draw upon the Bloody-Handed Gods merciless example to dispatch their foes.
]]></string>

    <string name="khaine_vengeance_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever a friendly **BLADES OF KHAINE** operative is shooting an expended enemy
operative, that friendly operative’s ranged weapons have the Ceaseless weapon rule.
]]></string>

    <string name="dance_of_death_lore"><![CDATA[
Lithe, acrobatic and utterly deadly, Aeldari Aspect
Warriors exchange tactical positions with flawless grace.
]]></string>

    <string name="dance_of_death_description"><![CDATA[
Select two friendly **BLADES OF KHAINE** operatives visible to and within 6\" of each other.
Remove them both from the killzone and set them back up in each other’s previous locations
(in other words, swap their positions).
]]></string>



    <!--Firefight ploys-->
    <string name="bladewind_lore"><![CDATA[
Aspect Warriors strike with speed and precision, their
shining blades scything through the foe in a storm of steel.
]]></string>

    <string name="bladewind_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy during a friendly **BLADES OF KHAINE** operatives activation. During
that activation, that operative can perform two **Fight** actions.
]]></string>

    <string name="starfall_lore"><![CDATA[
With punishing fusillades of accurate shuriken fire do the Aspect Warriors fell their enemies.
]]></string>

    <string name="starfall_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy during a friendly **BLADES OF KHAINE** operatives activation. During
that activation, that operative can perform two **Shoot** actions.
]]></string>

    <string name="fading_light_lore"><![CDATA[
The Aspect Warrior slips away into darkness, leaving their foe striking at nothing but shadow.
]]></string>

    <string name="fading_light_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy during a friendly **BLADES OF KHAINE** operatives activation, before or
after it performs an action. During that activation,
that operative can perform the **Fall Back** action for 1 less AP.
]]></string>

    <string name="blades_contempt_lore"><![CDATA[
The martial superiority of the Aeldari species is
expressed by their Aspect Warriors, who dance
through incoming fire and heavy strikes with contemptuous ease.
]]></string>

    <string name="blades_contempt_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy when a friendly **BLADES OF KHAINE** operative is retaliating or an enemy
operative is shooting it, after your opponent rolls their attack dice, but before re-rolls. Until the end
of the sequence, your opponent cannot re-roll their attack dice (if your opponent declared the
use of any firefight ploys during that sequence that would allow them to re-roll, that ploy is
cancelled and the CP spent on it is refunded).
]]></string>

</resources>