<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>


    <!--Scout-->

    <string name="guidance_and_experience_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="guidance_and_experience_description"><![CDATA[
 Once during each of this operatives activations, you can select one other friendly **SCOUT SQUAD**
operative visible to it. Until the end of that operatives next activation, add 1 to its APL stat.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="scout_astartes_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="scout_astartes_description"><![CDATA[
During this operatives activation, it can perform either two **Shoot** actions or two **Fight** actions. If its two **Shoot** actions,
an Astartes shotgun, bolt pistol or boltgun must be selected for at least one of them. This operative can counteract regardless of
its order.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="grapnel_launcher_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="grapnel_launcher_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever this operative is climbing up, you
can treat the vertical distance as 2\" (regardless of how far the
operative actually moves vertically).
    ]]></string>

    <string name="grapnel_assault_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="grapnel_assault_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever this operative performs the **Charge**
action during its activation, if it climbs, drops, jumps or its
base moves underneath Vantage terrain during that action, its
melee weapons have the Lethal 3+ weapon rule until the end of
that activation.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="track_enemy_usage"><![CDATA[
        1AP
    ]]></string>

    <string name="track_enemy_description"><![CDATA[
Select one enemy operative within 8\" of this operative. Until
the end of the turning point, whenever a friendly **SCOUT
SQUAD** operative is shooting that enemy operative, that
friendly operatives ranged weapons have the Seek Light
weapon rule.\n\n
This operative cannot perform this action while within control
range of an enemy operative.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="scout_auspex_scan_usage"><![CDATA[
        1AP
    ]]></string>

    <string name="scout_auspex_scan_description"><![CDATA[
Until the start of this operatives next activation or until
it is incapacitated (whichever comes first), whenever a
friendly **SCOUT SQUAD** operative is shooting an
enemy operative within 8\" of this operative, that enemy
operative cannot be obscured; if that friendly operative is a
**SNIPER** that is currently benefitting from the effects of its
**Optics** action, its ranged weapons also have the Seek Light
weapon rule.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="scout_adaptive_equipment_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="scout_adaptive_equipment_description"><![CDATA[
You can do each of the following once per turning point:\n

• One friendly **SCOUT SQUAD WARRIOR** operative can perform the Smoke Grenade action.\n
• One friendly **SCOUT SQUAD WARRIOR** operative can perform the Stun Grenade action.\n
The rules for these actions are found in universal equipment. Performing these actions using this
rule does not count towards their action limits (i.e. if you also select those grenades from equipment).
    ]]></string>

    <!--Faction Rules-->

    <string name="foward_scouting_lore"><![CDATA[
Central to the role of Space Marine Scouts is ranging
ahead of the strike force they are attached to, spending
extensive periods laying traps for the foe, harassing
enemy patrols, gathering intelligence and reconnoitring
the ground in preparation for the Chapters
assault force.
]]></string>

    <string name="foward_scouting_description"><![CDATA[
At the end of the Set Up Operatives step, you can
select and resolve up to six Forward Scouting
options. Each option has a number in brackets,
which is the maximum number of times you can
select and resolve it for the battle. For example,
your six selections could be Reposition (2), Trip
Alarm (1), Booby Trap (1) and Diversion (1). If
both players have this rule, alternate resolving
selection by selection, starting with the player
with initiative.\n
\n
\n
**Redeploy** (1)\n
Change the set up of one third of your operatives (rounding up).\n
\n
**Reposition** (2)\n
Perform a free **Reposition** action with one friendly
operative that’s wholly within your drop zone.
It must end that move wholly within 3\" of your drop zone.\n
\n
**Trip Alarm** (2)\n
Place one of your Trip Alarm markers more than
6\" from your opponents drop zone. During
the first and second turning point, whenever a
friendly **SCOUT SQUAD** operative is shooting an
enemy operative that is within 2\" of that marker,
that friendly operatives ranged weapons have the
Seek weapon rule. In the Ready step of the third
Strategy phase, remove that marker.\n
\n
**Booby Trap** (1)\n
Place one of your Booby Trap markers more than
6\" from your opponents drop zone and more
than 2\" from other markers, access points and
Accessible terrain. The first time your Booby
Trap marker is within an enemy operatives
control range, remove that marker and inflict 2D3
damage on that operative; if it is not incapacitated,
end its action (if any), even if that actions effects
are not fulfilled. If it cannot be placed, move it the
minimum amount to do so.\n
\n
**Tactical Manoeuvre** (1)\n
Twice per battle **STRATEGIC GAMBIT**. Select
one friendly operative. Until the end of that
operatives next activation, add 1 to its APL stat.\n
\n
**Diversion** (1)\n
Once per battle **STRATEGIC GAMBIT**. Select one
enemy operative within 6\" of a killzone edge.
Until the end of that operative’s next activation,
subtract 1 from its APL stat.\n
\n
**Devise Plan** (1)\n
You gain 1CP.\n
\n
**Designate Target** (1)\n
Select one enemy operative to gain one of your
Target tokens. Whenever a friendly **SCOUT
SQUAD** operative is shooting against, fighting
against or retaliating against an enemy operative
that has one of your Target tokens, you can re-roll
one of your attack dice.\n
\n
**Spy** (1)\n
Approved Ops only. Your opponent must reveal
their selected tac op.
]]></string>

    <!--Equipment-->

    <string name="camo_cloak_scout_lore"><![CDATA[
Crafted from light-manipulating materials such as
cameleoline, camo cloaks help the bearer blend into
surrounding terrain.
]]></string>

    <string name="camo_cloak_scout_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever an operative is shooting a friendly
**SCOUT SQUAD** operative (excluding **SNIPER**),
if you can retain any cover saves, you can retain
one additional cover save. This is not cumulative
with improved cover saves from Vantage terrain.
]]></string>

    <string name="targeting_oculars_lore"><![CDATA[
These highly sensitive multispectral targeting visors
serve to aid the bearers aim, rendering their weapons
even more lethal.
]]></string>

    <string name="targeting_oculars_description"><![CDATA[
Up to twice per turning point, when a friendly
**SCOUT SQUAD** operative is performing the
**Shoot** action and you are selecting a valid target,
you can use this rule. If you do, until the end
of that action, that friendly operatives ranged
weapons have the Lethal 5+ and Saturate
weapon rules.
]]></string>

    <string name="scout_combat_blades_lore"><![CDATA[
Space Marine Neophytes wield a variety of short-bladed
melee weapons, demonstrating lethal proficiency with
them all.
]]></string>

    <string name="scout_combat_blades_description"><![CDATA[
Friendly **SCOUT SQUAD** operatives have
the following melee weapon. Note that some
operatives already have this weapon but
with better stats; in that instance, use the
better version.
]]></string>

    <string name="heavy_weapon_bipod_lore"><![CDATA[
Deploying a heavy weapon bipod allows the bearer to lay
down a hail of suppressing fire.
]]></string>

    <string name="heavy_weapon_bipod_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever a friendly **SCOUT SQUAD HEAVY
GUNNER** operative is shooting with a heavy bolter
or missile launcher, if it has not moved during
the activation, or if it is a counteraction, that
weapon has the Ceaseless weapon rule; if the
weapon already has that weapon rule, it has the
Relentless weapon rule. Note that operative is not
restricted from moving after shooting.
]]></string>



    <!--Ploys-->
    <!--Strategy ploys-->
    <string name="guerrilla_engagement_lore"><![CDATA[
Space Marine Scouts learn to use terrain to their
advantage, preventing the enemy from getting a bead on
them as they move within killing range.
]]></string>

    <string name="guerrilla_engagement_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever an enemy operative is shooting a
friendly **SCOUT SQUAD** operative, if that friendly
operative is in cover and more than 6\" from
enemy operatives it is visible to, you can re-roll
one of your defence dice.
]]></string>

    <string name="ambush_lore"><![CDATA[
Scout Squads utilise stealth to close within range
of their foes, carefully selecting their targets before
unleashing a devastating assault.
]]></string>

    <string name="ambush_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever a friendly **SCOUT SQUAD** operative
is shooting or fighting during its activation, if its
order was changed from **Conceal** to **Engage** at
the start of that activation, or it was not visible to
enemy operatives at the start of that activation:\n
• That friendly operatives weapons have the Balanced weapon rule.
• If the target is expended, that friendly operatives weapons have the Ceaseless weapon rule instead.
]]></string>

    <string name="adaptable_training_lore"><![CDATA[
Space Marine Neophytes and their experienced
Sergeants draw upon a host of versatile tactics
embedded through hypno-indoctrination. Coupled
with their stealth training, this enables them to
outmanoeuvre their foes while remaining out of reach.
]]></string>

    <string name="adaptable_training_description"><![CDATA[
You can change the order of up to D3 friendly
**SCOUT SQUAD** operatives that are more than 4\"
from enemy operatives.
]]></string>

    <string name="stealth_relocation_lore"><![CDATA[
Space Marine Scout Squads are highly mobile
units, shifting swiftly from cover to cover in order to
outmanoeuvre the foe.
]]></string>

    <string name="stealth_relocation_description"><![CDATA[
Up to D3 friendly **SCOUT SQUAD** operatives that
have a Conceal order and are more than 4\" from
enemy operatives can immediately perform a free
**Dash** action. You cannot use this ploy during the
first turning point.
]]></string>



    <!--Firefight ploys-->
    <string name="astartes_training_lore"><![CDATA[
Space Marine Chapters are amongst the galaxys most
elite fighting forces. Even their Neophytes wield their
weapons with peerless skill.
]]></string>

    <string name="astartes_training_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy during a friendly **SCOUT
SQUAD** operatives activation. Until the end
of that activation, that operative can do one of
the following:\n
• Perform two **Fight** actions.\n
• Perform two **Shoot** actions if an Astartes shotgun, bolt pistol or boltgun is selected for at
least one of them. \
• Perform two **Shoot** actions with a heavy bolter,
missile launcher or sniper rifle, but 1 additional
AP must be spent for the second action.
]]></string>

    <string name="raw_physiology_lore"><![CDATA[
Though their training may not yet be complete, Space
Marine Scouts possess the same genetically augmented
resilience as their fully fledged battle-brothers
]]></string>

    <string name="raw_physiology_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy during a friendly **SCOUT
SQUAD** operatives activation, before or after
it performs an action. Until the start of its next
activation, add 1\" to its Move stat and you can
ignore any changes to that operatives stats from
being injured (including its weapons’ stats).
]]></string>

    <string name="emboldened_aspirant_lore"><![CDATA[
Surgical enhancement, indoctrination and brutal
training instil within a Space Marine Neophyte the
confidence and determination to battle powerful foes.
]]></string>

    <string name="emboldened_aspirant_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy when a friendly **SCOUT
SQUAD** operative performs the **Shoot** or
**Fight** action, after any re-rolls. If it is the first
friendly operative to perform either of those
actions during this turning point, or if the
enemy operative in that action (primary target,
if relevant) has a higher Wounds stat than that
friendly **SCOUT SQUAD** operative, you can
retain one of your normal successes as a critical
success instead.
]]></string>

    <string name="covert_position_lore"><![CDATA[
Space Marine Scouts excel at camouflaging themselves,
laying in wait for hours or even days at a time until they
identify the perfect moment to strike
]]></string>

    <string name="covert_position_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy during a friendly **SCOUT
SQUAD** operatives activation. Until the start
of its next activation, while that operative has
a **Conceal** order and is in cover, it cannot be
selected as a valid target, taking precedence over
all other rules (e.g. Seek, Vantage terrain) except
being within 2\".
]]></string>

</resources>