<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>


    <!--Blooded-->

    <string name="blooded_grenadier_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="blooded_grenadier_description"><![CDATA[
This operative can use frag and krak grenades (see
universal equipment). Doing so does not count towards any
limited uses you have (i.e. if you also select those grenades from
equipment for other operatives). Whenever it is doing so, improve
the Hit stat of that weapon by 1.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="explosive_demise_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="explosive_demise_description"><![CDATA[
If this operative is incapacitated, before it is
removed from the killzone, you can use this rule. If you do, roll
two D6, or one D6 if this operative is within control range of an
enemy operative. If any result is a 4+, inflict D3+2 damage on
each operative visible to and within 2\" of this operative (roll
separately for each). If this operative has not used its diabolyk
bomb during the battle, inflict D6+2 damage instead.
    ]]></string>


    <string name="blooded_icon_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="blooded_icon_description"><![CDATA[
Once per turning point, when a friendly
**BLOODED** operative that has one of your Blooded tokens is
incapacitated, if this operative is within 6\" of it, you can regain
that token.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="lead_with_strength_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="lead_with_strength_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever this operative has one of your
Blooded tokens or is wholly within your opponents territory,
treat it as if it is under the **GAZE OF THE GODS**.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="unholy_sustenance_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="unholy_sustenance_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever this operative is fighting or
retaliating, if it incapacitates the enemy operative in that
sequence, it regains up to D3 lost wounds. This is cumulative
with the Symbols of Bloody Worship equipment.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="blood_offering_usage"><![CDATA[

        Special Weapon Rule

    ]]></string>

    <string name="blood_offering_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever this operative is fighting or retaliating
with this weapon, the first time you strike with a critical success
during that sequence, you gain one Blooded token.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="regular_dosage_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="regular_dosage_description"><![CDATA[
At the end of the Select
Operatives step, if this operative is
selected for deployment, you can select
one other friendly **BLOODED** operative
to gain one **STIMM** rule for the battle
(excluding Rejuvenated).\n
\n
**STIMM RULES:**\n
\n
• Rejuvenated: The operative regains up to 2D3 lost wounds.\n
\n
• Enraged: The operatives melee weapons have the Relentless weapon rule.\n
\n
• Fortified: Whenever an attack dice inflicts damage of 3 or more on the operative, roll
one D6: on a 5+, subtract 1 from that inflicted damage
    ]]></string>

    <string name="stimms_usage"><![CDATA[

        1AP

    ]]></string>

    <string name="stimms_description"><![CDATA[
Select one friendly **BLOODED** operative within this
operatives control range, then select the Rejuvenated
**STIMM** rule, or one other **STIMM** rule for that operative to
have for the battle. You cannot select each **STIMM** rule for
each operative more than once per battle.\n\n

This operative cannot perform this action while within control
range of an enemy operative.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="blooded_signal_usage"><![CDATA[
        1AP
    ]]></string>

    <string name="blooded_signal_description"><![CDATA[
**SUPPORT.** Select one other friendly **BLOODED**
operative (excluding **OGRYN**) visible to and within 6\" of this
operative. Until the end of that operative’s next activation,
add 1 to its APL stat.\n\n
This operative cannot perform this action while within control
range of an enemy operative.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="sacrilegious_actuation_usage"><![CDATA[

        1AP

    ]]></string>

    <string name="sacrilegious_actuation_description"><![CDATA[
You gain one Blooded token.\n\n
This operative cannot perform this action while within control
range of an enemy operative, or if it does not have one of your
Blooded tokens.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="gruelling_disciplinarian_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="gruelling_disciplinarian_description"><![CDATA[
• Whenever a friendly **BLOODED** operative is within 6\" of this
operative, you can ignore any changes to that operatives stats
from being injured (including its weapons stats).\n
\n
• Whenever a friendly **BLOODED** operative is activated
within 6\" of this operative, you can ignore any changes to
that operatives stats from being injured until the end of its
activation (including its weapons’ stats).
    ]]></string>

    <string name="enforce_usage"><![CDATA[

        1AP

    ]]></string>

    <string name="enforce_description"><![CDATA[
Select one other friendly **BLOODED** operative visible
to and within 3\" of this operative. That operative can
immediately perform a 1AP action for free, but it cannot
move more than 2\" during that action. If the selected
friendly operative is a **COMMSMAN**, it cannot perform the
**Sacrilegious Actuation** or **Signal** actions.\n\n
This operative cannot perform this action while within control
range of an enemy operative.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="stalk_usage"><![CDATA[
        Special Weapon Rule
    ]]></string>

    <string name="stalk_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever this operative is fighting or retaliating with this
weapon, if Light or Heavy terrain is within its control range, this
weapon has the Lethal 5+ weapon rule.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="wretched_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wretched_description"><![CDATA[
This operative can perform the **Charge** action while
it has a **Conceal** order. If this operative is incapacitated during
the **Fight** action, you can strike the enemy operative in that
sequence with one of your unresolved successes before this
operative is removed from the killzone
    ]]></string>

    <string name="chem_enhance_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="chem_enhance_description"><![CDATA[
 You can ignore any changes to this operatives
APL stat and it is not affected by enemy operatives Shock and
Stun weapon rules.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="avalanche_muscle_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="avalanche_muscle_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever this operative ends its move
during the **Charge** action, you can inflict D3 damage on one
enemy operative within its control range.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="blooded_camo_cloak_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="blooded_camo_cloak_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever an operative is shooting this operative,
if you can retain any cover saves, you can retain one additional
cover save. This is not cumulative with improved cover saves from
Vantage terrain.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="a_name_whispered_in_blood_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="a_name_whispered_in_blood_description"><![CDATA[
**STRATEGIC GAMBIT** in the
first turning point. Select one enemy operative. Whenever this
operative is shooting that enemy operative, treat this operative
as if it has one of your Blooded tokens and is under the **GAZE
OF THE GODS.**
    ]]></string>

    <string name="tough_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="tough_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever this operative is fighting or retaliating, or an
operative is shooting it, Normal Dmg of 3 or more inflicts 1 less
damage on it.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="blooded_shield_usage"><![CDATA[

        Special Weapon Rule

    ]]></string>

    <string name="blooded_shield_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever this operative is fighting or retaliating with
this weapon, each of your blocks can be allocated to block two
unresolved successes (instead of one).
    ]]></string>

    <string name="shielding_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="shielding_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever this operative is activated, you can use this
rule. If you do, until the start of this operative’s next activation:\n
\n
• Subtract 2" from its Move stat.\n
\n
• Whenever an operative is shooting this operative, you can
re-roll any of your defence dice.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="blooded_group_activation_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="blooded_group_activation_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever this operative is expended, you
must then activate one other ready friendly **BLOODED
TROOPER** operative (if able) before your opponent activates.
When that other operative is expended, your opponent then
activates as normal (in other words, you cannot activate more
than two operatives in succession with this rule).
    ]]></string>
    <!--Faction Rules-->

    <string name="blooded_lore"><![CDATA[
The Blooded seek to earn the favour of malign warp
entities by hurling themselves into combat and slaying
the most potent foes. Should they die in the attempt,
their souls may serve as acceptable sacrifices.
]]></string>

    <string name="blooded_description"><![CDATA[
You gain one Blooded token:\n
\n
• In the Ready step of each Strategy phase.\n
\n
• The first time an enemy operative is incapacitated during each turning point.\n
\n
• The first time a friendly operative is incapacitated within 6\" of an enemy operative
during each turning point.\n
\n
As a **STRATEGIC GAMBIT**, you can assign any
of your unassigned Blooded tokens to friendly
**BLOODED** operatives. Each operative cannot
have more than one of your Blooded tokens.
Then, if four or more friendly operatives in the
killzone have one of your Blooded tokens, you can
select one of them to be under the **GAZE OF THE
GODS** until the end of the turning point.\n
\n
Whenever a friendly **BLOODED** operative has
one of your Blooded tokens, its weapons have
the Accurate 1 weapon rule. If that friendly
**BLOODED** operative is under the **GAZE OF
THE GODS**, you can retain one of your normal
successes as a result of the Accurate 1 weapon
rule as a critical success instead.
]]></string>


    <!--Equipment-->

    <string name="chaos_sigil_lore"><![CDATA[
The disquieting sigils carried by the Blooded bend
reality and thin the veil between realspace and the
ever-shifting tides of the warp.
]]></string>

    <string name="chaos_sigil_description"><![CDATA[
The Reward Earned firefight ploy costs you 0CP.
]]></string>

    <string name="sinister_trophies_lore"><![CDATA[
The Blooded adorn their armour with severed heads
affixed to rusty spikes, cloaks and tabards of flayed skin,
and all manner of other grisly trophies hacked from the
corpses of their victims.
]]></string>

    <string name="sinister_trophies_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever an enemy operative is shooting
against, fighting against or retaliating against
a friendly **BLOODED** operative that has one of
your Blooded tokens and is within 2\" of it, your
opponent cannot re-roll their attack dice results
of 1
]]></string>

    <string name="symbols_of_worship_lore"><![CDATA[
Desperate to garner the favour of malefic warp entities,
the Blooded will daub their armour with bloody runes
and take risks to be imbued with malevolent power.
]]></string>

    <string name="symbols_of_worship_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever a friendly **BLOODED** operative ends
an action, if it was not incapacitated but inflicted
damage on any enemy operatives during that
action, it regains 1 lost wound.
]]></string>

    <string name="wicked_blades_lore"><![CDATA[
The Ruinous Powers respect nothing so much as the
lethal arena of close combat, and so the Blooded seek
to plunge their wickedly sharp weapons into the flesh of
their foes.
]]></string>

    <string name="wicked_blades_description"><![CDATA[
Add 1 to both Dmg stats of each friendly
**BLOODED** operatives bayonet, bayonet & shield
and improvised blade for the battle.
]]></string>



    <!--Ploys-->
    <!--Strategy ploys-->
    <string name="glory_kill_lore"><![CDATA[
By bringing down the strongest and most capable of
enemies, the Blooded may provide a worthy offering to
the Ruinous Powers.
]]></string>

    <string name="glory_kill_description"><![CDATA[
Select one enemy operative visible to a friendly
**BLOODED** operative. Until the end of the turning
point, whenever a friendly **BLOODED** operative
is shooting against, fighting against or retaliating
against that enemy operative, that shooting,
fighting or retaliating operatives weapons have
the Ceaseless weapon rule, or Relentless if it has
one of your Blooded tokens.
]]></string>

    <string name="reckless_aspirant_lore"><![CDATA[
No coward can earn glory. The Blooded are willing to
risk life and limb in pursuit of malefic warp powers.
]]></string>

    <string name="reckless_aspirant_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever a friendly **BLOODED** operative
that is wholly within your opponents territory
and does not have one of your Blooded tokens
is shooting or fighting, its weapons have the
Accurate 1 weapon rule.\n
\n
Whenever a friendly **BLOODED** operative that
has one of your Blooded tokens is wholly within
your opponents territory, its weapons have the
Punishing weapon rule.
]]></string>

    <string name="malevolent_grit_lore"><![CDATA[
Those that have earned the favour of the Dark Gods of
Chaos may draw upon the warp to predict and avoid the
bullets of their foes.
]]></string>

    <string name="malevolent_grit_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever an operative is shooting a friendly
**BLOODED** operative that has one of your
Blooded tokens or is wholly within your
opponents territory, you can re-roll one of your
defence dice.
]]></string>

    <string name="bitter_demise_lore"><![CDATA[
Consumed by hatred, the Blooded spit, curse and lash
out as they die, screaming aggrieved words of heresy as
they land a final strike upon the foe.
]]></string>

    <string name="bitter_demise_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever a friendly **BLOODED** operative is
incapacitated, before it is removed from the
killzone, roll one D3: on a 3 (or 2+ if that friendly
operative has one of your Blooded tokens),
inflict damage equal to the result on one
enemy operative visible to and within 2\" of that
friendly operative.
]]></string>



    <!--Firefight ploys-->
    <string name="callous_disregard_lore"><![CDATA[
Pity is a trait of the weak. The Blooded will gladly turn
their guns upon their own kin if doing so will ensure the
destruction of an enemy.
]]></string>

    <string name="callous_disregard_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy when a friendly **BLOODED**
operative performs the Shoot action and you are
selecting a valid target. Having other friendly
**BLOODED** operatives within an enemy
operatives control range does not prevent that
enemy operative from being selected. Until
the end of that action, whenever you discard
an attack dice as a fail, inflict damage equal to
the dice result on one friendly operative of your
choice within control range of the target.
]]></string>

    <string name="moment_of_repute_lore"><![CDATA[
When infused with a portion of the Dark Gods’ power,
the Blooded are lent infernal speed and aggression.
]]></string>

    <string name="moment_of_repute_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy during the activation of a
friendly **BLOODED** operative that is under the
**GAZE OF THE GODS**, before or after it performs
an action. Until the end of that operatives
activation, add 1 to its APL stat.
]]></string>

    <string name="reward_earned_lore"><![CDATA[
The surest way to earn the attention of the Ruinous
Powers is to draw blood in their name.
]]></string>

    <string name="reward_earned_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy when an enemy operative is
incapacitated by a friendly **BLOODED** operative
within 2\" of it that has one of your Blooded
tokens. You gain one Blooded token.
]]></string>

    <string name="dark_favour_lore"><![CDATA[
Those who have spilled the blood of the foe and earned
the favour of their infernal patron may be spared from
death, as long as another pays the price in their stead
]]></string>

    <string name="dark_favour_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy when a friendly **BLOODED**
operative that has one of your Blooded tokens
is selected as the valid target of a **Shoot** action
or to fight against during the **Fight** action. Select
one other friendly **BLOODED** operative visible
to and within 3\" of that first friendly operative to
become the valid target or to be fought against
(as appropriate) instead (even if it would not
normally be valid for this). If it is the **Fight** action,
treat that other operative as being within the
fighting operatives control range for the duration
of that action. If it is the **Shoot** action, that other
operative is only in cover or obscured if the
original target was.
]]></string>

</resources>