<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <!--Elucidian-->


    <string name="elucidian_beast_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
]]></string>

    <string name="elucidian_beast_description"><![CDATA[
This operative cannot perform any actions other than
**Charge, Dash, Fall Back, Fight, Gather, Guard,
Reposition, Pick Up Marker** and **Place Marker**. It
cannot use any weapons that arent on its datacard.
]]></string>

    <string name="loyal_companion_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
]]></string>

    <string name="loyal_companion_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever an enemy operative performs
the **Fight** action, if this operative is a valid operative to fight
against, you can force them to select this operative to fight
against instead. Whenever an enemy operative ends the **Charge**
action within control range of another friendly **ELUCIDIAN
STARSTRIDER** operative within 3\" of this operative, if this
operative isnt within control range of enemy operatives, this
operative can immediately perform a free **Charge** action (you
can change its order to **Engage** to do so), but must end that move
within control range of that enemy operative.
]]></string>

    <string name="gather_usage"><![CDATA[
        1AP
]]></string>

    <string name="gather_description"><![CDATA[
Perform a free **Dash** or **Reposition** action with this
operative. During that move, it can perform a free **Pick
Up Marker** or **Place Marker** action (you can determine
control during that action to do so), and any remaining move
distance it had from the **Dash** or **Reposition** action can be
used after it does so.
]]></string>

    <string name="digital_lasers_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
]]></string>

    <string name="digital_lasers_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever this operative performs the **Fight**
action, at the start of the Roll Attack Dice step, you can use
this rule. If you do, inflict 1 damage on the enemy operative in
that sequence.
]]></string>

    <string name="merciless_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
]]></string>

    <string name="merciless_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever this operative is shooting against, fighting
against or retaliating against an enemy operative that was
already wounded when the action started, this operatives
weapons have the Balanced weapon rule; if the weapon already
has that weapon rule, it has the Ceaseless weapon rule instead
of Balanced.
]]></string>

    <string name="disruption_field_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
]]></string>

    <string name="disruption_field_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever an operative is shooting this operative, ignore the Piercing weapon rule.
]]></string>

    <string name="reputation_to_maintain_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
]]></string>

    <string name="reputation_to_maintain_description"><![CDATA[
The first time this operative incapacitates an enemy operative during the battle, you can
either gain 1 additional CP or use an additional **WARRANT OF
TRADE** rule (up to five uses per battle, instead of four). Note
that you still cannot use the same **WARRANT OF TRADE** rule
more than once per battle.
]]></string>

    <string name="rapid_reflexes_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
]]></string>

    <string name="rapid_reflexes_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever an operative is shooting this operative, ignore the Piercing weapon rule.
]]></string>

    <string name="elucidian_bladed_stance_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
]]></string>

    <string name="elucidian_bladed_stance_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever this operative is fighting or retaliating, you can resolve one of your successes before the normal order. If
you do, that success must be used to block.
]]></string>

    <string name="elucidian_zealot_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
]]></string>

    <string name="elucidian_zealot_description"><![CDATA[
If this operative is incapacitated during the **Fight** action,
you can strike the enemy operative in that sequence with one of
your unresolved successes before this operative is removed from
the killzone.
]]></string>

    <string name="elucidian_trained_assasin_usage"><![CDATA[
        1AP
]]></string>

    <string name="elucidian_trained_assasin_description"><![CDATA[
Change this operatives order.\n\n
This operative cannot perform this action while within control range of an enemy operative.
]]></string>

    <string name="missionary_martian_creed_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
]]></string>

    <string name="missionary_martian_creed_description"><![CDATA[
Once during each of this operatives activations, it can perform the **Pick Up Marker**,
**Place Marker** or a **mission action** for 1 less AP.
]]></string>

    <string name="voltaghiest_array_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
]]></string>

    <string name="voltaghiest_array_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever an operative is shooting a friendly
**ELUCIDIAN STARSTRIDER** operative thats within 4\" of
this operative, you can re-roll one of your defence dice.
]]></string>

    <string name="calibrate_voltagheist_usage"><![CDATA[
        1AP
]]></string>

    <string name="calibrate_voltagheist_description"><![CDATA[
Select one of the following effects to last until the start of
this operatives next activation, until its incapacitated or
until it performs this action again (whichever comes first):\n
\n
• Charge: This operatives voltaic pistol has the Lethal 4+
weapon rule.\n
\n
• Field: Whenever an enemy operative ends the **Charge,
Dash, Fall Back or Reposition** action visible to and
within 4\" of this operative, inflict D6 damage on that
enemy operative.\n\n
This operative cannot perform this action while within control
range of an enemy operative.
]]></string>

    <string name="elucidian_medic_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
]]></string>

    <string name="elucidian_medic_description"><![CDATA[
The first time during each turning point that another
friendly **ELUCIDIAN STARSTRIDER** operative would be
incapacitated while visible to and within 3\" of this operative,
you can use this rule, providing neither this nor that operative
is within control range of an enemy operative. If you do, that
friendly operative isnt incapacitated, has 3 wounds remaining
and cannot be incapacitated for the remainder of the action.
After that action, that friendly operative can immediately
perform a free **Dash** action, but must end that move within
this operatives control range.\nIf this rule was used during that
friendly operatives activation, that activation ends. You cannot
use this rule if this operative is incapacitated, or if its a **Shoot**
action and this operative would be a primary or secondary target.
]]></string>

    <string name="normaliser_helm_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
]]></string>

    <string name="normaliser_helm_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever a friendly **ELUCIDIAN
STARSTRIDER** operative is within 6\" of this operative, you
can ignore any changes to that operatives stats from being
injured (including its weapons stats).
]]></string>

    <string name="healing_serum_usage"><![CDATA[
    1AP
]]></string>

    <string name="healing_serum_description"><![CDATA[
Select one friendly **ELUCIDIAN STARSTRIDER**
operative within this operatives control range to regain up to
D3+3 lost wounds. It cannot be an operative that the Medic!
rule was used on during this turning point.\n\n
This operative cannot perform this action while within control
range of an enemy operative
]]></string>

    <string name="disciplinarian_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
]]></string>

    <string name="disciplinarian_description"><![CDATA[
**SUPPORT.** Whenever another friendly
**ELUCIDIAN STARSTRIDER NAVIS** operative is within
3\" of this operative, that friendly operatives ranged weapons
(excluding **PRIVATEER SUPPORT ASSET** weapons)
have the Balanced weapon rule; if the weapon already has
that weapon rule, it has the Ceaseless weapon rule instead
of Balanced.
]]></string>

    <string name="elucidian_hardy_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive/ Once per battle
]]></string>

    <string name="elucidian_hardy_description"><![CDATA[
Once per battle, when an attack dice inflicts Normal Dmg on this operative, you can ignore that inflicted damage.
]]></string>

    <string name="uncompromising_fire_usage"><![CDATA[
        1AP
]]></string>

    <string name="uncompromising_fire_description"><![CDATA[
Perform two free **Shoot** actions with this operative (this
takes precedence over action restrictions). You must select
its relic laspistol for one action and its artificer shotgun
(close range) for the other (in any order).\n\n
This operative cannot perform this action while it has a
Conceal order, or during an activation in which it performed
the **Shoot** action (or vice versa).
]]></string>

    <string name="crewmen_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
]]></string>

    <string name="crewmen_description"><![CDATA[
Once per turning point, whenever you would counteract, if you havent used a **PRIVATEER SUPPORT ASSET**
during this turning point, you can use this rule. If you do, you can counteract with one friendly **ELUCIDIAN STARSTRIDER
VOIDSMAN** operative that has a **Conceal** order, but during that counteraction you cannot perform any actions other than **Shoot**,
and you must use a **PRIVATEER SUPPORT ASSET** to do so.
]]></string>


    <!--Faction Rules-->

    <string name="warrant_of_trade_lore"><![CDATA[
The writ of a Rogue Trader allows them incredible
access across the Imperium. With more flexibility than
almost any other agents of the Imperium, they barter,
intimidate and "\borrow"\ to gain valuable resources
that allow them to enter any engagement with the
upper hand.
]]></string>

    <string name="warrant_of_trade_description"><![CDATA[
Up to four times per battle, you can use a
WARRANT OF TRADE rule (below). Each one
specifies when it can be used, and you cannot
use the same WARRANT OF TRADE rule more
than once per battle.\n
\n
Consideration\n
When: In the Select Operatives step, after
revealing your equipment options.
Effect: Select one additional equipment option. It
cannot be an option you have previously selected.\n
\n
Coordinate\n
When: At the end of the Select Operatives step.
Effect: You gain 1 additional CP.\n
\n
Coerce\n
When:At the start of the Set Up Operatives step
Effect:Your opponent must set up all of their operatives before you set up any. Additionally,
select one of the following options:\n
• Your opponent must set up all of their equipment before you set up any.\n
• You can set up all of your equipment before your opponent sets up any.\n
\n
Explore\n
When:STRATEGIC GAMBIT in the first turning point.
Effect:Perform a free Reposition action with D3 friendly ELUCIDIAN STARSTRIDER operatives
that are wholly within your drop zone. Each that does so must end that move wholly within 4\" of
your drop zone.\n
\n
Bribe\n
When:Its your turn to activate an operative.
Effect: You can skip that activation.\n
\n
Seize\n
When: In the Strategy phase, after rolling off to decide initiative.
Effect:You can re-roll your dice.\n
\n
Adaptable Terms (Approved Ops only)\n
When: At the end of the second turning point.
Effect:  Select a new tac op or a new primary op. If you select a new tac op, any points scored from
the previous tac op are discarded.

]]></string>

    <string name="privateer_support_assets_lore"><![CDATA[
The Starstriders never stray too far from the New Dawn.
Overhead, its massive batteries of ship-based artillery
rain down on enemies, providing invaluable air support.
]]></string>

    <string name="privateer_support_assets_description"><![CDATA[
Once per Firefight phase, when a friendly ELUCIDIAN STARSTRIDER NAVIS or ELUCIDIAN
STARSTRIDER ELUCIA VHANE operative performs the Shoot action, you can select one
of the following PRIVATEER SUPPORT ASSET ranged weapons for it to use. You cannot use
each PRIVATEER SUPPORT ASSET more than once per battle.\n
\n
Whenever a friendly ELUCIDIAN STARSTRIDER operative is using a PRIVATEER SUPPORT ASSET,
determine cover saves differently. Instead, the target has a cover save if any part of its base is
underneath Vantage terrain. Note that while this can affect the target’s cover save, you must still
select a valid target as normal. In other words, the shot is guided by an operative in the killzone, but
it comes from above.
]]></string>


    <!--Equipment-->

    <string name="armoured_undersuit_lore"><![CDATA[
Ablative plates and steel reinforcements are woven
into naval fatigues, providing an additional layer
of protection.
]]></string>

    <string name="armoured_undersuit_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever an operative is shooting a friendly
**ELUCIDIAN STARSTRIDER** operative (excluding
**CANID**) that has a 5+ Save stat, you can retain
one of your defence dice results of 4 as a
normal success.
]]></string>

    <string name="hot_shot_capacitor_packs_lore"><![CDATA[
Dangerous but lethal modification of lasguns and
laspistols provide the Starstriders with additional killing
power, albeit with the risk of injury.
]]></string>

    <string name="hot_shot_capacitor_packs_description"><![CDATA[
Up to twice per turning point, whenever a
friendly **ELUCIDIAN STARSTRIDER** operative
is performing the **Shoot** action and you select a
laspistol, lasgun or relic laspistol, you can use this
rule. If you do, until the end of the turning point,
add 1 to both Dmg stats of that weapon and it has
the Hot and Piercing Crits 1 weapon rules.
]]></string>

    <string name="improved_coordinates_uplink_lore"><![CDATA[
Coordinated triangulation undertaken by Navis
Imperialis operatives allows the New Dawns weapon
batteries to more accurately target the foe.
]]></string>

    <string name="improved_coordinates_uplink_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever a friendly **ELUCIDIAN STARSTRIDER**
operative is using a **PRIVATEER SUPPORT ASSET**,
if the target is within 6\" of a friendly **ELUCIDIAN
STARSTRIDER NAVIS** operative, the target
cannot be obscured and that weapon has the
Saturate weapon rule.
]]></string>

    <string name="rapid_gunnery_lore"><![CDATA[
The New Dawns colossal batteries are slow to reload
and recharge. Only veteran gun crews possess the
expertise and coordination to fire a rapid salvo.
]]></string>

    <string name="rapid_gunnery_description"><![CDATA[
Once per battle, when selecting a **PRIVATEER
SUPPORT ASSET**, you can select one thats
already been used during the battle. This
takes precedence over the normal **PRIVATEER
SUPPORT ASSET** rules.
]]></string>




    <!--Ploys-->
    <!--Strategy ploys-->
    <string name="lethal_proximity_lore"><![CDATA[
Well-drilled in boarding actions and combat in cramped
conditions, the Starstriders truly excel in closequarters firefights.
]]></string>

    <string name="lethal_proximity_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever a friendly **ELUCIDIAN STARSTRIDER**
operative is shooting an operative within 6\" of
it, that friendly operatives ranged weapons
(excluding **PRIVATEER SUPPORT ASSET**
weapons) have the Balanced weapon rule.
]]></string>

    <string name="elucidian_stake_claim_lore"><![CDATA[
When Elucia Vhane stakes her claim upon a prize, the
Starstriders will strive to ensure it is delivered into
her hands.
]]></string>

    <string name="elucidian_stake_claim_description"><![CDATA[
Place your Claim marker in the killzone.
Whenever a friendly **ELUCIDIAN STARSTRIDER**
operative is shooting against, fighting against
or retaliating against an enemy operative thats
within 3\" of that marker, in the Roll Attack
Dice step, you can retain one of your fails as
a normal success instead of discarding it, or
retain one of your normal successes as a critical
success instead.
]]></string>

    <string name="undaunted_explorers_lore"><![CDATA[
The Starstriders have weathered many terrible storms
in their journeys through the void, and are capable of
shrugging off wounds that would fell lesser soldiers.
]]></string>

    <string name="undaunted_explorers_description"><![CDATA[
The first time an attack dice inflicts damage
on each friendly **ELUCIDIAN STARSTRIDER**
operative during the turning point in the Resolve
Attack Dice step, you can halve that inflicted
damage (rounding up, to a minimum of 2).
]]></string>

    <string name="quick_march_lore"><![CDATA[
As fearless as any elite Astra Militarum regiment, the
Elucidian Starstriders advance swiftly to outflank and
isolate their enemies.
]]></string>

    <string name="quick_march_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever a friendly **ELUCIDIAN STARSTRIDER**
operative performs the **Reposition** action
during its activation, you can use this rule. If
you do, add 1\" to its Move stat until the end
of that activation, but it must end that move
closer to your opponents drop zone and cannot
use a **PRIVATEER SUPPORT ASSET** during
that activation.
]]></string>

    <!--Firefight ploys-->
    <string name="elucidian_combined_arms_lore"><![CDATA[
The standard training of the Navis Imperialis allows the
Starstriders to rain fury down upon the enemy with rapid
volleys. In great enough volume, even the humble lasgun
can shatter formidable defences.
]]></string>

    <string name="elucidian_combined_arms_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy after rolling your attack
dice for a friendly **ELUCIDIAN STARSTRIDER**
operative, if its shooting an enemy operative
thats been shot by another friendly **ELUCIDIAN
STARSTRIDER** operative during this turning
point. You can re-roll any of your attack dice.
You cannot use this ploy while shooting with a
PRIVATEER SUPPORT ASSET.
]]></string>

    <string name="elucidian_survivalist_lore"><![CDATA[
Ducking into cover for a brief moment, the Starstrider
bandages their wounds, applies stimms and prepares to
rejoin the fight.
]]></string>

    <string name="elucidian_survivalist_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy when a friendly **ELUCIDIAN
STARSTRIDER** operative is activated. That
friendly operative regains up to D3+2 lost wounds
and during that activation you can ignore any
changes to its APL stat.
]]></string>

    <string name="great_endurance_lore"><![CDATA[
Each member of the Navis Imperialis assigned to a
Rogue Trader is elite and prepared to endure the most
testing of circumstances to perform their duties.
]]></string>

    <string name="great_endurance_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy during a friendly **ELUCIDIAN
STARSTRIDER NAVIS** operatives activation.
Until the end of the activation, add 1 to its
APL stat.
]]></string>

    <string name="well_drilled_lore"><![CDATA[
Trained regularly and vigorously in the art of boarding
actions, members of the Navis Imperialis are expected
to precisely coordinate their strikes, working in tandem
to complete the goals of the mission at hand
]]></string>

    <string name="well_drilled_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy when a friendly **ELUCIDIAN
STARSTRIDER NAVIS** operative is activated.
Select one other ready friendly **ELUCIDIAN
STARSTRIDER NAVIS** operative visible to and
within 3\" of that operative. When that first friendly
operative is expended, you can activate that other
friendly operative before your opponent activates.
When that other operative is expended, your
opponent then activates as normal.
]]></string>

</resources>