<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <!--Exation-->

    <string name="exaction_assault_shield_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="exaction_assault_shield_description"><![CDATA[
If this operative has a dominator maul & assault
shield, it has a 3+ Save stat
    ]]></string>

    <string name="nuncio_aquila_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="nuncio_aquila_description"><![CDATA[
• Whenever an enemy operative is within 3\n" of your
Nuncio-aquila marker (or this operative if your Nuncio-aquila
marker isnt in the killzone), your opponent must spend 1
additional AP for that enemy operative to perform the **Pick
Up Marker** and mission actions.\n
• Whenever determining control of a marker, treat the total
APL stat of enemy operatives that contest it as 1 lower if
at least one of those enemy operatives is within 3\n" of your
Nuncio-aquila marker (or this operative if your Nuncio-aquila
marker isnt in the killzone). Note this isnt a change to the APL
stat, so any changes are cumulative with this.

    ]]></string>

    <string name="deploy_nuncio_aquila_usage"><![CDATA[

        1AP

    ]]></string>

    <string name="deploy_nuncio_aquila_description"><![CDATA[
If your Nuncio-aquila marker isnt in the killzone, place it
within 6\" horizontally of this operative; otherwise, move your
Nuncio-aquila marker up to 6\" horizontally. If this operative
is removed from the killzone, remove your Nuncio-aquila
marker from the killzone.\n\n
This operative cannot perform this action while within control
range of an enemy operative.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="exaction_medic_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="exaction_medic_description"><![CDATA[
The first time during each turning point that another friendly **EXACTION SQUAD** operative would be
incapacitated while visible to and within 3\" of this operative, you can use this rule, providing
neither this nor that operative is within control range of an enemy operative. If you do, that
friendly operative isnt incapacitated, has 1 wound remaining and cannot be incapacitated for the
remainder of the action. After that action, that friendly operative can immediately perform a
free **Dash** action, but must end that move within this operatives control range. Subtract 1 from
this and that operatives APL stats until the end of their next activations respectively, and if
this rule was used during that friendly operatives activation, that activation ends.
You cannot use this rule if this operative is incapacitated, or if its a **Shoot** action and this
operative would be a primary or secondary target.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="exaction_medikit_usage"><![CDATA[
        1AP
    ]]></string>

    <string name="exaction_medikit_description"><![CDATA[
Select one friendly **EXACTION SQUAD** operative
within this operatives control range to regain up to 2D3 lost
wounds. It cannot be an operative that the Medic! rule was
used on during this turning point.\n\n

This operative cannot perform this action while within control
range of an enemy operative.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="handler_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="handler_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever this operative is
activated, you can activate a ready
friendly **EXACTION SQUAD R-VR
CYBER-MASTIFF** operative at the
same time. Complete their activations
action by action in any order.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="attack_pattern_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive/ Strategic Gambit

    ]]></string>

    <string name="attack_pattern_description"><![CDATA[
**STRATEGIC GAMBIT** in the first turning point. Select two
of the following attack patterns for a friendly **EXACTION SQUAD R-VR
CYBER-MASTIFF** operative to have for the battle:\n
\n
• Aggressive: Its melee weapons have the Relentless weapon rule.\n
• Swift: Add 2" to its Move stat.\n
• Defensive: Improve its Save stat by 1.\n
    ]]></string>

    <string name="rvr_command_usage"><![CDATA[

        0AP

    ]]></string>

    <string name="rvr_command_description"><![CDATA[
Select one friendly **EXACTION SQUAD R-VR
CYBER-MASTIFF** operative and change one of its
attack patterns.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="exaction_beast_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="exaction_beast_description"><![CDATA[
This operative cannot perform
any actions other than **Apprehend,
Charge, Dash, Fall Back, Fight,
Guard, Reposition, Pick Up
Marker** and **Place Marker**. It
cannot use any weapons that arent on
its datacard.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="apprehend_usage"><![CDATA[

        0AP

    ]]></string>

    <string name="apprehend_description"><![CDATA[
Select one enemy operative within this operatives control range. Until that enemy
operative is no longer within this operatives control range, or until this operative
performs this action again (whichever comes first), worsen the Hit stat of that
enemy operatives weapons by 1 (this isnt cumulative with being injured); in
addition, that enemy operative cannot perform the **Fall Back** action.\n\n
This operative cannot perform this action unless an enemy operative is within its
control range.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="engendered_focus_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="engendered_focus_description"><![CDATA[
You can ignore any changes to this
operatives stats (including its weapons’ stats, but excluding its
Save stat).
    ]]></string>

    <string name="zealous_dedication_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="zealous_dedication_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever an attack dice inflicts damage of
3 or more on this operative, roll one D6: on a 5+, subtract 1 from
that inflicted damage.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="castigator_arrest_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="castigator_arrest_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever an enemy operative is within
control range of this operative, if no other enemy operatives
are within this operatives control range, that enemy operative
cannot perform the **Fall Back** action.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="acute_focus_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="acute_focus_description"><![CDATA[
Once during each of this operatives activations, it can perform the
**Pick Up Marker, Place Marker, Veriscant** or a mission action for 1 less AP.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="veriscant_usage"><![CDATA[
        1AP
    ]]></string>

    <string name="veriscant_description"><![CDATA[
Select one enemy operative visible to this operative. Until the start of this operatives next
activation, until its incapacitated or until it performs this action again (whichever comes first),
whenever a friendly **EXACTION SQUAD** operative is shooting against, fighting against or
retaliating against that enemy operative, that friendly operatives weapons have the Lethal 5+
and Severe weapon rules.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="exaction_optics_usage"><![CDATA[
        1AP
    ]]></string>

    <string name="exaction_optics_description"><![CDATA[
Until the start of this operatives next activation:\n
• The concealed and stationary profiles of its executioner shotgun have the Lethal 5+ weapon rule.\n
• Whenever its shooting with its executioner shotgun, enemy operatives cannot be obscured.\n\n

This operative cannot perform this action while within control range of an enemy operative.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="first_in_the_field_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="first_in_the_field_description"><![CDATA[
**STRATEGIC GAMBIT** in the first turning point. If this operative is wholly
within your drop zone, it can immediately perform a free **Reposition** action.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="exaction_spot_usage"><![CDATA[
        1AP
    ]]></string>

    <string name="exaction_spot_description"><![CDATA[
Select one enemy operative visible to and within 8\" of this operative. Until the end of the turning
point, whenever a friendly **EXACTION SQUAD** operative is shooting that enemy operative,
you can use this effect. If you do:\n
\n
• That friendly operatives ranged weapons have the Seek Light weapon rule.\n
• That enemy operative cannot be obscured.\n\n
This operative cannot perform this action while within control range of an enemy operative.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="stubborn_subjugator_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="stubborn_subjugator_description"><![CDATA[
You can ignore any changes to the Hit stat of this operatives melee weapons.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="close_quarters_vigilance_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="close_quarters_vigilance_description"><![CDATA[
This operative can perform the **Shoot** action (excluding **Guard**) while within control range of
an enemy operative, but only if it hasnt performed the **Charge**
action during the activation, or if its a counteraction. Note this
operative isnt restricted from performing the **Charge** action
after performing the **Shoot** action.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="exaction_signal_usage"><![CDATA[
        1AP
    ]]></string>

    <string name="exaction_signal_description"><![CDATA[
**SUPPORT**. Select one other friendly **EXACTION
SQUAD** operative visible to this operative. Until the end of
that operatives next activation, add 1 to its APL stat.\n\n

This operative cannot perform this action while within control
range of an enemy operative.
    ]]></string>

    <!--Faction Rules-->

    <string name="ruthless_efficiency_lore"><![CDATA[
A target, whether marked to be apprehended or eliminated, stands little chance of escaping the
attention of an Adeptus Arbites Exaction Squad.
]]></string>

    <string name="ruthless_efficiency_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever a friendly EXACTION SQUAD operative is shooting (excluding with frag or krak
grenades) and you’re selecting a valid target, you can use this rule. If you do, having other friendly
EXACTION SQUAD operatives within an enemy operatives control range doesn’t prevent that
enemy operative from being selected.
]]></string>

    <string name="marked_for_justice_lore"><![CDATA[
Exaction Squads prioritise their targets, focusing their
ire on those marked for immediate punishment before
moving on to the next transgressor.
]]></string>

    <string name="marked_for_justice_description"><![CDATA[
STRATEGIC GAMBIT. Select one enemy operative
to be your mark for the turning point. Whenever a
friendly EXACTION SQUAD operative is shooting
against, fighting against or retaliating against
your mark, that friendly operatives weapons
have the Punishing weapon rule. Whenever your
mark is incapacitated, you can select a new
enemy operative to be your mark for the turning
point (and can continue to do so during this
turning point).
]]></string>

    <string name="repress_lore"><![CDATA[
Experienced in suppressing riots, rebellions and various
other kinds of unrest, the Adeptus Arbites are resilient
in the face of any oncoming foe, no matter their origin.
]]></string>

    <string name="repress_description"><![CDATA[
Some weapons in this teams rules have the Repress weapon rule below.\n
*Repress: Whenever this operative is using this weapon:\n
• Each of your blocks can be allocated to block two unresolved successes (instead of one).\n
• If this operative is retaliating, you resolve the first attack dice (i.e. defender instead
of attacker).
]]></string>


    <!--Equipment-->

    <string name="reinforced_mirrovisor_lore"><![CDATA[
This armoured visor is designed to shield the wearer
from blinding and disorientating weapons or devices.
]]></string>

    <string name="reinforced_mirrovisor_description"><![CDATA[
You can ignore any changes to the APL stat of friendly **EXACTION SQUAD** operatives, and
they arent affected by enemy operatives’ Shock weapon rule.
]]></string>

    <string name="manacles_lore"><![CDATA[
These adamantine manacles prevent captive subjects from escaping custody.
]]></string>

    <string name="manacles_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever an enemy operative would perform
the **Fall Back** action while within control range
of a friendly **EXACTION SQUAD** operative, if no
other enemy operatives are within that friendly
operatives control range, you can use this rule.
If you do, roll two D6, or one D6 if that enemy
operative has a higher Wounds stat than that
friendly operative. If any result is a 4+, that enemy
operative cannot perform that action during that
activation/counteraction (no AP are spent on it),
and you cannot use this rule again during this
turning point.
]]></string>

    <string name="strobing_phosphorlumen_lore"><![CDATA[
The brilliant white, flickering light of this rotating lumen
device has the effect of disorientating foes caught in its beam.
]]></string>

    <string name="strobing_phosphorlumen_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever an enemy operative is shooting against, fighting against or retaliating against a
friendly **EXACTION SQUAD** operative within 2\" of it, your opponent cannot re-roll their attack dice
results of 1.
]]></string>

    <string name="special_issue_shells_lore"><![CDATA[
Arbites shotguns can be loaded with a wide range of specialist ammunition, including but not limited to
incendiary rounds and armour-piercing slugs.
]]></string>

    <string name="special_issue_shells_description"><![CDATA[
Up to twice per turning point, when a friendly
**EXACTION SQUAD** operative is performing the
**Shoot** action and you select a combat shotgun,
executioner shotgun, scoped shotpistol or
shotpistol, you can use this rule. If you do, select
one of the following weapon rules for that weapon
to have until the end of that action:\n
• Saturate.\n
• Piercing 1, but only if the target has a Save stat of 3+ or better.\n
• Torrent 1", but you cannot select more than one secondary target.\n
]]></string>



    <!--Ploys-->
    <!--Strategy ploys-->
    <string name="guilt_reveals_itself_lore"><![CDATA[
Exaction Squads are relentless in their pursuit of the condemned. Few escape their clutches.
]]></string>

    <string name="guilt_reveals_itself_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever youre selecting a valid target for a friendly *EXACTION SQUAD* operative, enemy
operatives within 4\" of it cannot be in cover (instead of 2\"). While this can allow such
operatives to be targeted (assuming theyre visible), it doesnt remove their cover save (if
any), unless the friendly **EXACTION SQUAD** operative is within 2\" as normal.
]]></string>

    <string name="inviolate_jurisdiction_lore"><![CDATA[
Emboldened by the authority they hold, Exaction Squads will fight with zealous determination to
hold key positions against the foe.
]]></string>

    <string name="inviolate_jurisdiction_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever an operative is shooting a friendly **EXACTION SQUAD** operative thats within 2\" of
an objective marker or an enemy operative, you can re-roll one of your defence dice.
]]></string>

    <string name="dispense_justice_lore"><![CDATA[
In pursuit of the guilty, Arbitrators are focused, disciplined and utterly determined.
]]></string>

    <string name="dispense_justice_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever a friendly **EXACTION SQUAD** operative is fighting or retaliating, if it hasnt
moved more than its Move stat during the activation, or if its a counteraction, its melee
weapons have the Ceaseless weapon rule.
]]></string>

    <string name="terminal_decree_lore"><![CDATA[
A dangerous quarry has been judged guilty of heinous crimes against the Imperium and must
be terminated with extreme prejudice.
]]></string>

    <string name="terminal_decree_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever a friendly **EXACTION SQUAD** operative is shooting an enemy operative within
6\" of it, or whenever a friendly **EXACTION SQUAD GUNNER** operative is shooting, that
friendly operatives ranged weapons have the Balanced weapon rule.
]]></string>



    <!--Firefight ploys-->
    <string name="long_arm_emperor_law_lore"><![CDATA[
No one escapes the merciless judgement of the Adeptus Arbites.
]]></string>

    <string name="long_arm_emperor_law_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy when a friendly **EXACTION SQUAD** operative is performing the **Shoot**
action and you select a weapon with the Range x weapon rule (excluding frag or krak grenade).
Until the end of that action, add 3\" to x.
]]></string>

    <string name="exact_punishment_lore"><![CDATA[
To strike against an Arbitrator is an offence punishable by immediate termination.
]]></string>

    <string name="exact_punishment_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy after an enemy operative shoots against or fights against a friendly
**EXACTION SQUAD** operative within 6\" of it, and that friendly operative isnt incapacitated as a
result. That friendly operative can immediately perform either a free **Shoot** or a free **Fight** action,
but you cannot select any other enemy operative as a valid target or to fight against during that
action (note that secondary targets from the Blast weapon rule can still be targeted).
]]></string>

    <string name="brutal_backup_lore"><![CDATA[
When combating the most belligerent of foes,
Arbitrators may combine their considerable might to
bludgeon the guilty with baton and maul.
]]></string>

    <string name="brutal_backup_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy during a friendly **EXACTION
SQUAD** operatives activation, before or after it
performs an action. Select one enemy operative
within its control range. One other friendly
**EXACTION SQUAD** operative can immediately
perform a free **Fight** action, but you cannot select
any other enemy operative to fight against during
that action.
]]></string>

    <string name="execution_order_lore"><![CDATA[
Those who have earned the ire of the Imperium are
marked by the Adeptus Arbites for execution, their
termination prioritised.
]]></string>

    <string name="execution_order_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy when an enemy operative performs a mission action (excluding Operate
Hatch). Alternatively, use it at the end of the Firefight phase and select one enemy operative
that controls an objective marker. \n

In either case, the next time your opponent would
activate that enemy operative, you can interrupt
that activation and activate a ready friendly
**EXACTION SQUAD** operative. If you do, during
that activation, that friendly operative must shoot
against or fight against that enemy operative, and
cannot do so against any other enemy operatives
until it does (if this isnt possible, that friendly
operatives activation is cancelled).\n
After completing that friendly operatives
activation, continue that enemy operatives
activation (if possible). You cannot use this ploy
again until that enemy operative is activated
or incapacitated.
]]></string>
</resources>