<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>


    <!--Phobos-->

    <string name="tactical_advantage_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="tactical_advantage_description"><![CDATA[
You can do each of the following once per battle:\n
• After rolling-off to decide initiative, if this operative is in the killzone, you can re-roll your dice.\n
• You can use a firefight ploy for 0CP if this is the specified **PHOBOS STRIKE TEAM** operative (including Command Re-roll if the
attack or defence dice was rolled for this operative), or the Patient Ambush firefight ploy for 0CP if this operative is ready and not
within control range of enemy operatives
    ]]></string>

    <string name="strategic_oversight_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="strategic_oversight_description"><![CDATA[
In the Ready step of each Strategy phase, when you gain CP, if this operative is in the killzone and is not within
control range of enemy operatives, you can use this rule. If you do, roll one D6: on a 4+, you gain one additional CP
    ]]></string>

    <string name="comms_array_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="comms_array_description"><![CDATA[
Once per turning point, during a friendly **PHOBOS STRIKE TEAM** operatives activation or counteraction, before
or after it performs an action, if this operative is in the killzone, you can change one strategy ploy you have used this turning point (it
does not cost you any CP to do so).
    ]]></string>

    <string name="phobos_medic_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="phobos_medic_description"><![CDATA[
The first time during each turning point that another friendly **PHOBOS STRIKE TEAM** operative would be incapacitated
while visible to and within 3\" of this operative, you can use this rule, providing neither this nor that operative is within control range of
an enemy operative. If you do, that friendly operative is not incapacitated, has D3 wounds remaining and cannot be incapacitated for
the remainder of the action. After that action, that friendly operative can immediately perform a free **Dash** action, but must end that
move within this operative’s control range. Subtract 1 from this and that operatives APL stats until the end of their next activations
respectively, and if this rule was used during that friendly operatives activation, that activation ends. You cannot use this rule if this
operative is incapacitated, or if it is a **Shoot** action and this operative would be a primary or secondary target.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="helix_gauntlet_usage"><![CDATA[
       1AP
    ]]></string>

    <string name="helix_gauntlet_description"><![CDATA[
Select one friendly **PHOBOS STRIKE TEAM** operative
within this operatives control range to regain up to D3+3 lost
wounds. It cannot be an operative that the Medic! rule was
used on during this turning point.\n\n
This operative cannot perform this action while within control
range of an enemy operative.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="plant_explosives_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="plant_explosives_description"><![CDATA[
This operative is carrying your Explosives marker. It can perform the **Pick Up Marker** action on that marker, and
whenever it performs the Place Marker action on that marker, it can immediately perform a free **Dash** action
    ]]></string>

    <string name="phobos_detonate_usage"><![CDATA[

        Special Weapon Rule

    ]]></string>

    <string name="phobos_detonate_description"><![CDATA[
Do not select a valid target. Instead, shoot against each operative within 2\" of your Explosives marker, unless Heavy terrain
is wholly intervening between that operative and that marker. Each of those operatives cannot be in cover or obscured. Roll each
sequence separately in an order of your choice. This weapon cannot be selected if your Explosives marker is not in the killzone. At the
end of the action, remove your Explosives marker from the killzone. In a killzone that uses the close quarters rules (e.g. Killzone: Tomb
World), this weapon has the Lethal 5+ weapon rule.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="custom_usage"><![CDATA[

        Special Weapon Rule

    ]]></string>

    <string name="custom_description"><![CDATA[
At the end of the Select Operatives step, if this
operative is selected for deployment, select up to two of the
following weapon rules for this weapon to have for the battle:
Balanced, Lethal 5+, Piercing Crits 1, Rending, Saturate.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="voxbreak_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="voxbreak_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever an enemy operative
is within 6\" of this operative, your
opponent cannot re-roll their attack or
defence dice for that operative.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="phobos_auspex_scan_usage"><![CDATA[
        1AP
    ]]></string>

    <string name="phobos_auspex_scan_description"><![CDATA[
Until the start of this operatives next activation or until it is incapacitated
(whichever comes first), whenever a friendly **PHOBOS STRIKE TEAM**
operative is shooting an enemy operative within 8\" of this operative, that enemy
operative cannot be obscured; if that friendly operative is an **INCURSOR**, its
ranged weapons also have the Seek Light weapon rule.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="vanguard_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="vanguard_description"><![CDATA[
Once per turning point, one friendly **PHOBOS
STRIKE TEAM** operative with this rule can perform the **Pick
Up Marker** or a mission action for 1 less AP.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="track_target_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="track_target_description"><![CDATA[
This operative can perform the **Guard** action
during its activation regardless of the killzone (see close quarters
rules, Kill Team Core Book). It can perform the **Guard** action
while it has a **Conceal** order, but when you perform the free
**Shoot** or **Fight** action during the interruption, you must change
its order to **Engage**.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="haywire_mine_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="haywire_mine_description"><![CDATA[
This operative is carrying your Haywire Mine
marker. It can perform the **Pick Up Marker** action on that
marker, but that marker cannot be placed within an enemy
operatives control range (if this operative is incapacitated while
carrying that marker and that marker cannot be placed, it is
removed with this operative).
    ]]></string>

    <string name="phobos_proximity_mine_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="phobos_proximity_mine_description"><![CDATA[
The first time your Haywire Mine marker is
within another operatives control range, remove that marker,
subtract 1 from that operatives APL stat until the end of
its next activation, and inflict 2D3+3 damage on it; if it is not
incapacitated, end its action (if any), even if that actions effects
are not fulfilled. If it cannot be placed, move it the minimum
amount to do so. Note that this operative is ignored for these
effects (i.e. it cannot set it off or take damage from that marker).
    ]]></string>

    <string name="phobos_gravchute_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="phobos_gravchute_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever this operative is climbing up, you can treat the vertical distance as 2\" (regardless of
how far the operative actually moves vertically). Whenever this operative is dropping, ignore the vertical distance.
    ]]></string>


    <!--Faction Rules-->

    <string name="omni_scrambler_lore"><![CDATA[
Backpack-mounted omni-scramblers serve to disrupt
enemy communications.
]]></string>

    <string name="omni_scrambler_description"><![CDATA[
**STRATEGIC GAMBIT** if a friendly **INFILTRATOR**
operative is in the killzone. Select one enemy
operative visible to a friendly **INFILTRATOR**
operative, or within 6\" of a friendly **VOXBREAKER**
operative. In the Firefight phase of this turning
point, that enemy operative cannot be activated
or perform actions until one of the following
is true:\n
\n
• Your opponent has activated a number of enemy operatives equal to the number of
friendly **INFILTRATOR** operatives in the killzone when this **STRATEGIC GAMBIT** was used.\n
\n
• It’s the last enemy operative to be activated.
]]></string>

    <string name="terror_lore"><![CDATA[
Dedicated terror troops, Space Marine Reivers utilise
skull masks, shock grenades and vox-enhanced roars to
terrify their victims.
]]></string>

    <string name="terror_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever an enemy operative is within 3\" of
friendly **REIVER** operatives, your opponent must
spend 1 additional AP for that enemy operative to
perform the **Pick Up Marker** and mission actions.\n
Whenever determining control of a marker,
treat the total APL stat of enemy operatives
that contest it as 1 lower if at least one of those
enemy operatives is within 3\" of friendly **REIVER**
operatives. Note this is not a change to the APL
stat, so any changes are cumulative with this.
]]></string>

    <string name="phobos_astartes_lore"><![CDATA[
These genetically modified superhumans are made for
one purpose: war.
]]></string>

    <string name="phobos_astartes_description"><![CDATA[
During each friendly **PHOBOS STRIKE TEAM**
operatives activation, it can perform either two
**Shoot** actions or two **Fight** actions. If it is two
**Shoot** actions, a bolt weapon must be selected
for at least one of them. A bolt weapon is any
ranged weapon that includes bolt in its name,
e.g. marksman bolt carbine, special issue bolt
pistol, etc.\n
Each friendly **PHOBOS STRIKE TEAM** operative
can counteract regardless of its order.
]]></string>

    <string name="multispectrum_array_lore"><![CDATA[
Feeding into the auto-senses of the bearers armour, the
multi-spectrum arrays powerful augurs help to reveal
hidden foes.
]]></string>

    <string name="multispectrum_array_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever a friendly **INCURSOR** operative is
shooting, enemy operatives cannot be obscured.
]]></string>


    <!--Equipment-->

    <string name="phobos_purity_seal_lore"><![CDATA[
Awarded by the Chapters Chaplains, purity seals are
inscribed with blessings and inspire the bearer to fight
with increased vigour.
]]></string>

    <string name="phobos_purity_seal_description"><![CDATA[
Once per turning point, when a friendly **PHOBOS
STRIKE TEAM** operative is shooting, fighting or
retaliating, if you roll two or more fails, you can
discard one of them to retain another as a normal
success instead.
]]></string>

    <string name="additional_utility_lore"><![CDATA[
Some Space Marines opt to carry additional smoke
grenades, shock grenades and other forms of
hand-held explosives.
]]></string>

    <string name="additional_utility_description"><![CDATA[
This equipment allows you to select four utility
grenades from the utility grenades equipment
(see universal equipment). You cannot also select
that equipment as normal (i.e. to give you six).
]]></string>

    <string name="phobos_combat_blades_lore"><![CDATA[
These blades are tough, thick and possess a razor-sharp
cutting edge.
]]></string>

    <string name="phobos_combat_blades_description"><![CDATA[
Friendly **PHOBOS STRIKE TEAM** operatives have
the following melee weapon:
]]></string>

    <string name="phobos_special_issue_ammunition_lore"><![CDATA[
Space Marine bolt weapons can be loaded with a variety
of special ammunition.
]]></string>

    <string name="phobos_special_issue_ammunition_description"><![CDATA[
Once per turning point, when a friendly **PHOBOS
STRIKE TEAM** operative is performing the
**Shoot** action and you select a bolt carbine,
marksman bolt carbine or occulus bolt carbine,
you can use this rule. If you do, until the end of
the turning point, that weapon has the Piercing 1
weapon rule.
]]></string>



    <!--Ploys-->
    <!--Strategy ploys-->
    <string name="guerrilla_warfare_lore"><![CDATA[
Phobos Strike Teams utilise stealth and ambush tactics
to overwhelm their foes, striking when least expected.
]]></string>

    <string name="guerrilla_warfare_description"><![CDATA[
Friendly **PHOBOS STRIKE TEAM** operatives can
perform the following unique action:
]]></string>

    <string name="guerrilla_warfare_usage"><![CDATA[
1AP
]]></string>

    <string name="guerrilla_warfare_description2"><![CDATA[
Change this operatives order.\n\n
An operative cannot perform this action while within control range of an enemy operative.
]]></string>

    <string name="phobos_no_fear_lore"><![CDATA[
Space Marines possess superhuman courage and are
utterly unflinching in the face of terrifying horrors and
overwhelming odds.
]]></string>

    <string name="phobos_no_fear_description"><![CDATA[
You can ignore any changes to the stats of
friendly **PHOBOS STRIKE TEAM** operatives from
being injured (including their weapons stats).
]]></string>

    <string name="deadly_shots_lore"><![CDATA[
Space Marines spend countless hours perfecting
their marksmanship.
]]></string>

    <string name="deadly_shots_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever a friendly **PHOBOS STRIKE TEAM**
operative is shooting during an activation in
which it has not performed the **Charge, Fall Back**
or **Reposition** action, or against an operative
that is not in cover and is more than 6\" from it,
that friendly operatives ranged weapons have
the Balanced weapon rule. Note that for the first
requirement, that operative is not restricted from
performing those actions after shooting.
]]></string>

    <string name="lethal_assaults_lore"><![CDATA[
Space Marine warriors strike down their foes with
incredible power and precision.
]]></string>

    <string name="lethal_assaults_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever a friendly **PHOBOS STRIKE TEAM**
operative is fighting, its melee weapons have the
Balanced weapon rule. If that friendly operative
is doing so during an activation in which it
performed the Charge action, its melee weapons
also have the Lethal 5+ weapon rule.
]]></string>



    <!--Firefight ploys-->
    <string name="patient_ambush_lore"><![CDATA[
A Phobos Strike Team may lay in wait for hours, days
or even weeks before launching an assault upon an
unsuspecting enemy.
]]></string>

    <string name="patient_ambush_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy when it is your turn to
activate a friendly operative. You can skip
that activation.
]]></string>

    <string name="critical_shot_lore"><![CDATA[
A well-placed bolt round can fell even the most resilient
of foes.
]]></string>

    <string name="critical_shot_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy when you resolve a critical
success for a friendly **PHOBOS STRIKE TEAM**
operative that is shooting with a bolt weapon.
Inflict D3 additional damage.
]]></string>

    <string name="phobos_transhuman_lore"><![CDATA[
The genetically modified physiology of a Space
Marine is capable of resisting wounds that would kill a
lesser being.
]]></string>

    <string name="phobos_transhuman_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy when an operative is
shooting a friendly **PHOBOS STRIKE TEAM**
operative, in the Roll Defence Dice step. You can
retain one of your normal successes as a critical
success instead.
]]></string>

    <string name="stealth_assault_lore"><![CDATA[
The silenced servos of Phobos-pattern power armour
allow a Space Marine to strike swiftly and overwhelm a
surprised foe.
]]></string>

    <string name="stealth_assault_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy when a friendly **PHOBOS
STRIKE TEAM** operative that has a **Conceal**
order is activated, is given an **Engage** order,
performs the **Charge** and then the **Fight** action,
and you are resolving your first attack dice
from this activation. After doing so, you can
immediately resolve another of your attack dice
(before your opponent). The operative cannot
have performed any other actions during this
activation (but can do so after resolving this ploy).
]]></string>

</resources>