<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <!--Wreckas-->

    <string name="wrecka_demolisha_recklesstemperament"><![CDATA[

        Reckless Temperament

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wrecka_demolisha_recklesstemperament_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wrecka_demolisha_recklesstemperament_description"><![CDATA[

        If this Operative has a Conceal order, Normal damage of 4 or more inflicts
                     1 less damage. If this Operative has an Engage order, this rule applies for
                    Normal and Critical damage.

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wrecka_demolisha_detonate"><![CDATA[

        Detonate

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wrecka_demolisha_detonate_usage"><![CDATA[

        Special Weapon Rule

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wrecka_demolisha_detonate_description"><![CDATA[

        The first time you would inflict damage on an enemy Operative with this weapon profile
                 during the battle, on a normal success, inflict D6+6 damage on that enemy Operative
                 and each other Operative within this Operativs control range (Roll separately for each),
                    on a critical do the same but for 2D6+6. Then the action ends and you gain 1 Wrecka point +1
                    for each operative that was incapacitated during this action. Damage from
        this weapon cannot be reduced or ignored.

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wrecka_fighter"><![CDATA[

        BREAK STUFF

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wrecka_fighter_usage"><![CDATA[

        1 AP/Firefight Phase

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wrecka_fighter_description"><![CDATA[

        Select a terrain feature within the control range of this Operative. If is an
                     equipment terrain, remove it. Otherwise, place one of your Breach markers within
                     this Operatives control range as close as possible to that terrain feature.
                     Whenever an Operative is within 1\" of that marker, it treats parts of that terrain
                     feature that are no more than 1\" thick as Accessible terrain\n\nThis
                    operative CANNOT perform this action while within control range of an enemy
                    Operative, or if a terrain feature isnt within its control range.

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wrecka_gunner"><![CDATA[

        Kompetitive Streak

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wrecka_gunner_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wrecka_gunner_description"><![CDATA[

        Once per **Shoot** action, if this operative shoots an enemy Operative that
                     another friendly Operative has already Shot during this turning point, you
                     gain 1 Wrecka point. Determine this when you select a valid target, but you can
                     include any secondary targets when doing so (Ex from the Blast weapon rule).

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wrecka_krusha_armoured"><![CDATA[

        Armoured Up

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wrecka_krusha_armoured_usage"><![CDATA[

        Pasive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wrecka_krusha_armoured_description"><![CDATA[

        Whenever an enemy Operative is Shooting, or this operative is Fighting or
                    Retaliating, your opponent cannot retain a dice result less than 6 as a Critical
                    success (Ex Severe,Lethal,Rending weapon rules)

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wrecka_krusha_smash"><![CDATA[

        Smash

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wrecka_krusha_smash_usage"><![CDATA[

        Special Weapon Rule

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wrecka_krusha_smash_description"><![CDATA[

        Whenever you strike, you can move the enemy Operative in a straight line increment
                 of up to 1\". If you do, it must end the move further away from this Operative and
                 in a location it can be placed. Then move this Operative in a straight line the same
                 distance, but it must end that move within that enemy Operatives control range
                (If neither is possible, you cannot move them).

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wrecka_rokkiteer_shock"><![CDATA[

        Shokkwave

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wrecka_rokkiteer_shock_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wrecka_rokkiteer_shock_description"><![CDATA[

        Whenever an operative is within your Pulsa area of effect, subtract 2\"
                    from its Move stat and worsen the hit stat of its weapons by 1. This is
                    Cumulative with being injured.\nIn the Ready step of each Strategy phase,
                    subtract 1 from your Pulsa markers points, If it reaches 0 points, remove it.\n
                    (In practice, your Pulsa area of effect is smaller every turning pont.)

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wrecka_pulsa"><![CDATA[

        Pulsa

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wrecka_pulsa_usage"><![CDATA[

        Special Weapon Rule

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wrecka_pulsa_description"><![CDATA[

        Dont select a valid target, place your Pulsa marker visible to this operative, or
                 on Vantage terrain of a terrain feature that is visible to this operative. That marker
                 gains 1 Pulsa point, then roll attack dice as normal.\n It gains 1 additional Pulsa
                 point for each success(up to 3 additional points). \n This token has an area of effect
                 equal to its pulsa points, every point is 1\" of additional distance (To a max of 4\").
                \n Deal D3 damage on each operative wholly within your Pulsa marker range(Roll for each).

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wreckaboss"><![CDATA[

        Wrecka Boss

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wreckaboss_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wreckaboss_description"><![CDATA[

        Whenever this operative performs the **Shoot** or **Fight** action (Excluding
                    **Guard**), you gain 1 Wrecka point

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wrecka_salvo"><![CDATA[

        Salvo

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wrecka_salvo_usage"><![CDATA[

        Special Weapon Rule

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wrecka_salvo_description"><![CDATA[

        Select up to Two different valid targets that arent within control range of friendly
                 Operatives. Shoot with this weapon against both primary targets in an order of your
                 choice, then against all remaining secondary targets if any. Each target (primary
                 and secondary) cannot be shot more than once during the action.

    ]]></string>

    <string name="squig_explosive"><![CDATA[

        Explosive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="squig_explosive_usage"><![CDATA[

        Special Weapon Rule

    ]]></string>

    <string name="squig_explosive_description"><![CDATA[

        This operative can perform the Shoot action with this weapon while being in control
                 range of an enemy operative, Dont select a valid target. Instead, this operative is always
                 the primary target and cannot be in cover or Obscured.

    ]]></string>

    <string name="squig_stoopid"><![CDATA[

        Stoopid

    ]]></string>

    <string name="squig_stoopid_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="squig_stoopid_description"><![CDATA[

        In the Firefight phase, whenever you determine this operatives order
                    , you cannot select conceal. This Operative cannot perform any action other than
                     **CHARGE**, **DASH**, **FIGHT**, **REPOSITION** and **SHOOT**. It cannot use any weapons that
                    arent on its datacard.

    ]]></string>

    <string name="squig_expendable"><![CDATA[

        Expendable

    ]]></string>

    <string name="squig_expendable_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="squig_expendable_description"><![CDATA[

        This operative is ignored for your opponents kill op(Making this team a
                     6 Operatives Kill team). Its also ignored for victory conditions and scoring VPs
                     if either require operatives to \"escape\" or \"survive\" or be incapacitated by
                     enemy Operatives.

    ]]></string>

    <string name="squig_boom"><![CDATA[

        Boom!

    ]]></string>

    <string name="squig_boom_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive, when this operative is incapacitated

    ]]></string>

    <string name="squig_boom_description"><![CDATA[

        If this Operative is incapacitated during the battle in which it hasnt
                    used its explosives, roll one D6, or two D6 if you wish. If any result is 4+,
                     this Operative performs a free Shoot action with its explosives before is removed
                     from the game.

    ]]></string>

    <!--/Equipment Wreckas-->

    <string name="wrecka_drillrokkit"><![CDATA[

        DRILL ROKKITS

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wrecka_drillrokkit_lore"><![CDATA[

        Mek ingenuity knows few bounds. Drill rokkits are designed to strike a target
                        " and bore through thick armour before exploding(Like 3+ Saves).

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wrecka_drillrokkit_description"><![CDATA[

        Once per turning point, when a friendly **WRECKA KREW** Operative is
                         performing the **Shoot** action and you select a **Rokkit launcha** or
                         **Eavy rokkit launcha**, you can use this rule. If you do, until the end
                         of that action, that weapon loses the Blast weapon rule but has the Piercing 1
                         weapon rule (You cant combine this with the **Kaboom** Firefight ploy).

    ]]></string>


    <string name="wrecka_extra_armour"><![CDATA[

        EXTRA ARMOUR

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wrecka_extra_armour_lore"><![CDATA[

        Scrap metal Ork armour may appear haphazard, but it is no less effective for
                         its simple construction.

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wrecka_extra_armour_description"><![CDATA[

        Subtract 1\" from the Move stat of friendly **WRECKA KREW** Operatives
                        and improve their Save stat by 1. This excludes **BOMB SQUIG** Operatives
                        and isnt cumulative with the Protective rule of a Portable Barricade from
                        universal equipment.

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wrecka_engine_oil"><![CDATA[

        ENGINE OIL

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wrecka_engine_oil_lore"><![CDATA[

        Wrecka Krews are known yo ingest the oils of vehicles they have destroyed.
                         The intoxicating fluid bolsters their natural resilience.

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wrecka_engine_oil_description"><![CDATA[

        Once per turning point, when a friendly **WRECKA KREW** Operative
                         (Excluding **BOMB SQUIG**) is activated, you can use this rule. If you do
                        , until the end of that activation, you can ignore any changes to that
                        Operatives from being injured (including its weapons stats).

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wrecka_glyphs"><![CDATA[

        GLYPHS

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wrecka_glyphs_lore"><![CDATA[

        Back-banners, crude markings and glyph-scrawled armour proudly display the
                         Wrecka Krews favoured method of destruction.

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wrecka_glyphs_description"><![CDATA[

        When this equipment is selected, also select between the ploys
                         **Waaagh!** or **Destruction**. The first time you would use that ploy
                         during the battle, it costs you 0CP; whenever you would use it thereafter,
                         it costs you 0CP if you have any Wrecka points.

    ]]></string>

    /Faction Rules


    <string name="wrecka_rampage"><![CDATA[

        WRECKA RAMPAGE

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wrecka_rampage_lore"><![CDATA[

        The sound of explosions, thea acrid stench of smoke and screams of battle drive
                         Wrecka Krews forwards to ever more destructive acts.

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wrecka_rampage_description"><![CDATA[

        Whenever a friendly **WRECKA KREW** Operative is shooting, fighting or
                         retaliating in the Roll Attack Dice step:\n\n•For each attack dice result
                        of 6 you retain, you gain one Wrecka point.\n•You can spend up to 3 of
                        your Wrecka points (unless it’s a **BOMB SQUIG**). For each point you spend this
                         way, retain one of your fails as a normal success instead of discarding it.\n\n
                        You cannot have more than 6 Wrecka points at once. You can gain and spend
                        Wrecka points during the same action and can do so in an order of your choice,
                        unless you started the action with 6, in which case you can
                        only spend them.

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wrecka_tanked_up"><![CDATA[

        TANKED UP

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wrecka_tanked_up_lore"><![CDATA[

        Wrecka Krews are empowered by by the thrill of explosive combat, lending them
                         fresh impetus as they undertake their murderous rampages.

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wrecka_tanked_up_description"><![CDATA[

        The first time a friendly **WRECKA KREW** Operative (excluding **BOMB SGUIG**)
                        that has an Engage order performs either the **Charge**, **Shoot** or **Fight** action
                         (excluding **Guard**) during each of its activations/counteractions, add 1 to
                         its APL stat until the start of its next activation

    ]]></string>

    /Ploys
    /Strategic Ploy
    <string name="wrecka_waaagh"><![CDATA[

        WAAAGH!

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wrecka_waaagh_lore"><![CDATA[

        When the Wrecka Krews violent rampage reaches its crescendo, a rage overcomes
                         them. They bellow the infamous Ork battle cry as they set upon their enemies
                         with hammer and fist.

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wrecka_waaagh_description"><![CDATA[

        Friendly **WRECKA KREW** Operatives melee weapons have the Balanced
                         weapon rule.

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wrecka_tuff_gitz"><![CDATA[

        TUFF GITZ

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wrecka_tuff_gitz_lore"><![CDATA[

        Wrecka Krews dont have time for mukkin about. Theyll gladly take a hit
                         if it means they get to land a few of their own.

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wrecka_tuff_gitz_description"><![CDATA[

        Whenever an Operative is shooting a friendly **WRECKA KREW** Operative
                        that has an **Engage** order, you can re-roll one of you defense dice.

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wrecka_destruction"><![CDATA[

        DESTRUCTION

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wrecka_destruction_lore"><![CDATA[

        If an enemy takes cover, this just proves Wrecka krews with the opportunity
                         to blow more stuff up.

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wrecka_destruction_description"><![CDATA[

        Friendly WRECKA KREW Operatives ranged weapons have the Saturate
                         weapon rule.

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wrecka_amped_up"><![CDATA[

        AMPED UP

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wrecka_amped_up_lore"><![CDATA[

        Orks thrive in the chaos and cacophony of battle. The greater the explosions
                         and destruction around them, the more their adrenaline kicks in. When whipped
                         up into such a fury, they can fight on through injuries that would ordinarily
                         lay them low.

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wrecka_amped_up_description"><![CDATA[

        Each friendly **WRECKA KREW** Operative that has an **Engage** order
                         can immediately regain up to D3+1 lost wounds (roll separately for each).

    ]]></string>

    /Firefight Ploy

    <string name="wrecka_demolition_job"><![CDATA[

        DEMOLITION JOB

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wrecka_demolition_job_lore"><![CDATA[

        Should a prime target present itself, the Wrecka Krew will unleash their
                         combined destructive might, demolishing anything in the vicinity.

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wrecka_demolition_job_description"><![CDATA[

        Use this firefight ploy after a friendly **WRECKA KREW** Operative
                         performs the **Shoot** or **Fight** action; just before incapacitated
                         Operatives are removed (if any). Place one of your Demolition markers within
                         the targets control range (if its using a Blast weapon, the primary target).
                         Whenever a friendly **WRECKA KREW** Operative (excluding BOMB **SQUIG**)
                         is shooting against, fighting against, or retaliating against an Operative
                         thats within 3\" of that marker, you can spend a Wrecka pont for free (
                        even if you have none). In the Ready step of the next Strategy phase, remove
                         that marker.

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wrecka_proppa_scrap"><![CDATA[

        PROPPA SCRAP

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wrecka_proppa_scrap_lore"><![CDATA[

        Orks like nothing better than a good scrap. With fist or hammer, they seek to
                     demonstrate that might is right.

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wrecka_proppa_scrap_description"><![CDATA[

        Use this firefight ploy during a **WRECKA KREW BREAKKA BOY** or **WRECKA
                     KREW BOSS NOB** Operatives activation. During that activation, that Operative
                     can perform two **Fight** actions.

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wrecka_kaboom"><![CDATA[

        KABOOM!

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wrecka_kaboom_lore"><![CDATA[

        The more intense the dakka and the louder the boom explosions, the more
                         satisfying the carnage!

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wrecka_kaboom_description"><![CDATA[

        Use this firefight ploy when a friendly **WRECKA KREW** Operative
                         performs the **Shoot** action and a weapon with Blast is selected. Until
         the end of that action, add 1\" to that Blast range, and it has the Severe
                         weapon rule when shooting the primary target. You cannot use this ploy and
                         the **Drill Rokkits** rule, note that Severe as not being a natural 6, doesnt
                         generate Wrecka points.

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wrecka_jas"><![CDATA[

        JUST A SCRATCH

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wrecka_jas_lore"><![CDATA[

        The favorite for Ork players, Orks have a remarkable ability to shrug off
                        grievous damage that would incapacitate most other creatures.

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wrecka_jas_description"><![CDATA[

        Use this firefight ploy when an attack dice inflicts Normal Dmg on a friendly
                         **WRECKA KREW** Operative (excluding **BOMB SQUIG**). ignore that inflicted
                         damage.

    ]]></string>



</resources>