<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>


    <!--Chaos Cult-->

    <string name="incite_slaughter_usage"><![CDATA[
        1AP
    ]]></string>

    <string name="incite_slaughter_description"><![CDATA[
**SUPPORT.** One other friendly **CHAOS CULT** operative
visible to and within 9\" of this operative can immediately
perform a free **Fight** action.\n\n

This operative cannot perform this action while within control
range of an enemy operative.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="incite_urgency_usage"><![CDATA[
        1AP
    ]]></string>

    <string name="incite_urgency_description"><![CDATA[
**SUPPORT.** One other friendly **CHAOS CULT** operative
visible to and within 9\" of this operative can immediately
perform a free **Charge** or **Dash** action (for the former, it
cannot move more than 3\").
    ]]></string>


    <string name="cut_them_down_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="cut_them_down_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever an enemy operative performs the
**Fall Back** action while within control range of this operative,
you can use this rule. If you do, inflict D3+1 damage on that
enemy operative before it moves. If that enemy operative is
within control range of two of these operatives, inflict 2D3+2
damage instead.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="attune_in_purpose_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="attune_in_purpose_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever this operative is activated,
you can activate another ready friendly **BLESSED BLADE**
operative within 6\" of it at the same time. Complete their
activations action by action in any order.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="chaos_icon_bearer_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="chaos_icon_bearer_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever determining control of a marker, treat
this operatives APL stat as 1 higher. Note this is not a change to
its APL stat, so any changes are cumulative with this.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="ruinous_icon_usage"><![CDATA[
        1AP
    ]]></string>

    <string name="ruinous_icon_description"><![CDATA[
**PSYCHIC**. Select one of the following effects to last
until the start of this operative’s next activation, until
it’s incapacitated or until it performs this action again
(whichever comes first):\n
\n
• Invigoration: **PSYCHIC.** Whenever a friendly **CHAOS
CULT** operative is within 4\" of this operative, Normal
and Critical Dmg of 4 or more inflicts 1 less damage on that operative.\n
\n
Deterioration: **PSYCHIC**. Whenever an enemy
operative is within 4\" of this operative, Normal and Critical
Dmg inflicts 1 more damage on that operative.\n\n

This operative cannot perform this action while within control range of an enemy operative.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="heinous_deluge_usage"><![CDATA[
        1AP
    ]]></string>

    <string name="heinous_deluge_description"><![CDATA[
**PSYCHIC**. Select one enemy operative that is a valid target for this operative. Until the end of that
operatives next activation, subtract 1 from its APL stat.\n\n

This operative cannot perform this action while within control range of an enemy operative.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="malefic_vortex_usage"><![CDATA[
        1AP
    ]]></string>

    <string name="malefic_vortex_description"><![CDATA[
**PSYCHIC.** Remove your Malefic Vortex marker from the killzone (if any). Then
place your Malefic Vortex marker visible to this operative, or on Vantage terrain of
a terrain feature that is visible to this operative. Inflict 1 damage on each enemy
operative within 2\" of that marker. In addition, in the Ready step of each Strategy
phase, inflict 1 damage on each enemy operative within 2\" of that marker.\n\n

This operative cannot perform this action while within control range of an enemy operative.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="chaos_group_activacion_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="chaos_group_activacion_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever this operative is expended, you must then activate one other ready friendly **CHAOS CULT
DEVOTEE** operative (if able) before your opponent activates.
When that other operative is expended, your opponent then
activates as normal (in other words, you cannot activate more
than two operatives in succession with this rule).
    ]]></string>

    <string name="accursed_mutant_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="accursed_mutant_description"><![CDATA[
This operative cannot perform unique actions. You must spend 1 additional AP for this operative to
perform the **Pick Up Marker** and mission actions (excluding **Operate Hatch**).
    ]]></string>

    <string name="unnatural_regeneration_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="unnatural_regeneration_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever an attack dice inflicts damage of 3 or more on this operative, roll one D6: on a 5+,
subtract 1 from that inflicted damage.
    ]]></string>

    <!--Faction Rules-->

    <string name="accursed_gifts_lore"><![CDATA[
Accursed followers of Chaos are blessed by the gods
with a horrifying array of mutations. Chiropteran wings,
rigid horns, wicked claws and dextrous tentacles: all of
these diabolical gifts are used to devastating effect.
]]></string>

    <string name="accursed_gifts_description"><![CDATA[
**ACCURSED GIFTS** are rules that friendly **CHAOS
CULT** operatives gain when they turn into
another operative type (see **Mutation** faction
rule). The first time a friendly **DEVOTEE** operative
turns into a **MUTANT** operative during the battle,
select your primary **ACCURSED GIFT**. The first
time a friendly **MUTANT** operative turns into a
**TORMENT** operative during the battle, select your
secondary **ACCURSED GIFT**.\n
\n
All friendly **MUTANT** operatives have your primary
**ACCURSED GIFT**, and all friendly **TORMENT**
operatives have your primary and secondary
**ACCURSED GIFTS**. You cannot select the same
**ACCURSED GIFT** more than once per battle.
]]></string>

    <string name="gift1_lore"><![CDATA[
Tattered, leathery wings burst from heaving folds of
flesh. These infernal mutations allow their wretched
bearer to ascend and drop into the fray with
terrifying agility.
]]></string>

    <string name="gift1_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever this operative is climbing up, you can
treat the vertical distance as 2\" (regardless of
how far the operative actually moves vertically).
Whenever this operative is dropping, ignore the
vertical distance.
]]></string>


    <string name="gift2_lore"><![CDATA[
Muscular, misshapen limbs, undulating tentacles and
slime-slick extrusions propel mutant Cultists across
the battlefield with a speed that is as shocking as it
is horrific.
]]></string>

    <string name="gift2_description"><![CDATA[
Add 1\" to this operatives Move stat.
]]></string>


    <string name="gift3_lore"><![CDATA[
Hardened plates formed of chitinous, daemonic material
erupt from angry, swollen flesh, lending the accursed
unholy resilience and turning lasbolts, bullets and
blades aside.
]]></string>

    <string name="gift3_description"><![CDATA[
Improve this operatives Save stat by 1.
]]></string>


    <string name="gift4_lore"><![CDATA[
Pairs of sharp, curved horns protrude from the
foreheads of some mutant Cultists, used to charge, gore
and impale their victims.
]]></string>

    <string name="gift4_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever this operative ends its move during the
**Charge** action, you can inflict 1 damage on one
enemy operative within its control range, or D3
damage instead if this operative is a **TORMENT**.
]]></string>


    <string name="gift5_lore"><![CDATA[
Within this Cultists twisted form, hardened sinews and
tendons bind muscle, lending monstrous strength to
each and every strike they make.
]]></string>

    <string name="gift5_description"><![CDATA[
You can ignore any changes to the Hit stat of this
operatives melee weapons from being injured.
This operatives melee weapons have the Brutal
weapon rule.
]]></string>


    <string name="gift6_lore"><![CDATA[
This Cultists body and weapons are coated with sharp
barbs that bite into those nearby, ripping flesh and
spilling blood.
]]></string>

    <string name="gift6_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever this operative is fighting or retaliating:\n
\n
• Enemy operatives cannot assist.\n
\n
• The first time you strike during that sequence, also inflict 1 damage on each other enemy
operative within this operatives control range, or D3 damage instead if this operative is a
**TORMENT* (roll separately for each).
]]></string>

    <string name="mutation_lore"><![CDATA[
Through arcane ritual, the most devoted among a
Chaos Cult have profane symbols carved into their
flesh or tattooed onto their skin. Should the correct
words of invocation be uttered, these icons appear to
draw empyric power, mutating the form of the devotee.
This does not satisfy the dark cravings and power lust
of some; depraved prayers are written upon flayed
skin and nailed into tormented flesh, and daemons are
summoned and bound into mortal bodies.
]]></string>

    <string name="mutation_description"><![CDATA[
During the battle, friendly **CHAOS CULT** operatives can **MUTATE** as follows:\n
\n
• As a **STRATEGIC GAMBIT**, you can **MUTATE** a number of friendly **CHAOS CULT** operatives
based on the turning point as follows: TP1 = 2, TP2 = 2, TP3 = 3, TP4+ = 4.\n
\n
• Whenever a friendly **DEVOTEE** operative incapacitates an enemy operative within its
control range, it can **MUTATE**.\n
\n
• Each operative cannot MUTATE more than once per turning point.\n
\n
Whenever a friendly operative **MUTATES**, select one of the following:\n
\n
• If it is a **DEVOTEE** operative, turn it into a **MUTANT** operative.\n
\n
• If it is a **MUTANT** operative, turn it into a **TORMENT** operative (max twice per turning point).\n
\n
• It can regain up to D3+1 lost wounds.\n
\n
You cannot have more than five **MUTANT** operatives and three **TORMENT** operatives at
once. Whenever a friendly operative turns into a new operative:\n
\n
• Swap the miniatures, ensuring the centre of the new miniatures base is as close as possible to
where the centre of the old miniatures base was. This can put it within control range of
enemy operatives, and if the old miniature was, the new miniature must be if possible.\n
\n
• The new operative type loses a number of wounds equal to the lost wounds of its preceding operative type.\n
\n
• It is still the same operative for any rules its already been selected for. The operative is
simply a new operative type and will use that new type’s miniature and datacard rules.\n
\n

]]></string>


    <!--Equipment-->

    <string name="baleful_script_lore"><![CDATA[
These infernal scrawlings, inscribed upon pages
wrought from Human flesh, may bestow malefic gifts
upon the reader when recited in the dark tongue.
]]></string>

    <string name="baleful_script_description"><![CDATA[
Once per battle **STRATEGIC GAMBIT**. Change
one of your **ACCURSED GIFTS**. Note that if it is
an **ACCURSED GIFT** an operative has from the
Abhorrent Mutation firefight ploy, only that
operative benefits from this.
]]></string>

    <string name="chaos_covert_guises_lore"><![CDATA[
The most insidious of Chaos Cults are masters of
infiltration, disguise and betrayal.
]]></string>

    <string name="chaos_covert_guises_description"><![CDATA[
After revealing this equipment option, roll one D3.
As a **STRATEGIC GAMBIT** in the first turning point,
a number of friendly ***CHAOS CULT DEVOTEE**
operatives equal to the result that are wholly
within your drop zone can immediately perform a
free **Reposition** action, but must end that move
wholly within 3\" of your drop zone.
]]></string>

    <string name="unholy_talisman_lore"><![CDATA[
Whether held aloft on ragged banners, carved into
puckered flesh or hanging from spiked chains, these
Cultists display talismans in the belief that the Dark
Gods will look favourably upon them.
]]></string>

    <string name="unholy_talisman_description"><![CDATA[
Once per turning point, when an operative is shooting a friendly **CHAOS CULT** operative,
in the Roll Defence Dice step, you can retain one of your normal successes as a critical
success instead.
]]></string>

    <string name="vile_blessing_lore"><![CDATA[
Though hideous, disturbing and often painful, the Dark
Gods gifts of mutation bestow upon their recipients
incredible resilience
]]></string>

    <string name="vile_blessing_description"><![CDATA[
Once per battle, when an attack dice inflicts Normal Dmg on a friendly **CHAOS CULT**
operative (excluding **DEVOTEE**), you can ignore that inflicted damage. If that friendly operative
is a **MUTANT** or **TORMENT** operative, you cannot roll for the Unnatural Regeneration rule for that
attack dice then decide to use this rule on the same dice – you must use one or the other.
]]></string>



    <!--Ploys-->
    <!--Strategy ploys-->
    <string name="exaltation_in_pain_lore"><![CDATA[
Spurred on by their fervour, Cultists embrace the
exquisite agony of wounds upon their mutant flesh with
maniacal delight.
]]></string>

    <string name="exaltation_in_pain_description"><![CDATA[
You can ignore any changes to the Hit stat of
friendly **CHAOS CULT** operatives weapons
from being injured. Whenever an operative is
shooting a friendly **CHAOS CULT** operative
that is wounded, you can re-roll one of your
defence dice.
]]></string>

    <string name="fervent_onslaught_lore"><![CDATA[
The lost and the damned fight with a zealous
desperation to earn the fickle favour of their
uncaring patrons.
]]></string>

    <string name="fervent_onslaught_description"><![CDATA[
Friendly **CHAOS CULT** operatives melee
weapons have the Accurate 1 weapon rule, or the
Accurate 2 weapon rule if that friendly operative
is a **MUTANT** or **TORMENT** operative.
]]></string>

    <string name="creatures_of_nightmare_lore"><![CDATA[
The twisted and unnatural forms of these accursed monstrosities inspire abject terror.
]]></string>

    <string name="creatures_of_nightmare_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever determining control of a marker, treat the total APL stat of enemy operatives that
contest it as 1 lower if at least one of those enemy operatives is within 2\" of friendly **CHAOS CULT**
**MUTANT** or **CHAOS CULT TORMENT** operatives. Note this is not a change to the APL stat, so any
changes are cumulative with this.
]]></string>

    <string name="sickening_aura_lore"><![CDATA[
Sickening corruption flows from the hideous form of
Mutant and Torment, eroding the sanity and strength of
those who gaze upon them.
]]></string>

    <string name="sickening_aura_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever an enemy operative is within 2\" of friendly **CHAOS CULT MUTANT** or **CHAOS CULT**
**TORMENT** operatives, worsen the Hit stat of that enemy operative’s weapons by 1. This is not
cumulative with being injured.
]]></string>



    <!--Firefight ploys-->
    <string name="faithful_follower_lore"><![CDATA[
The teeming masses of a Chaos Cult will gladly
sacrifice their own wretched lives to preserve their
unholy superiors.
]]></string>

    <string name="faithful_follower_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy when a friendly **CHAOS
CULT DARK COMMUNE** operative is selected
as the valid target of a Shoot action or to fight
against during the **Fight** action. Select one other
friendly **CHAOS CULT** operative (excluding **DARK
COMMUNE**) visible to and within 3\" of that **DARK
COMMUNE** operative to become the valid target
or to be fought against (as appropriate) instead
(even if it would not normally be valid for this). If
it is the **Fight** action, treat that other operative as
being within the fighting operatives control range
for the duration of that action. If it is the **Shoot**
action, that other operative is only in cover or
obscured if the original target was.\n
\n
This ploy has no effect if it is the **Shoot** action
and the ranged weapon has the Blast or Torrent weapon rule.
]]></string>

    <string name="abhorrent_mutation_lore"><![CDATA[
In the midst of battle, when violence and emotion
run rampant, the Ruinous Powers bestow upon their underlings their accursed gifts.
]]></string>

    <string name="abhorrent_mutation_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy when a friendly **CHAOS CULT** operative (excluding **DARK COMMUNE**)
is activated. Select an **ACCURSED GIFT** for that operative to gain. This is in addition to any
**ACCURSED GIFTS** it already has. Each friendly operative cannot be selected for this ploy more
than once per battle, and if that operative turns into a different one (see Mutation faction rule), it
still has that **ACCURSED GIFT.**
]]></string>

    <string name="frenzied_demise_lore"><![CDATA[
Even in their death throes, the devotees of the Dark Gods seek to inflict agony and destruction.
]]></string>

    <string name="frenzied_demise_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy when a friendly **CHAOS CULT MUTANT** or **CHAOS CULT TORMENT**
operative is incapacitated, before it is removed from the killzone. Inflict D3 damage (or D6
damage instead if that friendly operative is a **TORMENT**) on one enemy operative visible to and
within 2\" of that friendly operative.
]]></string>

    <string name="unleash_the_daemon_lore"><![CDATA[
Amidst escalating violence, the veil of reality is torn asunder and the influence of the daemonic strengthens.
]]></string>

    <string name="unleash_the_daemon_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy during a friendly **CHAOS CULT MUTANT** or **CHAOS CULT TORMENT**
operatives activation, before or after it performs an action. During that activation, that operative
can perform two **Fight** actions, and one of them can be free.
]]></string>

</resources>