<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>


    <!--Legionary-->

    <string name="in_the_eye_of_the_gods_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="in_the_eye_of_the_gods_description"><![CDATA[
Once during each of this operatives activations, if it incapacitates an enemy operative, add 1 to its APL stat
until the end of that activation.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="daemonic_aura_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="daemonic_aura_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever an enemy operative performs the **Fall Back** action while within control range of this operative,
you can use this rule. If you do, roll one D6: on a 3+, that enemy
operative cannot perform that action during that activation/
counteraction (the AP spent on it is refunded).
    ]]></string>

    <string name="soul_gorge_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="soul_gorge_description"><![CDATA[
After this operative fights or retaliates, if it is not incapacitated, but it incapacitated an enemy
operative during that sequence, it regains up to D3+1 lost wounds.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="unleash_daemon_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="unleash_daemon_description"><![CDATA[
Once per battle, when this operative is activated, you can use this rule. If you do, until the end of the battle:\n
\n
• This operative cannot perform the **Pick Up Marker** or mission actions (excluding Operate Hatch).
If it is carrying a marker, it must immediately perform the **Place Marker** action for 0AP
(this takes precedence over all other rules).\n
\n
• Normal and Critical Dmg of 4 or more inflicts 1 less damage on this operative. If this operative has the **NURGLE** keyword, you
cannot reduce the damage of an attack dice by more than 1. In other words, you cannot use both rules to reduce Normal Dmg of 4
or more by 2.\n
\n
• Its daemonic claw has the Ceaseless and Lethal 5+ weapon rules.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="siphon_life_usage"><![CDATA[
        Special Weapon Rule
    ]]></string>

    <string name="siphon_life_description"><![CDATA[
When you select this weapon, you can use this rule. If you do, at the start of the Resolve
Attack Dice step, select one friendly **LEGIONARY** operative visible to and within 6\" of this
operative. For each attack dice you resolve during that step that inflicts damage, that friendly
operative regains 1 lost wound, or D3 lost wounds if it was a critical success.
You cannot use this weapon rule more than once per turning point.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="devastating_onslaught_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="devastating_onslaught_description"><![CDATA[
• Whenever this operative is fighting or retaliating, enemy operatives cannot assist.\n
\n
• At the end of each enemy operatives activation or counteraction, you can select one enemy
operative within 2\" of this operative. This operative can perform a free **Charge**
action (you can change its order to **Engage** to do so), but it
cannot move more than 2\n" and must end that move within control range of that selected operative.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="legionaries_icon_bearer_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="legionaries_icon_bearer_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever determining control of a marker, treat this operatives APL stat as 1 higher.
Note this is not a change to its APL stat, so any changes are cumulative with this.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="favoured_of_the_dark_gods_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="favoured_of_the_dark_gods_description"><![CDATA[
In the Ready step of each Strategy phase, if this operative controls an objective marker that is not
tainted, that objective marker is tainted for the battle and you gain 1CP. Note that if any
operative (including enemy operatives) has tainted an objective marker, you cannot taint that
objective marker.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="vicious_reflexes_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="vicious_reflexes_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever this operative is retaliating, you resolve the first attack dice (i.e. defender instead of attacker).
    ]]></string>

    <string name="horrifying_dismemberment_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="horrifying_dismemberment_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever this operative incapacitates an enemy operative while fighting or retaliating,
select one other enemy operative visible to and within 3\" of either this operative or the
incapacitated enemy operative. Subtract 1 from that enemy operative’s APL stat until the end of its next activation.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="grisly_mark_usage"><![CDATA[
        2AP
    ]]></string>

    <string name="grisly_mark_description"><![CDATA[
Place your Grisly marker within this operatives control range.\n
\n
• Whenever an enemy operative is within 3\" of your Grisly marker, your opponent must spend 1 additional AP for that enemy
operative to perform the **Pick Up Marker** and mission actions.\n
\n
• Whenever determining control of a marker, treat the total APL stat of enemy operatives that
contest it as 1 lower if at least one of those enemy operatives is within 3\" of your Grisly marker.
Note this is not a change to the APL stat, so any changes are cumulative with this.\n\n

This operative cannot perform this action more than once per battle, and cannot perform it while within control range of an
enemy operative.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="infernal_pact_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="infernal_pact_description"><![CDATA[
Once per battle, when a friendly **LEGIONARY WARRIOR** operative is activated, you can use this rule. If you
do, change that operatives Marks of Chaos keyword.
    ]]></string>

    <!--Faction Rules-->

    <string name="marks_of_chaos_lore"><![CDATA[
By making dark pacts with the Ruinous Powers,
Legionaries may increase their own might. Yet such
bargains rarely come without a cost.
]]></string>

    <string name="marks_of_chaos_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever you select a **LEGIONARY** operative for the battle, you must select one of the following
keywords for it to have for that battle: **KHORNE, NURGLE, SLAANESH, TZEENTCH, UNDIVIDED.**
Each operatives keyword can be different, but
a **BALEFIRE ACOLYTE** operative cannot have the **KHORNE** keyword.
]]></string>


    <string name="khorne_description"><![CDATA[
**Wrathful Onslaught**\n
\n
This operatives melee weapons have the Severe weapon rule.
]]></string>


    <string name="nurgle_description"><![CDATA[
**Disgusting Vigour**\n
\n
Whenever Normal Dmg of 3 or more is inflicted on this operative, roll one D6: on a 5+, subtract 1
from that inflicted damage.
]]></string>

    <string name="slaanesh_description"><![CDATA[
**Unnatural Agility**\n
\n
Add 1" to this operative’s Move stat.
]]></string>


    <string name="tzeentch_description"><![CDATA[
**Empyreal Guidance**\n
\n
This operatives ranged weapons have the Severe weapon rule.
]]></string>


    <string name="undivided_description"><![CDATA[
**Vicious Reavers**\n
\n
Whenever this operative is shooting against, fighting against or retaliating against an enemy
operative within 6\" of it, this operative’s weapons have the Ceaseless weapon rule.
]]></string>


    <string name="legionaries_astartes_lore"><![CDATA[
These genetically modified superhumans are made for one purpose: war.
]]></string>

    <string name="legionaries_astartes_description"><![CDATA[
During each friendly **LEGIONARY** operatives activation, it can perform either two **Shoot**
actions or two **Fight** actions. If it is two **Shoot**
actions, a bolt pistol, boltgun or tainted bolt pistol must be selected for at least one of them\n
\n
Each friendly **LEGIONARY** operative can counteract regardless of its order.
]]></string>


    <!--Equipment-->

    <string name="warded_armour_lore"><![CDATA[
Daubed with profane icons, emblazoned with infernal
scripture and blessed by the Ruinous Powers, this power armour possesses unholy resilience.
]]></string>

    <string name="warded_armour_description"><![CDATA[
**STRATEGIC GAMBIT**. Select one friendly **LEGIONARY** operative. Until the Ready step of
the next Strategy phase, change that operatives Save stat to 2+.
]]></string>

    <string name="tainted_rounds_lore"><![CDATA[
Subjected to fell rituals, these bolt rounds are infused with corruption.
]]></string>

    <string name="tainted_rounds_description"><![CDATA[
Once per turning point, when a friendly **LEGIONARY** operative is performing the **Shoot**
action and you select a bolt pistol or boltgun, you can use this rule. If you do, until the end
of that action, that weapon has the Rending weapon rule.
]]></string>

    <string name="chaos_talismans_lore"><![CDATA[
Those who carry the talismans of the Ruinous Powers
may be granted great gifts, though they invariably come at a price.
]]></string>

    <string name="chaos_talismans_description"><![CDATA[
**STRATEGIC GAMBIT**. Select one Marks of Chaos keyword. Once during each of their activations,
when a friendly **LEGIONARY** operative that has that keyword is shooting, fighting or retaliating,
if you roll two or more fails, you can inflict D3 damage on that friendly operative to discard one
of them and retain the other as a normal success instead. Note that if it’s the Shoot action and that
damage incapacitates that friendly operative, the action does not end (continue the sequence with
your successful attack dice).
]]></string>

    <string name="malefic_blades_lore"><![CDATA[
Redolent with daemonic energies, this blade hungers for blood.
]]></string>

    <string name="malefic_blades_description"><![CDATA[
Friendly **LEGIONARY** operatives have the following melee weapon:
]]></string>



    <!--Ploys-->
    <!--Strategy ploys-->
    <string name="blood_for_the_blood_god_lore"><![CDATA[
Bloodthirsty, battle-hungry and filled with unbridled fury, Legionaries strike with rage-fuelled might.
]]></string>

    <string name="blood_for_the_blood_god_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever a friendly **LEGIONARY** operative (excluding **KHORNE**) is fighting, the first time you
strike during that sequence, inflict 1 additional damage (to a maximum of 7).\n
\n
Add 1 to both Dmg stats of friendly **LEGIONARY KHORNE** operatives melee weapons (to a maximum of 7).
]]></string>

    <string name="legionarie_implacable_lore"><![CDATA[
Empowered by their transhuman might and the
gifts of their daemonic patrons, Legionaries are monstrously resilient.
]]></string>

    <string name="legionarie_implacable_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever an operative is shooting a friendly **LEGIONARY** operative, weapons with the
Piercing 1 weapon rule have the Piercing Crits 1 weapon rule instead.\n
\n
You can ignore any changes to the stats of
friendly **LEGIONARY NURGLE** operatives from being injured (including their weapons’ stats).
]]></string>

    <string name="quicksilver_speed_lore"><![CDATA[
Some amongst the Heretic Astartes are possessed of
a fleetness of foot and inhuman agility with which they beguile and confound the foe.
]]></string>

    <string name="quicksilver_speed_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever a friendly **LEGIONARY** operative that performed an action in which it moved during this
turning point is fighting, worsen the Hit stat of the enemy operative’s melee weapons by 1.\n
\n
Whenever an operative is shooting a friendly **LEGIONARY SLAANESH** operative more than
6\" from it that performed an action in which it moved during this turning point, worsen the Hit
stat of the enemy operatives weapons by 1.\n
\n
In all cases for this ploy, this isn’t cumulative with being injured.
]]></string>

    <string name="fickle_fates_lore"><![CDATA[
With superhuman reactions, a Heretic Astartes warrior
can use even fractional glimpses of future events to devastating effect.
]]></string>

    <string name="fickle_fates_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever a friendly **LEGIONARY** operative is shooting a ready enemy operative, that friendly
operatives ranged weapons have the Balanced weapon rule.\n
\n
Whenever an operative is shooting a ready friendly **LEGIONARY TZEENTCH** operative, in the
Roll Defence Dice step, if you retain any critical successes, you can retain one of your fails as a
normal success instead of discarding it.
]]></string>



    <!--Firefight ploys-->
    <string name="uneding_bloodshed_lore"><![CDATA[
Even when on the verge of death, the devotees of
Khorne spend their last vestiges of energy to kill in the Blood Gods name.
]]></string>

    <string name="uneding_bloodshed_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy when a friendly **LEGIONARY KHORNE** operative is incapacitated
while fighting or retaliating. You can strike the enemy operative in that sequence with one of
your unresolved successes before it is removed from the killzone.
]]></string>

    <string name="mutability_and_change_lore"><![CDATA[
Tzeentch bestows upon his most devoted followers all
manner of bizarre mutations, some of which may even prove beneficial.
]]></string>

    <string name="mutability_and_change_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy when a friendly **LEGIONARY TZEENTCH** operative is activated.
Until the end of that operatives activation, add 1 to its APL stat, but it cannot perform the same
action more than once during that activation. If it is a **WARRIOR** operative, that operatives Marks
of Chaos keyword cannot be changed during this turning point (see Infernal Pact additional rule).
]]></string>

    <string name="malignant_aura_lore"><![CDATA[
Those who swear themselves to Nurgle may be granted
his favour. Some are even able to project an miasmic aura of decay.
]]></string>

    <string name="malignant_aura_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy when a friendly **LEGIONARY NURGLE** operative is performing the
**Shoot** action, when you select a valid target. Until the end of that action, whenever that friendly
operative is shooting an enemy operative within 3\" of it (i.e. including secondary targets, if any),
that friendly operatives ranged weapons have the Piercing 1 weapon rule.
]]></string>

    <string name="sickening_captivation_lore"><![CDATA[
Slaanesh bestows upon the loyal the power to nauseate
their foes, using dazzling speed, sickening perfumed auras and horrific sonic projections.
]]></string>

    <string name="sickening_captivation_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy during a friendly **LEGIONARY SLAANESH** operative’s activation, before or after it performs an action.
Select one enemy operative visible to and within 4\" of that friendly operative.
Until the end of that enemy operatives next activation, subtract 1 from its APL stat.
]]></string>

</resources>