<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <!--AOD-->
    <string name="brutal_assault_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
]]></string>

    <string name="brutal_assault_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever this operative is fighting, its heavy
thunder hammer has the Brutal weapon rule. Whenever this
operative performs the **Charge** action, its heavy thunder
hammer has the Ceaseless weapon rule until the end of
the activation/counteraction.
]]></string>

    <string name="aggresive_force_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
]]></string>

    <string name="aggresive_force_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever this operative is fighting or
retaliating, Normal and Critical Dmg of 3 or more inflicts 1 less
damage on it. This isnt cumulative with the Shield that Slays
strategy ploy.
]]></string>


    <string name="adaptive_armoury_usage"><![CDATA[
        Operative Selection Step
]]></string>

    <string name="adaptive_armoury_description"><![CDATA[
        You can select one additional equipment option.
]]></string>

    <string name="strategic_command_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive/ Once per battle
]]></string>

    <string name="strategic_command_description"><![CDATA[
       You can do each of the following once per battle if this Operative is in the killzone:
       \n
       -use a **DEATHWATCH** strategy ploy for 0CP.
       \n
       -use a **DEATHWATCH** firefight ploy for 0CP.
]]></string>

    <string name="vigilant_marksman_usage"><![CDATA[
        1AP
]]></string>

    <string name="vigilant_marksman_description"><![CDATA[
      This Operative can perform the **Guard** action during its activation regardless of the killzone
      (see close quarters rule, Kill Team : Tomb World).\n
      \n
      When using the close quarters rules, once per turning point, after this Operative performs
      a free **Shoot** action on guard, it can immediately perform a free **Guard** action.
      However, if it does, it cannot counteract during that tuning point (nor **Guard** twice if
      its counteracted).
]]></string>


    <string name="gravchute_and_grapnel_launcher_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
]]></string>

    <string name="gravchute_and_grapnel_launcher_description"><![CDATA[
       Whenever this operative is
climbing, treat the vertical distance as 2\" (regardless of how far
the operative actually moves vertically). Whenever this operative
is dropping, ignore the vertical distance.
]]></string>

    <string name="clandestine_headtaker_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
]]></string>

    <string name="clandestine_headtaker_description"><![CDATA[
This operative can perform the Charge
action while it has a Conceal order. Whenever this operative is
fighting against an operative it wasnt visible to at the start of
the activation/counteraction, the first time you strike during
that sequence, you can immediately resolve another of your
successes as a strike (before your opponent)
]]></string>

    <string name="advance_omniscrambler_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive/ Strategic gambit
]]></string>

    <string name="advance_omniscrambler_description"><![CDATA[
**STRATEGIC GAMBIT.** Select
one enemy operative visible to or within 6\" of this operative,
then roll one D6. In the Firefight phase of this turning point, that
enemy operative cannot be activated or perform actions until one
of the following is true:\n
\n
-Your opponent has activated a number of enemy operatives
equal to the result of the D6.
\n
-Its the last enemy operative to be activated.
]]></string>

    <string name="auspex_triangulation_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
]]></string>

    <string name="auspex_triangulation_description"><![CDATA[
        The Advanced Auspex Scan firefight ploy costs you 0CP when both of the following are true:\n
        \n
        -This Operative isnt within control range of enemy Operatives.
        \n
        -The target of that **Shoot** action (primary target, if relevant) is
visible to this operative.\n
\n
Note that it doesnt have to be this operative performing
the **Shoot** action, and that any subsequent **Shoot** actions
during that activation/counteraction must meet these same
requirements (or that ploy has no effect on those subsequent
**Shoot** actions).
]]></string>

    <string name="adaptive_swordmanship_usage"><![CDATA[
       Passive
]]></string>

    <string name="adaptive_swordmanship_description"><![CDATA[
You can ignore any changes to the Hit
stat of this operatives xenophase blade. Whenever this operative
is fighting or retaliating, you can resolve one of your successes
before the normal order. If you do, that success must be used
to block.
]]></string>

    <string name="phase_sweep_usage"><![CDATA[
       Special Weapon Rule
]]></string>

    <string name="phase_sweep_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever this operative performs the **Fight**
action with this weapon profile, if it isnt incapacitated, it can
immediately perform a free **Fight** action afterwards, but you
must select this weapon profile and it can only fight against each
enemy operative within its control range once per activation or
counteraction using this weapon profile. This takes precedence
over action restrictions, and you can continue to perform free
Fight actions until this operative is incapacitated or has fought
against every enemy operative within its control range.
]]></string>

    <string name="deathwatch_shield_usage"><![CDATA[
       Special Weapon Rule
]]></string>

    <string name="deathwatch_shield_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever this operative is fighting or retaliating with
this weapon, each of your blocks can be allocated to block two
unresolved successes (instead of one).
]]></string>

    <string name="storm_shield_usage"><![CDATA[
       Passive
]]></string>

    <string name="storm_shield_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever an operative is shooting this operative,
worsen the x of the Piercing weapon rule by 1 (if any). Note that
Piercing 1 would therefore be ignored.
]]></string>


    <!--Faction Rules-->

    <string name="veteran_astartes_lore"><![CDATA[
These genetically modified superhumans are made to
wage unending war. Their skills have been honed over
long years of battle and further refined with specialist
knowledge through their Long Vigil.
]]></string>

    <string name="veteran_astartes_description"><![CDATA[
During each friendly DEATHWATCH operatives
activation, it can perform either two Shoot
actions or two Fight actions. If its two Shoot
actions and an auxiliary grenade launcher, frag
cannon, heavy plasma incinerator, infernus
heavy bolter, plasma pistol or stalker bolt rifle is
selected for both, or if a melta bomb is selected
for either, 1 additional AP must be spent for the
second action.\n\n

Each friendly DEATHWATCH operative can
counteract regardless of its order. Whenever it
does, it can perform an additional 1AP action for
free during that counteraction, but both actions
must be different and you cannot perform a Fight
and Shoot action during the same counteraction.
]]></string>

    <string name="special_issue_ammunition_lore"><![CDATA[
The Deathwatch utilise a range of specialised
ammunition in many of their weapons. Each type is
designed to eliminate specific xenos foes
]]></string>

    <string name="special_issue_ammunition_description"><![CDATA[
Once per turning point, when a friendly
DEATHWATCH operative is performing the
Shoot action, in the Select Weapon step, you
can use this rule. If you do, select one of the
following weapon rules for that operatives ranged
weapons to have until the end of the action. This
rule cannot be used with explosive grenades (see
universal equipment) or melta bombs.\n
\n
-Blast 1\" (you cannot select thi if the weapon profile being used has the Torrent weapon rule)\n
-Devastating 1\n
-Lethal 5+\n
-Piercing Crits 1\n
-Saturate\n
-Severe\n
]]></string>


    <!--Equipment-->

    <string name="digital_weapons_lore"><![CDATA[
Various high-powered lasers, toxic needlers, incineration
projectors and more are concealed as bionic implants or
in the knuckles of gauntlets. They lack the power to be
used at range, but can be triggered up close to exploit a
weakness while the enemy fends off the main attack.
]]></string>

    <string name="digital_weapons_description"><![CDATA[
Once per turning point, when a friendly
**DEATHWATCH** operative performs the Fight
action, at the start of the Roll Attack Dice step,
you can use this rule. If you do, inflict 1 damage
on the enemy operative in that sequence.
]]></string>

    <string name="scrutavore_servothrall_lore"><![CDATA[
This specialised servo-skull circles a kill teams
deployment on anti-grav motors, consuming data at
a voracious rate before dissecting it and feeding the
resultant analyses to the battle-brothers to provide
maximum strategic awareness. Many are built upon
the skulls of loyal serfs, though some are constructed
around the sanctified craniums of defeated xenos.
]]></string>

    <string name="scrutavore_servothrall_description"><![CDATA[
Once per turning point, during a friendly
**DEATHWATCH** operatives activation, you can
use this rule. If you do, during that activation,
that operative can perform a mission action for 1
less AP.\n
\n
Having an enemy operative within its control
range doesnt prevent that friendly operative
from performing that mission action. However,
in such an instance, after it does so, you and
your opponent roll-off. If your opponent wins,
you cannot use this equipment for the rest of
the battle.
]]></string>

    <string name="sanctusv_biooscryer_cuffs_lore"><![CDATA[
Developed by Techmarines and Apothecaries of the
Castilos Nullifact watch fortress, these vambracemounted monitron relays offer unparalleled analysis
and purgation of a range of bio-threats to the wearers
augmented physiology.
]]></string>

    <string name="sanctusv_biooscryer_cuffs_description"><![CDATA[
Once during each friendly **DEATHWATCH**
operatives activation, before or after it performs
an action, if its not within control range of enemy
operatives, you can use this rule. If you do, select
one of the following:\n
\n

-That friendly operative regains up to D3
lost wounds.\n
-Remove any changes to that friendly
operatives APL stat.\n
-Remove one of the following tokens that
friendly operative has (before that tokens
activation effects are resolved, if relevant):
Neutron Fragment, Poison, Terrorchem.
]]></string>

    <string name="ammunition_reserve_lore"><![CDATA[
Awarded to kill teams whose marksmanship is as
efficient as it is lethal, additional caches of individually
crafted shells, fuel canisters and ammunition cells serve
to secure victory during the most dangerous missions.
]]></string>

    <string name="ammunition_reserve_description"><![CDATA[
Once per battle, you can use the Special Issue
Ammunition faction rule for up to two Shoot
actions during one turning point, but you must
select different weapon rules for both uses. This
takes precedence over the normal Special Issue
Ammunition rules.
]]></string>


    <!--Ploys-->
    <!--Strategy ploys-->

    <string name="mission_tactics_lore"><![CDATA[
Through collated strategic data and hard-won combat
experience, the Deathwatch possess the tactics to
combat almost any foe
]]></string>

    <string name="mission_tactics_description"><![CDATA[
Select Conceal or Engage. Whenever a friendly
**DEATHWATCH** operative is shooting against or
fighting against an enemy operative that has that
order, that friendly operative’s weapons have the
Balanced weapon rule.
]]></string>

    <string name="the_long_vigil_lore"><![CDATA[
The Deathwatch guard some of the most dangerous
stretches of the Imperium. Their vow to stand firm is
at the heart of their vigil; they will see their foes dead
before they abandon the Emperors realm.
]]></string>

    <string name="the_long_vigil_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever an operative is shooting a friendly
**DEATHWATCH** operative thats wholly within
your territory, you can re-roll one of your
defence dice
]]></string>

    <string name="the_shield_that_slays_lore"><![CDATA[
To enter the infested holds of the xenos is to be assailed
by the most inhuman of abominations and technology, a
foulness that the Deathwatch are trained to resist.
]]></string>

    <string name="the_shield_that_slays_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever a friendly **DEATHWATCH** operative is
wholly within your opponents territory, Normal
Dmg of 4 or more inflicts 1 less damage on it.
]]></string>

    <string name="dw_no_fear_lore"><![CDATA[
Space Marines possess extraordinary courage and are
utterly unflinching in the face of terrifying horrors and
overwhelming odds.
]]></string>

    <string name="dw_no_fear_description"><![CDATA[
You can ignore any changes to the stats of
friendly DEATHWATCH operatives from being
injured (including their weapons’ stats).
]]></string>



    <!--Firefight ploys-->

    <string name="suffer_not_the_alien_lore"><![CDATA[
Every tool at their disposal, every scrap of knowledge,
is sharpened upon the whetstone of the Deathwatchs
hatred of the alien.
]]></string>

    <string name="suffer_not_the_alien_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy after rolling your attack dice
for a friendly **DEATHWATCH** operative, if its
shooting against or fighting against an operative
that doesnt have the CHAOS or IMPERIUM
keyword. You can re-roll any of your attack dice.
]]></string>

    <string name="auspicator_tracking_lore"><![CDATA[
Neurally connected to a battle-brothers senses,
auspicator lenses can improve their data prescience to
almost precognitive levels.
]]></string>

    <string name="auspicator_tracking_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy when a friendly
**DEATHWATCH** operative is counteracting,
before it performs any actions. You can change
its order
]]></string>

    <string name="advance_auspex_scan_lore"><![CDATA[
Between unstinting sweeps of their bioscryer cuffs,
their inbuilt auspexes warning of hostile threats and the
augmented instincts of the Deathwatch themselves, no
lurking threat can long evade their sights.
]]></string>

    <string name="advance_auspex_scan_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy when a friendly
**DEATHWATCH** operative performs the
**Shoot** action. Until the end of the activation/
counteraction, its ranged weapons have the
Saturate weapon rule and enemy operatives
cannot be obscured.
]]></string>

    <string name="dw_transhuman_physiology_lore"><![CDATA[
The genetically modified physiology of a Space
Marine is capable of resisting wounds that would kill a
lesser being.
]]></string>

    <string name="dw_transhuman_physiology_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy when an operative is
shooting a friendly **DEATHWATCH** operative,
in the Roll Defence Dice step. You can retain
one of your normal successes as a critical
success instead.
]]></string>


</resources>