<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>


    <!--Nemesis-->

    <string name="prescience_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="prescience_description"><![CDATA[
**PSYCHIC.** In the Ready step of each Strategy phase, you gain D3 Prescience points. At the end of
each turning point, discard your Prescience points.
You can spend your Prescience points in the Firefight phase as follows (you cannot use each of the
following rules more than once per turning point):\n
\n
• Foreboding: **PSYCHIC**. Whenever it is your turn to activate a friendly operative, you can spend 1 of your Prescience points to
skip that activation.\n
\n
• Portent: **PSYCHIC**. Whenever an attack dice inflicts Normal Dmg on this operative, you can spend 1 of your Prescience points to
ignore that inflicted damage.\n
\n
You cannot gain or spend your Prescience points if this operative is incapacitated.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="nemesis_premonition_usage"><![CDATA[
        1AP
    ]]></string>

    <string name="nemesis_premonition_description"><![CDATA[
**PSYCHIC**. Spend 1 of your Prescience points to gain 1CP.\n\n

This operative cannot perform this action while within control range of an enemy operative, or more than once per turning point.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="terrochem_usage"><![CDATA[
        Special Weapon Rule
    ]]></string>

    <string name="terrochem_description"><![CDATA[
In the Resolve Attack Dice step, if you inflict
damage with any critical successes, the operative this weapon
is being used against gains one of your Terrorchem tokens (if it
does not already have one).
    ]]></string>

    <string name="terrochem_poison_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="terrochem_poison_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever an operative that has one of your Terrorchem tokens is activated, inflict D3 damage on it.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="poison_objective_usage"><![CDATA[
        1AP
    ]]></string>

    <string name="poison_objective_description"><![CDATA[
Select one objective marker this operative controls to gain
one of your Terrorchem tokens. It cannot be an objective
marker within control range of an enemy operative, or one
that already has one of your Terrorchem tokens. The first
time that objective marker is within control range of an
enemy operative that does not have one of your Terrorchem
tokens, that operative gains that Terrorchem token, then
inflict 2D3 damage on it (if it is during an action, at the end
of that action).\n\n

This operative cannot perform this action while within control range of an enemy operative.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="screecher_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="screecher_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever an enemy operative within 3\" of this
operative is shooting, fighting or retaliating, your opponent cannot re-roll their attack dice.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="appetite_for_cruelty_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="appetite_for_cruelty_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever this operative is fighting against
a wounded enemy operative, this operatives lightning claws have the Lethal 4+ weapon rule.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="flay_them_alive_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="flay_them_alive_description"><![CDATA[
Once per turning point, when this operative
incapacitates an enemy operative within its control range, you
can select one other enemy operative visible to and within 6\" of
either this operative or the incapacitated enemy operative. Until
the start of the next turning point, that other enemy operative
cannot control markers or perform the **Pick Up Marker** or
mission actions.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="tyrant_skinning_pits_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="tyrant_skinning_pits_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever this operative is fighting
or retaliating, Normal and Critical Dmg of 3 or more inflicts 1 less damage on it.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="nemesis_icon_bearer_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="nemesis_icon_bearer_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever determining control of a marker, treat this operative’s
APL stat as 1 higher. Note this
is not a change to its APL stat, so any changes are cumulative with this.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="disconcerting_mimicry_usage"><![CDATA[
        1AP
    ]]></string>

    <string name="disconcerting_mimicry_description"><![CDATA[
**PSYCHIC.** Select one enemy operative within 6\" of this operative, then select one of the
following for that enemy operative (you can only select each option once per battle):\n
\n
• Until the end of its next activation, subtract 1 from its APL stat.\n
\n
• Change its order.\n
\n
• Perform a free Dash action with it (specify the location for your opponent to move it to).\n\n

This operative cannot perform this action while within control range of an enemy operative
    ]]></string>

    <string name="cruel_tormenter_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="cruel_tormenter_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever this operative is shooting against,
fighting against or retaliating against an injured enemy operative,
or an enemy operative that has a Wounds stat of 7 or less, this
operatives weapons have the Lethal 5+ weapon rule.
    ]]></string>

    <!--Faction Rules-->

    <string name="nemesis_astartes_lore"><![CDATA[
These genetically modified superhumans are made for one purpose: war.
]]></string>

    <string name="nemesis_astartes_description"><![CDATA[
During each friendly **NEMESIS CLAW** operatives
activation, it can perform either two **Shoot**
actions or two **Fight** actions. If it’s two **Shoot**
actions, a bolt pistol, boltgun or scoped bolt pistol
must be selected for at least one of them.\n
\n
Each friendly **NEMESIS CLAW** operative can counteract regardless of its order.
]]></string>

    <string name="in_midnight_clad_lore"><![CDATA[
Night Lords are one with the darkness, employing it as an ally and a weapon.
]]></string>

    <string name="in_midnight_clad_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever an enemy operative is shooting a friendly **NEMESIS CLAW** operative, that friendly
operative is obscured if both of the following are true:\n
\n
• It is more than 8\" from enemy operatives it is visible to.\n
\n
• It has Heavy terrain within its control range, or any part of its base is underneath
Vantage terrain.
]]></string>

    <!--Equipment-->

    <string name="flayed_skin_lore"><![CDATA[
Bedecked with the bloody hides of butchered victims,
the Night Lords inspire abject terror and revulsion in
their enemies.
]]></string>

    <string name="flayed_skin_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever an enemy operative is shooting
against, fighting against or retaliating against a
friendly **NEMESIS CLAW** operative within 2\" of
it, your opponent cannot re-roll their attack dice results of 1.
]]></string>

    <string name="chain_snare_lore"><![CDATA[
Composed of hooked blades attached to a length of
chain, this weapon bites into the flesh or armour of the
wielder’s target, preventing them from fleeing.
]]></string>

    <string name="chain_snare_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever an enemy operative would perform
the **Fall Back** action while within control range
of a friendly **NEMESIS CLAW** operative, if no
other enemy operatives are within that friendly
operatives control range, you can use this rule.
If you do, roll two D6, or one D6 if that enemy
operative has a higher Wounds stat than that
friendly operative. If any result is a 4+, that enemy
operative cannot perform that action during that
activation/counteraction (no AP are spent on it),
and you cannot use this rule again during this
turning point.
]]></string>

    <string name="grisly_trophy_lore"><![CDATA[
Severed hands and limbs, eyeballs plucked from the
skulls of screaming victims – these macabre trophies
and more cause the Night Lords’ foes to waver.
]]></string>

    <string name="grisly_trophy_description"><![CDATA[
Once per battle, when a friendly **NEMESIS CLAW**
operative incapacitates an enemy operative
within 2\" of it, you can use this rule. If you do, that
friendly operative gains one of your Grisly Trophy
tokens (if it does not already have one). Whenever
a friendly **NEMESIS CLAW** operative that has
one of your Grisly Trophy tokens is visible to and
within 2\" of an enemy operative, subtract 1 from
the Atk stat of that enemy operatives weapons.
]]></string>

    <string name="nemesis_comms_jammers_lore"><![CDATA[
The Night Lords use jamming devices to sow chaos
and confusion by preventing their panicked foes
from communicating.
]]></string>

    <string name="nemesis_comms_jammers_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever an enemy operative is within 3\" of a
friendly **NEMESIS CLAW** operative, that enemy
operatives APL stat cannot be added to. Note
that this does not affect APL stats that have already been changed.
]]></string>



    <!--Ploys-->
    <!--Strategy ploys-->
    <string name="we_have_come_for_you_lore"><![CDATA[
The Night Lords strike their foes swiftly, utilising shock,
awe and terror to brutalise the enemy before they can
lift a blade in response.
]]></string>

    <string name="we_have_come_for_you_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever a friendly **NEMESIS CLAW** operative
is activated, if the first action it performs during
that activation is the **Charge** action, when it
ends its move during that action, you can inflict
D3 damage on one enemy operative within its control range.
]]></string>

    <string name="the_black_hunt_lore"><![CDATA[
A terrible malice burns within the twin hearts of each
Night Lord, and they enjoy nothing more than toying with their wounded prey
]]></string>

    <string name="the_black_hunt_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever a friendly **NEMESIS CLAW** operative
is shooting against, fighting against or retaliating
against a wounded enemy operative, you can
re-roll one of your attack dice.
]]></string>

    <string name="preysight_lore"><![CDATA[
The Night Lords seem able to sense the fear of cowering
prey, hunting down the craven with unerring precision
]]></string>

    <string name="preysight_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever you are selecting a valid target for a
friendly **NEMESIS CLAW** operative, enemy
operatives within 6\" of it cannot use Light terrain
for cover. While this can allow such operatives to
be targeted (assuming they are visible), it does not
remove their cover save (if any).
]]></string>

    <string name="return_to_darkness_lore"><![CDATA[
The Night Lords move from shadow to shadow with an
agility and speed belied by their transhuman bulk.
]]></string>

    <string name="return_to_darkness_description"><![CDATA[
One friendly **NEMESIS CLAW** operative
can immediately perform a free **Fall Back** or
**Reposition** action, but it must end that move
with Heavy terrain within its control range, or
any part of its base underneath Vantage terrain.
In addition, it cannot move more than 4\" during
that action and it cannot end that move closer
to enemy operatives (in a killzone that uses the
close quarters rules, e.g. Killzone: Tomb World,
ignore Wall terrain when determining this).
]]></string>



    <!--Firefight ploys-->
    <string name="nemesis_vox_scream_lore"><![CDATA[
By modulating the frequency of their helm-mounted
vox-units, Night Lord operatives can unleash a terrifying
scream with the ability to stun an opponent.
]]></string>

    <string name="nemesis_vox_scream_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy when your opponent would
activate an enemy operative that is visible to a
friendly **NEMESIS CLAW** operative. Roll one D6;
if the result is higher than that enemy operatives
APL stat, your opponent cannot activate it during
this activation; if the result is less than or equal
to that enemy operatives APL stat, this ploy is not
used, the CP spent on it is refunded and you
cannot use this ploy again during this turning
point. If there are no other enemy operatives
eligible to be activated, this ploy has no effect.
]]></string>

    <string name="death_to_the_false_emperor_lore"><![CDATA[
The Night Lords, like all Heretic Astartes, bear a
particular hatred for the corpse-worshipping soldiers of
the Imperium.
]]></string>

    <string name="death_to_the_false_emperor_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy after rolling your attack
dice for a friendly **NEMESIS CLAW** operative,
if it is shooting against, fighting against or
retaliating against an enemy operative that has
the **IMPERIUM** keyword. That friendly operatives
weapons have the Ceaseless weapon rule
until the end of that sequence; if that enemy
operative also has the **ADEPTUS ASTARTES**
keyword, that friendly operatives weapons have
the Relentless weapon rule until the end of that
sequence instead.
]]></string>

    <string name="proclivity_for_murder_lore"><![CDATA[
Each brutal kill a Night Lord performs serves to feed
their bloodlust and drives them to further acts of
terrible violence.
]]></string>

    <string name="proclivity_for_murder_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy after a friendly **NEMESIS
CLAW** operative incapacitates an enemy
operative within its control range. That friendly
operative can immediately perform a free **Charge**
or **Dash** action (for the former, it cannot move
more than 3\"), even if it is performed an action
that prevents it from performing those actions.
]]></string>

    <string name="dirty_fighter_lore"><![CDATA[
The Night Lords have no respect for the concept of
honour and will use whatever underhanded tactics they
deem necessary.
]]></string>

    <string name="dirty_fighter_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy when a friendly **NEMESIS CLAW** operative is retaliating, at the start of the
Resolve Attack Dice step. You can resolve one of
your successes before the normal order. If you do,
you cannot resolve any other successes during
that sequence.
]]></string>

</resources>