<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <!--Universal Equipments-->

    <string name="portable_barricade">
        PORTABLE BARRICADE"
    </string>
    <string name="portable_barricade_description">
        <![CDATA[A portable barricade is light cover, Protective and Portable terrain,
         except the feet which are Insignificant and Exposed. Before the battle,
         you can set it up wholly within your territory, on the killzone floor and more
         than 2" from other equipment terrain features, access points and Accessible terrain.

        <b>Protective:</b>While an Operative is in cover from this terrain feature, improve
         its Save stat by 1 (to a Maximum of 2+).
         <b>Portable:</b>This terrain feature only provides cover while an Operative is connected
         to it and if the shield is intervening (ignore its feet).

         Operatives connected to the inside of it can perform the following unique action during the battle.]]>
    </string>
    <string name="portable_barricade_title">
        MOVE WITH BARRICADE
    </string>
    <string name="portable_barricade_usage">
        1 AP
    </string>
    <string name="portable_barricade_ability_description">
        <![CDATA[The same as <b>Reposition</b> action, except the active Operative can move
         no more than its Move stat minus 2" and cannot climb, drop, jump, or use any
         kill teams rules that remove it and set it back up again (Ex Fly, Teleportation).

        Before this operative moves, remove the portable barricade its connected to.
         After it moves, set up the portable barricade so its connected again, but
         the portable barricade cannot be set up within 2" of other equipment terrain
         feature, access points or Accessible terrain. If this is not possible, the
         portable barricade is not set up again.

         This action is treated as a <b>Reposition</b> action. An Operative cannot perform
         this action while within control range of an enemy Operative or during the same activation
         in which it performed the <b>Fall Back</b> or <b>charge</b> action.]]>
    </string>


    <string name="explosive_grenades">
        EXPLOSIVE GRENADES

    </string>
    <string name="explosive_grenades_description">
        <![CDATA[When you select this equipment, select two explosive grenades
        -2 frag.
        -2 krak.
        -1 frag and 1 krak.

        Each selection is a unique action your Operatives can perform, but your kill team can only
        perform that action a total number of times during the battle equal to your election.]]>
    </string>


    <string name="smoke_grenade">
        SMOKE GRENADE
    </string>
    <string name="smoke_grenade_description">
        <![CDATA[When you select this equipment, select two utility grenades
        -2 Smokes.
        -2 Stun.
        -1 Smoke and 1 Stun.
        Each selection is a unique action your Operatives can perform, but your kill team can only
        perform that action a total number of times during the battle equal to your election.]]>
    </string>
    <string name="smoke_grenade_title">
        SMOKE GRENADE
    </string>
    <string name="smoke_grenade_usage">
        1 AP
    </string>
    <string name="smoke_grenade_ability_description">
        <![CDATA[Place one of your Smoke Grenade markers within 6" of this Operative.
         It must be visible to this Operative, or on Vantage terrain of a terrain feature
         thats visible to this Operative. The marker creates an area of smoke 1"
         horizontally and unlimited height vertically from (but not below) it.

         While an Operative is wholly within an area of smoke, its <b>Obscured</b> to Operatives
         more than 2" from it, and vice versa. In addition, whenever an Operative is
         shooting an enemy Operative wholly within an area of smoke, weapons with the
         <b>Piercing 2</b> or <b>Piercing Crits 2</b> weapon rule will have <b>Piercing 1</b>
         or <b>Piercing Crits 1</b> instead, unless theyre within 2" of each other


        In the Ready step of the next Strategy phase, roll one D3. Remove that Smoke
         Grenade marker after a number of activations equal to the result have been
         completed or at the end of the turning point (whichever comes first).


        An operative CANNOT perform this action while within control range of an
         enemy Operative, or if you have reached the total number of times you kill team
        can perform it.]]>
    </string>

    <string name="stun_grenade">
        STUN GRENADE
    </string>
    <string name="stun_grenade_description">
        <![CDATA[When you select this equipment, select two utility grenades
        -2 Smokes.
        -2 Stun.
        -1 Smoke and 1 Stun.
        Each selection is a unique action your Operatives can perform, but your kill team can only
        perform that action a total number of times during the battle equal to your election.]]>
    </string>
    <string name="stun_grenade_title">
        STUN GRENADE
    </string>
    <string name="stun_grenade_usage">
        1 AP
    </string>
    <string name="stun_grenade_ability_description">
        <![CDATA[Select one enemy Operative visible and within 6" of this Operative
        . That operative and each other Operative within 1" of it takes a stun test.
         For an Operative to take a stun test, roll one D6: on a 3+, subtract 1 from
         its APL stat until the end of its next activation.


        An operative CANNOT perform this action while within control range of an
         enemy Operative, or if you have reached the total number of times you kill team
        can perform it.]]>
    </string>

    <string name="ammo_cache">
        1X AMMO CACHE"
    </string>
    <string name="ammo_cache_description">
        <![CDATA[Before the battle, you can set up one of your Ammo Cache markers wholly within
                     your territory. Friendly Operatives can perform the following mission action
                     during the battle.]]>
    </string>
    <string name="ammo_cache_title">
        AMMO RESUPPLY
    </string>
    <string name="ammo_cache_usage">
        0 AP
    </string>
    <string name="ammo_cache_ability_description">
        <![CDATA[One of your Ammo Cache markers the active Operative controls is used
             during this turning point.
             Until the start of the next turning point,
             whenever this Operative is shooting with a weapon from its datacard, you
             can re-roll one of your attack dice.


            An operative CANNOT perform this action while within control range of an
             enemy Operative, if that marker isnt yours, or if that marker has been used
             during this turning point.]]>

    </string>

    <string name="razor_wire">
        1X RAZOR WIRE
    </string>
    <string name="razor_wire_description">
        <![CDATA[Razor wire is Exposed and Obstructing terrain. Before the battle, you can
                     set it up wholly within your territory, on the killzone floor and more than 2"
                     from other equipment terrain features, access points and Accessible terrain.

                    <b>Obstructing:</b> Whenever an Operative would cross over this terrain feature
                     within 1" of it, treat the distance as an additional 1".]]>

    </string>

    <string name="comms_device">
        1X COMMS DEVICE
    </string>
    <string name="comms_device_description">
        <![CDATA[Before the battle, you can set up one of your Comms Device markers wholly
                     within your territory. While a friendly operative controls this marker, add 3"
                     to the distance requirements of its <b>SUPPORT</b> rules that refer to friendly
                     Operatives, improving the distance. Note that you cannot benefit from your
                     opponents Comms Device markers.]]>
    </string>

    <string name="mines">
        1X MINES
    </string>
    <string name="mines_description">
       <![CDATA[Before the battle, you can set up one of your Mines Marker wholly within
                     your territory and more than 2" from other markers, access points and
                     Accessible terrain. The first time that marker is within an Operatives control
                     range, remove that marker and inflict D3+3 damage on that Operative.]]>
    </string>

    <string name="light_barricades">
        2X LIGHT BARRICADES
    </string>
    <string name="light_barricades_description">
        <![CDATA[Light barricades are Light terrain, except the feet, which are Insignificant
                     and Exposed. Before the battle, you can set up one of your Light Barricades wholly
                     within your territory and more than 2" from other markers, access points and
                     Accessible terrain.]]>
    </string>

    <string name="heavy_barricade">
        1X HEAVY BARRICADE
    </string>
    <string name="heavy_barricade_description">
        <![CDATA[A heavy barricade is Heavy terrain. Before the battle, you can set it up"
                     wholly within 4" of your drop zone, on the kill zone floor and more than 2"
                    from other markers, access points and Accessible terrain.]]>
    </string>

    <string name="ladder">
        2X LADDERS
    </string>
    <string name="ladder_description">
        <![CDATA[Ladders are Insignificant and Exposed terrain. Before the battle, you can
         set up any of them as follows:

         *Wholly within your territory.\nUpright against a terrain thats at least 2" tall.
        *More than 2" from other equipment terrain features.
        *More than 1" from doors and access points.

        Once per action, whenever an Operative is climbing the terrain feature a ladder is placed against
        , treat the vertical distance as 1" if the ladder is within that Operatives
         control range during that entire climb.]]>
    </string>

    <string name="breaching_charge">
        BREACHING CHARGE
    </string>
    <string name="breaching_charge_description">
        <![CDATA[Once per battle, when a friendly Operative performs the **BREACH** action,
                     you can use this rule. If you do, that Operative can perform that action for 1
                     less AP (to a minimum of 1AP) as though it had the word "breach marker" on its
                    datacard.]]>
    </string>
</resources>