<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <!--Battleclade-->

    <string name="battleclade_autoproxy_eye"><![CDATA[

        Achillan Eye

]]></string>

    <string name="battleclade_autoproxy_eye_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

]]></string>

    <string name="battleclade_autoproxy_eye_description"><![CDATA[

        Whenever a friendly **BATTLECLADE** Operative is shooting an enemy Operative visible
                     to this Operative, that friendly Operatives ranged weapons have the **Saturate** weapon rule.
                     This rule has no effect if this Operative is within control range of an enemy Operative.

]]></string>

    <string name="battleclade_autoproxy_gaze"><![CDATA[

        GAZE OF THE OMNISSIAH

]]></string>

    <string name="battleclade_autoproxy_gaze_usage"><![CDATA[

        1AP/Firefight Phase

]]></string>

    <string name="battleclade_autoproxy_gaze_description"><![CDATA[

        Select one enemy Operative visible to this Operative. Until the end of the turning point, whenever
                     a friendly **BATTLECLADE** Operative is shooting that enemy Operative, you can use this rule. If you do:\n
                    \n*That enemy Operative cannot be obscured.
                     \n\nThis Operative **CANNOT** perform this action while within control range of an enemy Operative.

]]></string>

    <string name="battleclade_breach"><![CDATA[

        Breach

]]></string>

    <string name="battleclade_breach_usage"><![CDATA[

        1 AP/Firefight phase

]]></string>

    <string name="battleclade_breach_description"><![CDATA[

        Place one of your Breach markers within this Operatives control range as close as possible to a
                     terrain feature within control range of it. Whenever an Operative is within 1\" of that marker,
                     it treats parts of that terrain feature that are no more than 1\" thick as Accessible terrain.\n\n
                    This Operative **cannot** perform this action while within control range of an enemy Operative, or if
                     a terrain feature isnt within its control range.

]]></string>

    <string name="battleclade_divinearcana"><![CDATA[

        Seeker of Divine Arcana

]]></string>

    <string name="battleclade_divinearcana_usage"><![CDATA[

        Strategic Gambit

]]></string>

    <string name="battleclade_divinearcana_description"><![CDATA[

        You can inmediatly change this Operatives order and/or can inmediatly perform
                        any of these actions for free:\nOmniscanner\nFall Back\nPlace Marker\nPick Up Marker
                        \nMission Action\nReposition.\nWhen doing a Reposition or Fall back action with this rule
                         and this Operative is not carrying a marker, it must end that move either within your drop
                         zone(or as close as possible), or with control of a mission marker or objective marker.

]]></string>


    <string name="battleclade_omniscanner"><![CDATA[

        Omniscanner

]]></string>

    <string name="battleclade_omniscanner_usage"><![CDATA[

        1AP/Firefight Phase or Strategic Gambit

]]></string>

    <string name="battleclade_omniscanner_description"><![CDATA[

        Select one enemy Operative visible or within 8\" of this operative to gain one of your
                        Omniscanner tokens. Whenever a friendly BATTLECLADE Operative is shooting, fighting, or retaliating
                         an enemy Operative with one of your Omniscanner tokens, that friendly Operatives weapons have
                         the Ceasless weapon rule.\n\nThis Operative CANNOT perform this action while within control range
                         of an enemy Operative.

]]></string>


    <string name="battleclade_datacoronal"><![CDATA[

        Datacoronal Accumulator

]]></string>

    <string name="battleclade_datacoronal_usage"><![CDATA[

        1AP/ Firefight phase

]]></string>

    <string name="battleclade_datacoronal_description"><![CDATA[

        **SUPPORT.** Determine the friendly **BATTLECLADE** operatives within 6\" of this operative and/or a friendly
**BATTLECLADE AUTO-PROXY** operative, then roll one D3. If the result is equal to or less than the number of objective
markers those friendly operatives contest, you gain 1CP. For the purposes of the Comms Device universal equipment, the
operative the distance is being determined from must control your Comms Device marker to add 3\" to its distance requirement
for this rule.\n\n

 This operative cannot perform this action while within control range of an enemy operative.
    ]]></string>



    <string name="battleclade_network_usage"><![CDATA[

        1AP/ Firefight phase

    ]]></string>

    <string name="battleclade_network_description"><![CDATA[
       **SUPPORT**. Select one friendly **BATTLECLADE SERVITOR** operative within 6\" of either this operative or a friendly
**BATTLECLADE AUTO-PROXY** operative to immediately **NETWORK COUNTERACT** (you dont have to **TRANSFER
POWER** to do so). Continue this operatives activation after doing so. For the purposes of the Comms Device universal
equipment, the operative the distance is being determined from must control that marker.\n\n

 This operative cannot perform this action while within control range of an enemy operative.
    ]]></string>


    <string name="battleclade_mechanosuture_array_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive/Friendly Operative is incapacitated

    ]]></string>

    <string name="battleclade_mechanosuture_array_description"><![CDATA[
Once per turning point, when another friendly **BATTLECLADE** operative would be incapacitated while
visible to and within 3\" of this operative, you can use this rule, providing neither this nor that operative is within control range of
an enemy operative. If you do, that friendly operative isnt incapacitated, has 1 wound remaining and cannot be incapacitated
for the remainder of the action. After that action, that friendly operative can immediately perform a free **Dash** action, but must
end that move within this operatives control range. If this rule was used during that friendly operatives activation, that activation
ends. You cannot use this rule if this operative is incapacitated, or if its a **Shoot** action and this operative would be a primary or
secondary target.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="battleclade_expedient_repair_usage"><![CDATA[

        1AP

    ]]></string>

    <string name="battleclade_expedient_repair_description"><![CDATA[
Select one friendly **BATTLECLADE** operative within this
operatives control range to regain up to D3+3 lost wounds.
It cannot be an operative that the Mechanosuture Array rule
was used on during this turning point.\n\n

This operative cannot perform this action while within control
range of an enemy operative.
    ]]></string>


    <!--Faction Rules-->

    <string name="noospheric_network_lore"><![CDATA[
Servitors are yoked to their Tech-Priest masters by
an invisible web of control. This noospheric network
enables servitors to be rapidly reorganised, transferring
processing power to other thralls who might better serve
the Tech-Priests immediate wishes. While some are
left to conform to their basic programming, others are
instructed with key tasks that must be fulfilled for the
glory of the Machine God.
]]></string>

    <string name="noospheric_network_description"><![CDATA[
Once during each friendly **BATTLECLADE
SERVITOR** operatives activation, before or after
it performs an action, you can spend 1AP to
**TRANSFER POWER**. \n\n

After that activation, you can **NETWORK
COUNTERACT** with one other friendly
**BATTLECLADE SERVITOR** operative before your
opponent activates. Whenever you **NETWORK
COUNTERACT** with a friendly operative, first
select its order. It can then perform a 1AP action
for free, but cannot move more than 2\" during
that action. Once its done so, your opponent
then activates as normal.\n\n

An operative cannot **TRANSFER POWER** or
**NETWORK COUNTERACT** if it has an APL stat of
less than 2 (e.g. if the stat has been changed to
less than 2 by a rule). **NETWORK COUNTERACT** is
a counteraction, but the operative doesnt need
to be expended with an Engage order to do it.
That means if they’re ready when they **NETWORK
COUNTERACT**, they can still be activated as
normal later in the turning point. An operative
that does **NETWORK COUNTERACT** cannot
do so again, or counteract, during the same
turning point.
]]></string>


    <!--Equipment-->

    <string name="covert_guises_lore"><![CDATA[
        Using filthy bodysuits of local design, falsified insignia or emitters that broadcast shrouding
        static-filled hisses to foil biological senses, this Battleclade can infiltrate into restricted areas undetected.
]]></string>

    <string name="covert_guises_description"><![CDATA[
        After revealing this equipment option, roll one D3. As a **STRATEGIC GAMBIT** in the first
        turning point, a number of friendly **BATTLECLADE** Operatives equal to the result that are
        wholly within your drop zone can immediately perform a free **Reposition** action, but must
        end that move wholly within 3\" of your drop zone. Your **TECHNOARCHEOLOGIST** Operative
        cannot perform more than one **Reposition** action in the Strategy phase of the first turning
        point (result of Seeker of Divine Arcana rule as well).
]]></string>

    <string name="electromantic_capacitors_lore"><![CDATA[
       Wired into an Operatives numerous mechanical components, these devices can charge the bodies
       of a clandestine team with coruscating arcs of the sacred Motive Force.
]]></string>

    <string name="electromantic_capacitors_description"><![CDATA[
        Friendly **BATTLECLADE** Operatives melee weapons have the Shock weapon rule. Whenever a friendly
        **BATTLECLADE** Operative is retaliating, its melee weapons have the Severe weapon rule.
]]></string>

    <string name="concealed_apparatus_lore"><![CDATA[
       Seemingly equipper servitors can, at an imperative from their master, swiftly assemble far
       more deadly apparatus, the components of which were hidden in body cavities or as entirely different
       mechanisms.
]]></string>

    <string name="concealed_apparatus_description"><![CDATA[
        **STRATEGIC GAMBIT** in the second turning point. You can swap the locations of any number of
        friendly **BATTLECLADE SERVITOR** Operatives with each other (excluding **GUN SERVITOR**),
        and you can swap the locations of friendly **BATTLECLADE GUN SERVITOR** Operatives with each
        other (remove then from the killzone and swt them back up gain). You cannot swap any Operative
        that have done any of the following during the battle:
        \n
        -Used any weapons on their datacard.
        \n
        -Performed any actions on their datacard.
        \n
        -Used the Mechanosuture Array rule.

]]></string>

    <string name="neurocylic_reserve_cells_lore"><![CDATA[
       Battleclades are granted these devices to accelerate servitor capabilities.
]]></string>

    <string name="neurocylic_reserve_cells_description"><![CDATA[
       After revealing this equipment option, roll one D3. A number of times during the battle equal
       to the result, whenever you **TRANSFER POWER**, you can use this rule. If you do, you can
       **TRANSFER POWER** for 0AP (this takes precedence over the normal Noospheric Network Rules).
]]></string>



    <!--Ploys-->
    <!--Strategy ploys-->
    <string name="noospheric_possession_lore"><![CDATA[
    By broadcasting portions of their neural architecture into their thralls, sometimes via a
    well-positioned relay, manipulative Servitor Underseers effectively possess their tools to better
    direct the Omnissiahs wrath.
]]></string>

    <string name="noospheric_possession_description"><![CDATA[
**SUPPORT.** Whenever a friendly **BATTLECLADE SERVITOR** Operative is within 6\" of a friendly
**BATTLECLADE AUTO-PROXY** or **BATTLECLADE SERVITOR UNDERSEER** Operative, that friendly **SERVITOR**
Operativves weapons have the Accurrate 1 weapon rule.\n\n

For the purpose of the Comms Device universal equipment, the Operative the distance is being
determined from must control your Comms Device marker to add 3\" to its distance requirement
for this rule.
]]></string>

    <string name="duty_of_reclamation_lore"><![CDATA[
    Embedded in Battleclade operatives are lurking strands of enhanced binharic doctrine. These instructions await
the moment to activate, triggered by the proximity of a Tech-Priests designated prize.
]]></string>

    <string name="duty_of_reclamation_description"><![CDATA[
    Once per action, you can use the Command Reroll firefight ploy for 0CP if the attack or defence
dice was rolled for a friendly **BATTLECLADE** operative that contests an objective marker or
one of your mission markers.
]]></string>

    <string name="incantation_of_the_iron_soul_lore"><![CDATA[
    Through chanted binharic praise from the Tech-Priests,
or sparked by holy subroutines, microactuators lock
into bracing positions and reserve power cells are
brought online. The flesh may be weak, but the sacred
invulnerability of the Machine God’s augmetic blessings
is evident to all.
]]></string>

    <string name="incantation_of_the_iron_soul_description"><![CDATA[
    Whenever an attack dice inflicts damage of 3 or
more on a friendly **BATTLECLADE** operative,
roll one D6: on a 5+, subtract 1 from that
inflicted damage.
]]></string>

    <string name="prioritised_acquisition_lore"><![CDATA[
    Acquisition is a holy task to a Technoarcheologist,
and their zealous fanaticism bleeds into their binharic
instructions. Faced with the sacrilege of thieves,
aggression protocols are initiated and biochemical
stimulants are released in their thralls, endowing all with
a measure of their master’s repugnance.
]]></string>

    <string name="prioritised_acquisition_description"><![CDATA[
    Select one objective marker or one of your mission markers.\n
• Whenever determining control of that
marker, treat the total APL stat of friendly
**BATTLECLADE** operatives that contest it as 1
higher if at least one friendly **BATTLECLADE**
operative contests that marker. Note this isnt
a change to the APL stat, so any changes are
cumulative with this.\n
• Whenever a friendly **BATTLECLADE** operative
is within 3\" of that marker, add 1 to the Atk stat
of its melee weapons (to a maximum of 4).
]]></string>



    <!--Firefight ploys-->
    <string name="system_exorcism_lore"><![CDATA[
    By redirecting sensory pathways, purging contaminants
or unleashing feral machine spirits to consume tainted
logic loops, the elite operatives of a Battleclade can
exorcise many dangerous afflictions.
]]></string>

    <string name="system_exorcism_description"><![CDATA[
    Use this firefight ploy when you would activate a
friendly **BATTLECLADE** operative. Remove one
rules effect or stat change your opponent has
applied to it (e.g. Poison token, -1APL, cannot be
activated or perform actions, etc.), then activate
it. This ploy cannot allow it to regain lost wounds,
ignore the effects of being injured or remove
mission pack rules.
]]></string>

    <string name="remote_access_lore"><![CDATA[
    Projecting a canticle of hexamathic authority, the most
worthy Tech-Priests can commune with intransigent
machine spirits even without physical contact.
]]></string>

    <string name="remote_access_description"><![CDATA[
    Use this firefight ploy during a friendly
**BATTLECLADE TECH-PRIEST** operatives
activation. Once during that activation, you can
use one of the following rules:\n

• That operative doesnt require a marker to be
within its control range to perform a mission
action that usually requires this (this takes
precedence over that actions conditions).
Instead, the marker must be within 4\" of it
and no enemy operatives can contest that
marker. However, you can ignore enemy
operatives within control range of other
friendly **BATTLECLADE** operatives when
determining this.\n
• That operative doesnt require a hatchways
access point to be within its control range to
perform an **Operate Hatch** action. Instead, that
access point must be within 4\" of it.
]]></string>

    <string name="autoferric_supplication_lore"><![CDATA[
    In extremis, the Omnissiahs faithful channel their zeal
into shielding energy projectors and the refractive
realignment of their bionic body parts.
]]></string>

    <string name="autoferric_supplication_description"><![CDATA[
    Use this firefight ploy when an operative is
shooting a friendly **BATTLECLADE TECH-PRIEST**
operative, at the start of the Roll Attack Dice step.
Until the end of the sequence, ignore the Piercing
weapon rule.
]]></string>

    <string name="servile_surrogacy_lore"><![CDATA[
    Deeply woven into each thralls cybernetic programming
is the instinct to bodily shield their masters should they
be threatened.
]]></string>

    <string name="servile_surrogacy_description"><![CDATA[
    Use this firefight ploy when a friendly
**BATTLECLADE TECH-PRIEST** operative is
selected as the valid target of a Shoot action or
to fight against during the Fight action. Select
one friendly **BATTLECLADE SERVITOR** operative
visible to and within 3" of that first friendly
operative to become the valid target or to be
fought against (as appropriate) instead (even if
it wouldn’t normally be valid for this). If its the
Fight action, treat that SERVITOR operative as
being within the fighting operatives control range
for the duration of that action. If its the Shoot
action, that SERVITOR operative is only in cover
or obscured if the original target was.\n

This ploy has no effect if its the Shoot action
and the ranged weapon has the Blast or Torrent
weapon rule.
]]></string>

</resources>