<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <!--Battleclade-->

    <string name="battleclade_autoproxy_eye"><![CDATA[

        Achillan Eye

]]></string>







    <!--Faction Rules-->






  
    <!--Equipment-->

        <string name="purity_seals_lore"><![CDATA[
        Awarded by the Chapters Chaplains, purity seals are inscribed with blessings and inspire the bearer to fight with increased vigour.
]]></string>

          <string name="purity_seals_description"><![CDATA[

        Once per turning point, when a friendly **ANGEL OF DEATH** Operative is shooting, fighting or retaliating, if you roll two two or more fails, you
            can discard one of them to retain another as a normal success instead.

]]></string>

  <string name="chapter_reliquaries_lore"><![CDATA[
        Many Space Marines bear macabre relics taken from the bodies of their fallen. Those who bear these inspirational items fight all the harder to honour
    the sacrifice of their battle-brothers.
]]></string>

          <string name="chapter_reliquaries_description"><![CDATA[
        You can use the Wrath of Vengeance firefight ploy for 0CP if the specified friendly Operative has an **Engage** order
]]></string>

  <string name="tilting_shields_lore"><![CDATA[
    As well as displaying company colours and personal heraldry, a Space Marines tilting plate serves to protect the bearer in the press of melee combat.
]]></string>

          <string name="purity_seals_description"><![CDATA[
    Once per turning point, when a friendly **ANGEL OF DEATH** Operative is fighting or retaliating, after your opponent rolls their attack dice, but before re-rolls, you can use 
            this rule. If you do, your opponent cannot retain attack dice results of less than 6 as critical successes during that sequence (ex. Lethal, Rending or Severe).
]]></string>

  <string name="auspex_lore"><![CDATA[
    Auspexes come in many forms. These scanning devices can detect motion, analyse atmospheric conditions and reveal heat signatures.
]]></string>

          <string name="auspex_description"><![CDATA[
    Once per turning point, when a friendly **ANGEL OF DEATH** Operative performs the **Shoot** action, and you are selecting a valid target, you can use this rule.
            If you do, until the end of the activation/counteraction, enemy Operatives within 8\" of that friendly Operative cannot be Obscured.
]]></string>
  

    <!--Ploys-->
    <!--Strategy ploys-->

    <!--Firefight ploys-->


</resources>
