<resources>
    /Keywords

    <string name="keyword_accurrate">
        You can retain You can retain X Accurate results as normal successful before rolling dice.
    </string>

     <string name="keyword_balanced">
         You can re-roll one attack die.
     </string>

    <string name="keyword_blast">
    The target you select for a shoot action becomes the Primary target, and every other operative
                within X Blast distance and visible to the Primary Target becomes the Secondary targets(Regardless of their order). Resolve 
                 the shoot action for the Primary target, then roll another shoot action for every Secondary Target
                 (You have to roll dice for every valid target) if the Primary target was Obscure and/or in cover,
                 the Secondary targets will have those modifiers as well. 
    </string>

    <string name="keyword_brutal">
         Your opponent can only parry with critical successes.
     </string>

    <string name="keyword_ceaseless">
        You can re-roll all attack dice showing the same result(Ex: all dice with a result of 2)
    </string>

    <string name="keyword_concealed_position">
        This weapon can be used once while Concealed without changing order.
     </string>

    <string name="keyword_devastating">
        Critical hits inflict immediate damage equal to the Devastating value, the dice are 
                not discarded. If there´s Range associate with the keyword, inflict that damage each other operative in that
                distance.
    </string>

    <string name="keyword_heavy">
        An operative cannot use this weapon if it moved during its activation,
                        and it cannot move after performing a Shoot action with this weapon.\n\n
                        If marked Heavy (Reposition), Reposition is the only movement action
                        allowed that still permits shooting in the same activation.\n\n
                        An operative cannot use Guard with a Heavy weapon if these conditions are not met.
    </string>

     <string name="keyword_hot">
        After an operative shoots with this weapon, roll one D6, if the result
                 is equal or greater than the Hit stat nothing happens, if the roll is less than
                 the Hit stat, duplicate the value and deal that amount of damage to the friendly 
                operative who made the shoot action.
                 If you hit multiple targets, Ex: Blast. Still roll only one D6.
    </string>

    <string name="keyword_lethal">
        Your successes equal or greater to Lethal x value are Critical successes.
    </string>

    <string name="keyword_limited">
        After an operative uses this weapon x number of times, it cannot use this weapon
                again, if it hits multiple targets, Ex: Blast/Torrent. still treat it 
                as only one use.
    </string>

    <string name="keyword_obscure">
        Whenever an Operative Shoot another Opeative while this is Obscure, all Critical 
                successes will become Normal successes, any rule around Critical success is ignored
                (Ex: Devastating, Piercing Crits, Punishing).
    </string>

    <string name="keyword_psychic">
        This action or weapon is a psychic attack.
    </string>

    <string name="keyword_piercing">
        The defender picks one less dice based on the Piercing X value.
    </string>

    <string name="keyword_piercing_Crits">
        The defender picks one less dice based on the Piercing Crits X value, if you score a Critical success.
    </string>

    <string name="keyword_punishing">
        If you retain any critical successes, you can change one failed dice into one success normal attack.
    </string>

    <string name="keyword_range">
        Only operatives within X inches can be targeted.
    </string>

    <string name="keyword_relentless">
        You can re-roll all attack dice.
    </string>

    <string name="keyword_rending">
        Convert one normal hit into a critical when retaining a critical.
    </string>

    <string name="keyword_saturate">
        The defender cannot retain cover saves.
    </string>

    <string name="keyword_seek_light">
        For the purpose of selecting a valid target for a shoot action, you can
                 select operatives in Conceal if they are being cover by light terrain. This
                 doesn´t prevent Cover Saves if any.
    </string>

    <string name="keyword_seek">
        For the purpose of selecting a valid target for a shoot action, you can select operatives in Conceal. This doesn´t prevent any Cover Saves if any.
    </string>

    <string name="keyword_severe">
        If you don´t make any Critical success, you can change one Normal success
                 into a Critical success, any rule such as Devastating or Piercing Crits X is 
                applied accordingly, but it cannot be combine in any way with the rules Punishing
                 or Rending, Ex: You cant just have 2 free Crits lmao.
    </string>

    <string name="keyword_shock">
        The first time you strike with a Critical success, discard one of your
                 opponent´s unresolved Normal success, if the opponent has no more Normal
                 Successes, discard one of it´s Critical successes if any.
    </string>

    <string name="keyword_silent">
        This weapon can be used while having a Conceal order.
    </string>

    <string name="keyword_stun">
        If you retain any Critical success with this weapon, the enemy operative loses 1 Apl until the start of it´s next activation.
    </string>

    <string name="keyword_torrent">
        Select one valid target, this will be the Primary target, then select any
                 number of secondary targets if they are valid as well and, if they are within
                 Torrent X value range of the Primary objective. You cant select enemy targets 
                 in Control range of a friendly operative." +
                "Shoot this weapon against all of them, roll separately for each.
    </string>



    //Tacops
    <string name="recon_01_title">
        SCOUT ENEMY MOVEMENT
    </string>

    <string name="recon_01_reveal">
        The first time a friendly Operative performs the Scout action.
    </string>

    <string name="recon_01_atitle">
        SCOUT
    </string>

    <string name="recon_01_usage">
        1 AP / Firefight Phase
    </string>

    <string name="recon_01_description">
        Select one ready enemy Operative visible to and more than 6\" from
                         the active Operative. That enemy Operative is now monitored until the
                        Ready step of the next Strategy phase.\n\nAn Operative CANNOT perform this
                         action while it has an Engage order, during the first turning point, or
                        while within control range of an enemy Operative.
    </string>

    <string name="recon_01_victory">
        At the end of each turning point after the first for each monitored
                     enemy Operative that´s visible to any friendly Operative, you score 1VP.\nYou
                     Cannot score more than 2VP from this TacOp per turning point.
    </string>

    <string name="recon_02_title">
        RETRIEVAL
    </string>

    <string name="recon_02_reveal">
        The first time you score VP from this TacOp.
    </string>

    <string name="recon_02_atitle">
        RETRIEVE
    </string>

    <string name="recon_02_usage">
        1 APL / Firefight Phase
    </string>

    <string name="recon_02_description">
        If the active Operative controls an objective marker, that hasn´t been
                         been searched by friendly Operatives, that Operative is now carrying one of
                         your Retrieval mission markers and that objective marker is now searched.
                         Friendly Operatives can perform the Pick Up Marker action on your Retrieval
                         mission markers.\n\nAn Operative CANNOT perform this action during the first
                        turning point, or while within control range of an enemy Operative, or if
                         it´s already carrying a marker.
    </string>

    <string name="recon_02_victory">
        The first time each objective marked is searched by a friendly Operative
                     you score 1VP.\nAt the end of the battle, for each of your Retrieval mission markers
                     fiendly Operatives are carrying, you score 1VP.
    </string>

    <string name="recon_03_title">
        FLANK
    </string>

    <string name="recon_03_reveal">
        As a STRATEGIC GAMBIT.
    </string>

    <string name="recon_03_additional">
        Divide the killzone into two flanks(left and right) by drawing an
                     imaginary line that´s just like the centreline but vertical from each player
                     kill zone edge. An Operative contests a flank while is wholly within that side
                    (left or right) and wholly within the enemy the opponents territory. Friendly
                     Operatives control a flank if the total APL stat of those contesting that side
                     is greater than that of enemy Operatives.\n(Ex Your opponent has to follow these
                     rules to contest the flank and denied you point, his operatives must be on one
                     of the flanks and have a total APL in your territory greater than the total
                     APL you have in his territory and flank.)
    </string>

    <string name="recon_03_victory">
        After you reveal this TacOp, at the end of each turning point after the
                     first, for each flank friendly Operatives control, you score 1VP.
                     In the fourth turning point, if friendly Operatives also controlled that flank
                     at the end of end of the third turning point, you score 2VP instead.

        You cannot score more than 2VP from this TacOp per turning point.
    </string>

    <string name="security_01_title">
        PLANT BANNER
    </string>

    <string name="security_01_reveal">
        When you perform the Plant Banner action.
    </string>

    <string name="security_01_atitle">
        PLANT BANNER
    </string>

    <string name="security_01_usage">
        1 APL / Firefight Phase
    </string>

    <string name="security_01_description">
        Place your Banner mission marker within the active Operative´s control
                         range, wholly within your opponent´s territory and more than 5\" from a neutral
                         killzone edge. Operatives can perform the Pick Up Marker action on your
                         Banner mission marker.\n\nAn Operative CANNOT perform this action
                         during the first turning point, while within control range of an enemy
                         Operative, or if a friendly Operative has already performed this action
                         during the battle.
    </string>

    <string name="security_01_victory">
        At the end of each turning point after the first, if you Banner mission
                     marker is wholly within you opponent´s territory and friendly operatives control
                     it, you score 1VP; if that´s true and no enemy Operatives contest it, you score
                     2VP instead. Your Banner mission marker must be in the killzone to score(not
                     being carried).
    </string>

    <string name="security_02_title">
        MARTYRS
    </string>

    <string name="security_02_reveal">
        The first time a friendly Operative is incapacitated while contesting an objective
                     marker.
    </string>

    <string name="security_02_additional">
        Whenever a friendly Operative is incapacitated while contesting an objective marker, that marker
        gains one of your Martyr tokens. Note that this is only the first time each Operative is incapacitated
        (Ex Hierotek Circle).

        As a STRATEGIC GAMBIT in each turning point after the first, select
                     one friendly Operative to be your Envoy until the Ready step of the next
                     Strategy phase. You cannot select an Operative you selected during a previous
                     turning point.
    </string>

    <string name="security_02_victory">
        At the end of each turning point after the first, if a friendly Operative
                     contest an objective marker that has one or more of your Martyr tokens, you can
                     remove any of those tokens. For each token you remove this way, you score 1VP;
                    if friendly operatives also control that marker, you score 2VP instead.\nYou
                     cannot score more than 2VP from this TacOp per turning point.
    </string>

    <string name="security_03_title">
        ENVOY
    </string>

    <string name="security_03_reveal">
        The first time you select an envoy.
    </string>

    <string name="security_03_additional">
        As a STRATEGIC GAMBIT in each turning point after the first, select
                     one friendly Operative to be your Envoy until the Ready step of the next
                     Strategy phase. You cannot select an Operative you selected during a previous
                     turning point.
    </string>

    <string name="security_03_victory">
        At the end of each turning point after the first, if your Envoy is wholly
                     within enemy territory and not within control range of enemy Operatives, you score
                     1VP; if this is true and your Envoy has not lost any wounds during that turning
                     point, you score 2VP instead.
    </string>


    <string name="seek_and_destroy_01_title">
        SWEEP &amp; CLEAR
    </string>

    <string name="seek_and_destroy_01_reveal">
        The first time an enemy Operative is incapacitated while contesting an objective
                     marker, or the first time a friendly Operative performs the Clear action(whichever
                     comes first)
    </string>

    <string name="seek_and_destroy_01_atitle">
        CLEAR
    </string>

    <string name="seek_and_destroy_01_usage">
        1 APL / Firefight Phase
    </string>

    <string name="seek_and_destroy_01_description">
        An objective marker the active Operative controls is cleared for the
                         turning point.\n\nAn Operative CANNOT perform this action
                         during the first turning point, while within control range of an enemy
                        Operative.
    </string>

    <string name="seek_and_destroy_01_additional">
        When an enemy Operative that contests an objective marker is incapacitated,
                     that objective marker gains one of your Swept tokens(if it doesn´t have one already)
                     until the Ready step of the next Strategy phase.
    </string>

    <string name="seek_and_destroy_01_victory">
        At the end of each turning point after the first, if friendly operatives
                     control any objective markers that have one of your Swept tokens, you score 1VP.
                     If this is true and any of those objective markers are also cleared, you score
                     2VP instead. You cannot score more than 2VP from this TacOp per turning point.
    </string>

    <string name="seek_and_destroy_02_title">
        ROUTE
    </string>

    <string name="seek_and_destroy_02_reveal">
        The first time you score VP from this TacOp
    </string>

    <string name="seek_and_destroy_02_victory">
        Whenever a friendly Operative incapacitates an enemy Operative, if
                     that friendly Operative is within 6\" of your opponent´s drop zone, you score
                     1VP; if this is true and the enemy Operative had a Wounds stat of 12 or more,
                     you score 2 VP instead.\nYou cannot score more than 2VP from this TacOp per
                     turning point.
    </string>

    <string name="seek_and_destroy_03_title">
        DOMINATE
    </string>

    <string name="seek_and_destroy_03_reveal">
        The first time an enemy Operative is incapacitated by a friendly Operative.
    </string>

    <string name="seek_and_destroy_03_additional">
        Each time a friendly Operative incapacitates an enemy Operative, that
                     friendly Operative gains one of your Dominate tokens.
    </string>

    <string name="seek_and_destroy_03_victory">
        At the end of the third and fourth turning point, you can remove Dominate
                     tokens from friendly Operatives that aren´t incapacitated. For each you remove,
                    you score 1VP.\nYou cannot score more than 3VP from this op per turning point.
    </string>

    <string name="infiltration_01_title">
        TRACK ENEMY
    </string>

    <string name="infiltration_01_reveal">
        The first time you score VP from this TacOp.
    </string>

    <string name="infiltration_01_additional">
        An enemy Operative is being tracked if it´s a valid target for a
                     friendly Operative within 6\" of it. That friendly operative must have a Conceal
                     order, cannot be a valid target for the enemy Operative it´s attempting to Track
                    , and cannot be within control range of enemy Operatives.
    </string>

    <string name="infiltration_01_victory">
        At the end of each turning point after the first:\n*If one enemy Operative
                     is being tracked, you score 1VP, or 2VP instead if it´s the fourth turning point.\n
                    *If two or more enemy Operatives are being tracked, you score 2VP.\nYou cannot
                    "score more than 2VP from this TacOp per turning point.
    </string>

    <string name="infiltration_02_title">
        STEAL INTELLIGENCE
    </string>

    <string name="infiltration_02_reveal">
        The first time an enemy Operative is incapacitated.
    </string>

    <string name="infiltration_02_additional">
        Whenever an enemy Operative is incapacitated, before it´s removed from
                     the killzone, place one of your Intelligence mission markers within its control
                     range.\nFriendly Operatives can perform the Pick Up Marker action on your Intelligence
                     mission markers, and for the purpose of that action´s conditions, an Operative can
                     carry 2 Intelligence markers, or one other marker and one Intelligence marker.
    </string>

    <string name="infiltration_02_victory">
        At the end of each turning point after the first, if any friendly Operative
                     are carrying any of your Intelligence mission markers, you score 1VP.\nAt the
                     end of the battle, for each of your Intelligence mission markers friendly
                     Operatives are carrying, you score 1VP.
    </string>

    <string name="infiltration_03_title">
        PLANT DEVICES
    </string>

    <string name="infiltration_03_reveal">
        The first time a friendly Operative performs the Plant Device action.
    </string>

    <string name="infiltration_03_atitle">
        PLANT DEVICE
    </string>

    <string name="infiltration_03_usage">
        1 APL / Firefight Phase
    </string>

    <string name="infiltration_03_description">
        One objective marker the active operative controls gains one of your
                         Device tokens.\n\nAn Operative CANNOT perform this action
                         during the first turning point, while within control range of an enemy
                        Operative, or if that objective marker already has one of your Device tokens.
    </string>

    <string name="infiltration_03_victory">
        At the end of each turning point after the first:\n*If your opponent´s
                     objective marker has one of your Device tokens, you score 1VP.\n*For each other
                     objective marker enemy Operatives contest that has one of your Device tokens
                    , you score 1VP.\nYou cannot score more than 2VP from this TacOp per turning point.
    </string>


    //Operatives

        //Plague Marines
    <string name="malignantplaguecaster_poisonus_miasma">
        POISONOUS MIASMA
    </string>

    <string name="malignantplaguecaster_poisonus_miasma_usage">
        1 AP /SELECT AN ENEMY OPERATIVE
    </string>

    <string name="malignantplaguecaster_poisonus_miasma_description">
        Psychic Select one enemy operative visible and within 7\" of this operative
                     or one enemy Operative that´s a valid target for this Operative. That enemy
                     Operative gains one of your Poison tokens. If it has one already, inflict 3
                     damage on that enemy instead.\n\nThis operative CANNOT perform this action while
                     within control range of an enemy Operative.
    </string>

    <string name="malignantplaguecaster_putrescent_vitality">
        PUTRESCENT VITALITY
    </string>

    <string name="malignantplaguecaster_putrescent_vitality_usage">
        1 AP /SELECT AN ALLY OPERATIVE
    </string>

    <string name="malignantplaguecaster_putrescent_vitality_description">
        Psychic select one friendly operative visible and within 3\" of this
                     Operative, then roll 2D6: if the result is 7, the selected Operative regains
                     7 lost wounds; otherwise, the selected Operative regains wounds equal to the
                     highest result of the 2D6.\n\nThis operative CANNOT perform this action while
                     within control range of an enemy Operative, or more than once per turning point.
    </string>

    <string name="plaguemarinebombardier_grenadier">
        GRENADIER
    </string>

    <string name="plaguemarinebombardier_grenadier_usage">
        Passive
    </string>

    <string name="plaguemarinebombardier_grenadier_description">
        This operative can use blight and krak grenades ignoring the limit of uses
                    you have per universal equipment(It doesn´t count toward the number of grenades
                    the rest of the team can use), whenever this operative uses a grenade, improve the
                     Hit stat of that weapon by 1 and blight grenades have the Toxic weapon rule
    </string>

    <string name="plaguemarinechambion_gfblessing">
        Grandfather’s Blessing
    </string>

    <string name="plaguemarinechambion_gfblessing_usage">
        Passive
    </string>

    <string name="plaguemarinechambion_gfblessing_description">
       Whenever an enemy Operative that has one of your Poison tokens loses one
                     or more wounds within 7" of this operative, this operative regains up to an
                    equal number of lost wounds(to a maximum of 3 per turning point and only if
                    this operative isn´t incapacitated).
    </string>






    <string name="Select_Alliance"> Seleccionar Faccion</string>

    <string name="app_name">KillTeamRuleSet</string>
</resources>
