<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>


     <string name="plaguemarine_toxic"><![CDATA[

         Toxic

     ]]></string>

    <string name="plaguemarine_toxic_usage"><![CDATA[
         Pasiva
     ]]></string>

    <string name="plaguemarine_toxic_description"><![CDATA[
        Whenever this Operative is using this weapon against an enemy Operative that has one of your Poison tokens, add 1 to both Dmg stats of this weapon.
     ]]></string>


    <!--Plague Marines-->
    <string name="malignantplaguecaster_poisonus_miasma"><![CDATA[

        POISONOUS MIASMA

]]></string>

    <string name="malignantplaguecaster_poisonus_miasma_usage"><![CDATA[

        1 AP /SELECT AN ENEMY OPERATIVE

]]></string>

    <string name="malignantplaguecaster_poisonus_miasma_description"><![CDATA[
    Psychic Select one enemy operative visible and within 7\" of this operative
    or one enemy Operative thats a valid target for this Operative. That enemy
    Operative gains one of your Poison tokens. If it has one already, inflict 3
    damage on that enemy instead.\n\n

    This operative CANNOT perform this action while within control range of an enemy Operative.
]]></string>

    <string name="malignantplaguecaster_putrescent_vitality"><![CDATA[

        PUTRESCENT VITALITY

]]></string>

    <string name="malignantplaguecaster_putrescent_vitality_usage"><![CDATA[

        1 AP /SELECT AN ALLY OPERATIVE

]]></string>

    <string name="malignantplaguecaster_putrescent_vitality_description"><![CDATA[
        Psychic select one friendly operative visible and within 3\" of this
                     Operative, then roll 2D6: if the result is 7, the selected Operative regains
                     7 lost wounds; otherwise, the selected Operative regains wounds equal to the
                     highest result of the 2D6.\n\nThis operative CANNOT perform this action while
                     within control range of an enemy Operative, or more than once per turning point.
]]></string>

    <string name="plaguemarinebombardier_grenadier"><![CDATA[

        GRENADIER

]]></string>

    <string name="plaguemarinebombardier_grenadier_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

]]></string>

    <string name="plaguemarinebombardier_grenadier_description"><![CDATA[

        This operative can use blight and krak grenades ignoring the limit of uses
                    you have per universal equipment(It doesnt count toward the number of grenades
                    the rest of the team can use), whenever this operative uses a grenade, improve the
                     Hit stat of that weapon by 1 and blight grenades have the Toxic weapon rule

]]></string>

    <string name="plaguemarinechambion_gfblessing"><![CDATA[

        Grandfather’s Blessing

]]></string>

    <string name="plaguemarinechambion_gfblessing_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

]]></string>

    <string name="plaguemarinechambion_gfblessing_description"><![CDATA[
    Whenever an enemy Operative that has one of your Poison tokens loses one or more wounds within 7" of this operative, this operative regains up to an equal number of lost wounds(to a maximum of 3 per turning point and only if this operative isnt incapacitated).
]]></string>


    <string name="plaguemarinefighter_flail"><![CDATA[

        FLAIL

]]></string>

    <string name="plaguemarinefighter_flail_usage"><![CDATA[

        1 AP/ Fight Action

]]></string>

    <string name="plaguemarinefighter_flail_description"><![CDATA[
         Inflict D3+2 damage on each other operative thats visible and within 2\" of this operative. Roll separately foe each: if its an enemy operative, if the D3
   result is a 3, that enemy operative also gains one of your Poison tokens(if it
   doesnt have already one).\n\n

    This action is treated as a Fight action, and this operative cannot perform it while having a **Conceal** order
]]></string>

    <string name="plaguemarine_iconbearer"><![CDATA[

        ICON BEARER

]]></string>

    <string name="plaguemarine_iconbearer_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

]]></string>

    <string name="plaguemarine_iconbearer_description"><![CDATA[

      Whenever determining control of a marker, treat this operative’s APL stat
                     as 1 higher. Note this isn’t a change to its APL stat, so any changes are
                    cumulative with this

]]></string>

    <string name="plaguemarine_icon_of_contagion"><![CDATA[

        ICON OF CONTAGION

]]></string>

    <string name="plaguemarine_icon_of_contagionr_usage"><![CDATA[

        Strategy Phase

]]></string>

    <string name="plaguemarine_icon_of_contagionr_description"><![CDATA[

      Whenever this operative is within your opponents territory, the Contagion
                     strategy ploy costs you 0CP.

]]></string>

    <string name="plaguemarinefighter"><![CDATA[

        GRENADIER

]]></string>

    <string name="plaguemarinefighter_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

]]></string>

    <string name="plaguemarinefighter_description"><![CDATA[

        This operative can use blight and krak grenades ignoring the limit of uses
                    you have per universal equipment(It doesnt count toward the number of grenades
                    the rest of the team can use), whenever this operative uses a grenade, improve the
                     Hit stat of that weapon by 1 and blight grenades have the Toxic weapon rule

]]></string>

    <string name="plaguemarinewarrior"><![CDATA[

        Repulsive Fortitude

]]></string>

    <string name="plaguemarinewarrior_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

]]></string>

    <string name="plaguemarinewarrior_description"><![CDATA[
        Whenever an Operative is shooting this Operativem defence dice results of 5+ are critical successes
]]></string>




















    <!--/Equipment Wreckas-->

    <string name="plague_bell"><![CDATA[

        PLAGUE BELLS

]]></string>

    <string name="plague_bell_lore"><![CDATA[

        When the plague bells toll, the Death Guard are infused with corrupted energy, heightening their unholy resilence to extraordinary levels.

]]></string>

    <string name="plague_bell_description"><![CDATA[
        You can ignore any changes to the stats of friendly **PLAGUE MARINES** Operatives from being injured.
]]></string>


    <string name="plague_blight_grenades"><![CDATA[

        BLIGHT GRENADES

]]></string>

    <string name="plague_blight_grenades_lore"><![CDATA[
        These devices are packed with explosives, shards of jagged metal and deadly pathogens that poison any unfortunate enough to survive the initial blast.
]]></string>

    <string name="plague_blight_grenades_description"><![CDATA[
        Friendly **PLAGUE MARINES** Operatives have the following range weapon (you cannot use it more than twice per battle):
]]></string>

    <string name="plague_rounds"><![CDATA[
        PLAGUE ROUNDS
]]></string>

    <string name="plague_rounds_lore"><![CDATA[

       Virulent toxins ooze from these projectiles, so that those struck by them are infected with deadly diseases.

]]></string>

    <string name="plague_rounds_description"><![CDATA[

        Friendly **PLAGUE MARINES** Operatives Boltguns and Bolt Pistols have the Poison and Severe weapon rules

]]></string>

    <string name="plague_poison_vents"><![CDATA[

        POISON VENTS

]]></string>

    <string name="plague_poison_vents_lore"><![CDATA[

        Activating vents in their power armour, Plague Marines may unleash clouds of sickening fumes that clog the lungs of nearby foes.

]]></string>

    <string name="plague_poison_vents_description"><![CDATA[

        Whenever an enemy Operative that doesnt have one of your Poison tokens is activated within 3\"
        friendly Operative, roll one D3: on 3, that Operative gains one of your Poison tokens

]]></string>

    <!--/Faction Rules Plague marines-->


    <string name="plague_astartes"><![CDATA[

        ASTARTES

]]></string>

    <string name="plague_astartes_lore"><![CDATA[

        Space Marines are genetically augmented transhumans forged for only one purpose: war

]]></string>

    <string name="plague_astartes_description"><![CDATA[

        During each **Plague Marine** Operatives activation, it can perform either two Shoot actions
        or two Fight actions. if its two Shoot actions, a Bolt Pistol, Boltgun or **PSYCHIC** weapon
        must be selected for at least one of them. You cannot select the same **PSYCHIC** ranged weapon
        more than once per activation.

        Each friendly **PLAGUE MARINE** Operative can counteract regardless of its order.
]]></string>

    <string name="plague_poison"><![CDATA[

        POISON

]]></string>

    <string name="plague_poison_lore"><![CDATA[

        Nurgle deals in warp-tainted poisons, toxins, viral plagues and sicknesses of the soul that defy
        both natural resilience and medical intervention

]]></string>

    <string name="plague_poison_description"><![CDATA[

        Some weapons in this teams rules have the Poison weapon rule.

        **Poison:** In the Resolve Attack Step, if you inflict damage with any successes, the Operative
        this weapon is being used against (excluding friendly **PLAGUE MARINE** Operatives) gains one
        of your Poison tokens (if it doesnt have one already). Whenever an Operative that has one of
        your Poison tokens is activated, inflict 1 damage on it.

]]></string>



    <string name="plague_disgustingly_resilent"><![CDATA[

        DISGUSTINGLY RESILIENT

]]></string>

    <string name="plague_disgustingly_resilent_lore"><![CDATA[

        The followers of Nurgle possess extreme resilience to bullet and blade, for their hideous
        forms are swollen by death, decay and disease.

]]></string>

    <string name="plague_disgustingly_resilent_description"><![CDATA[

        Whenever an attack dice inflicts damage of 3 or more on a friendly **PLAGUE MARINE** Operative,
        roll one D6: on a 4+, subtract 1 from that inflicted damage.

]]></string>


    <!--/Ploys Plague marines-->

    <!--/Strategic Ploy Plague marines-->

    <string name="plague_contagion"><![CDATA[

        CONTAGION

]]></string>

    <string name="plague_contagion_lore"><![CDATA[

        Plague Marines are oozing with contagion, their hideous forms emanating a miasma of decay that saps
        the vigour of their foes.

]]></string>

    <string name="plague_contagion_description"><![CDATA[

        Substract 2\" from the Move stat of an enemy Operative and worsen the Hit stat of ots weapons
        by 1 (this isnt cumulative with being injured) whenever any of the following are true:\n\n

        *It has one of your Poison tokens and is visible to (or vice versa) and within 3\" of friendly **PLAGUE MARINES** Operatives.
        \n
        *Its visible to (or vice versa) and within 3\" of a friendly **PLAGUE MARINE ICON BEARER** Operative.

]]></string>

    <string name="plague_lumbering_death"><![CDATA[

        LUMBERING DEATH

]]></string>

    <string name="plague_lumbering_lore"><![CDATA[

        Plague Marines are methodical and uncompromising in their approach to warfare, advancing and
        firing with steadfast determination.

]]></string>

    <string name="plague_lumbering_description"><![CDATA[

        Whenever a friendly **PLAGUE MARINE** Operative is shooting or fighting during an activation
        in which it hasnt move more than 3\", or whenever its retaliating, its weapons have the Ceaseless
        weapon rule

]]></string>

    <string name="plague_cloud_flies"><![CDATA[

        CLOUD OF FLIES

]]></string>

    <string name="plague_cloud_flies_lore"><![CDATA[

        Disgusting, fat-bodied flies swarm the killzone, blurring the forms of advancing Plague Marines
        and absorbing the enemy´s projectiles.

]]></string>

    <string name="plague_cloud_flies_description"><![CDATA[

        Place one of your Cloud of Flies markers in the killzone, Whenever an Operative is shooting
        a friendly **PLAGUE MARINE** Operative thats more than 3\" from it, if that friendly Operative
        is wholly within 1\" of that marker, that friendly Operative is obscured. In the Ready step of the
        next Strategy phase, remove that marker.

]]></string>

    <string name="plague_nurglings"><![CDATA[

        NURGLINGS

]]></string>

    <string name="plague_nurglings_lore"><![CDATA[

        The smallest of Nurgle daemons, Nurlings are both malicious and playful cackling wildly as they claw and
        harass the Plague Marines foes with pestilent claws and teeth.

]]></string>

    <string name="plague_nurglings_description"><![CDATA[

        Select one enemy Operative within 3" of a friendly **PLAGUE MARINE** Operative, or one enemy
        Operative that has one of your Poison tokens and is within 7\" of a friendly **PLAGUE MARINES**
        Operative. Until the end of the selected Operatives next activation, subtract 1 from its APL stat.

]]></string>

    <!--/Firefight Ploy Plague marines-->

    <string name="plague_virulent_poison"><![CDATA[

        VIRULENT POISON

]]></string>

    <string name="plague_virulent_poison_lore"><![CDATA[

        The most potent of Grandfather Nurgle foul plagues spread swiftly through the air, breaching
        even enviro-seals and filtration masks.

]]></string>

    <string name="plague_virulent_poison_description"><![CDATA[

        Use this firefight ploy during a friendly **PLAGUE MARINE** Operatives activation or
        counteraction, before of after it performs an action. One enemy Operative within 3\"
        of, or visible to and within 7\" of, that Operative gains one of your Poison tokens (
        if it doesnt already have one).

]]></string>

    <string name="plague_poisonous_demise"><![CDATA[

        POISONOUS DEMISE

]]></string>

    <string name="plague_poisonous_demise_lore"><![CDATA[

        The body of a Plague Marine plays host of countless poisons and plagues. Upon death, their
        bloated forms may detonate, spreading foul contagion all around.

]]></string>

    <string name="plague_poisonous_demise_description"><![CDATA[

        Use this Firefight ploy when a friendly Operative **PLAGUE MARINES** Operatives is incapacitated,
        before its removed from the killzone. Each enemy Operative visible to and within 3\" of that
        Operative gains one of your Poison token (if they dont already have one): for each of those enemy
        Operatives that already has one of your Poison tokens (including if they gained one during this
        action), inflict 1 damage on them instead.

]]></string>

    <string name="plague_sickening_resilence"><![CDATA[

        SICKENING RESILENCE

]]></string>

    <string name="plague_sickening_resilence_lore"><![CDATA[

        By voluntarily offering their bodies as hosts for the Grandfather contagious gifts, some Plague
        Marines are granted even greater endurance.

]]></string>

    <string name="plague_sickening_resilence_description"><![CDATA[

        Use this firefight ploy when an attack dice inflicts damage on a friendly **PLAGUE MARINES**
        Operative. Until the end of the activation or counteraction, for the purpose of the
        Disgustingly Resilient rule for that Operative, always subtract 1 from the damage inflicted
        (to a minimum of 2), you dont need to roll.

]]></string>

    <string name="plague_curse_rot"><![CDATA[

        CURSE OF ROT

]]></string>

    <string name="plague_curse_rot_lore"><![CDATA[

        To engage a Plague Marine in single combat is to expose oneself to wilting contagion
        and soul-eroding decay.

]]></string>

    <string name="plague_curse_rot_description"><![CDATA[

        Use this firefight ploy when a friendly **PLAGUE MARINE** Operative is shooting against
        or fighting against and enemy Operative within 3\" of it (or within 7\" if it has one of
        your Poison tokens), after your opponent rolls their attack or defence dice. For eac result of 3
        they roll, inflict 1 damage on that enemy Operative that result cannot be retained as a
        success and they cannot re-roll it.

]]></string>




</resources>