<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>


    <!--Voidscarred-->

    <string name="veteran_rider_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="veteran_rider_description"><![CDATA[
This operative can perform a 1AP action for
free during their activation as a result of the Aeldari Raiders rule (instead of the Dash action).
    ]]></string>

    <string name="one_step_ahead_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="one_step_ahead_description"><![CDATA[
Once per battle, after an enemy operative performs an action, if this operative is
ready, you can use this rule. If you do, roll one D6: if the result is higher than that enemy operatives
APL stat, you can interrupt and immediately perform either a free **Shoot** or a free **Fight** action with
this operative, but you cannot select any other enemy operative as a valid target or to fight against
during that action (note that secondary targets from the Blast weapon rule can still be targeted). After
you perform that action, subtract 1 from this operatives APL stat until the end of its next activation.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="corsair_blademaster_usage"><![CDATA[
            Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="corsair_blademaster_description"><![CDATA[
This operative can perform the **Dash** action
during an activation in which it performed the **Charge** action,
but can only use any remaining move distance it had from that **Charge** action (to a maximum of 3\").
    ]]></string>

    <string name="corsair_blade_stance_usage"><![CDATA[
            Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="corsair_blade_stance_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever this operative is fighting or retaliating,
you can resolve one of your successes before the normal order. If
you do, that success must be used to block.
    ]]></string>


    <string name="faolchu_bond_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="faolchu_bond_description"><![CDATA[
The first time during each turning point that this operative is retaliating, if it is ready,
in the Resolve Attack Dice step of that sequence, you resolve the first attack dice (i.e. defender instead of attacker).
    ]]></string>

    <string name="erudite_hunter_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="erudite_hunter_description"><![CDATA[
**STRATEGIC GAMBIT**. Select one enemy operative within 9\" of this operative. Once during this
turning point, after that enemy operative performs an action in which it moves, you can interrupt to
use this rule. If you do, this operative can immediately perform either a free **Reposition**
action (it cannot end that move further away from that enemy operative), or a free **Charge** action
(you can change its order to do so, and it must end that move within control range of that enemy operative).
In a killzone that uses the close quarters rules (e.g. Killzone: Tomb World), ignore Wall terrain when determining further away.
    ]]></string>


    <string name="blink_pack_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="blink_pack_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever this operative performs the **Charge, Fall Back** or **Reposition** action, it can warp jump.
If it does, do not move it. Instead, remove it from the killzone and set it back up wholly within 7\"
horizontally of its original location (in a killzone that uses the close quarters rules, e.g. Killzone:
Tomb World, this distance can be measured through Wall terrain). It must be set up in a
location it can be placed, and unless it is the Charge action, it cannot be set up within control
range of an enemy operative.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="slicing_attack_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="slicing_attack_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever this operative performs the **Reposition** action with a warp jump (see other side of card),
you can use this rule. If you do, after it moves, draw an imaginary
line 1mm in diameter and up to 7\" long between it and its
previous location. Note this does not have to be a straight line.
Inflict D3+2 damage on one enemy operative that line crosses.
You cannot inflict damage on an enemy operative that was not
visible to this operative at the start of that action. A 28mm round
marker can be temporarily placed underneath this operative
before it moves to help determine this.
    ]]></string>


    <string name="soul_channel_usage"><![CDATA[
            1AP
    ]]></string>

    <string name="soul_channel_description"><![CDATA[
**PSYCHIC**. Select one other friendly **CORSAIR VOIDSCARRED** operative visible to and within 6\" of this
operative. Until the end of that operatives next activation, add 1 to its APL stat.\n\n

This operative cannot perform this action while within control
range of an enemy operative.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="soul_heal_usage"><![CDATA[
        1AP
    ]]></string>

    <string name="soul_heal_description"><![CDATA[
**PSYCHIC**. Select one friendly **CORSAIR VOIDSCARRED** operative visible to and within 6\" of this
operative. That operative regains up to 2D3 lost wounds.\n\n

This operative cannot perform this action while within control
range of an enemy operative.
    ]]></string>


    <string name="quick_trigger_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="quick_trigger_description"><![CDATA[
This operative can perform the **Shoot** action while within control range of an enemy operative. If it
does, when selecting a valid target, you can only select an enemy operative within this operatives control range, and can
do so even if other friendly operatives are within that enemy operatives control range.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="corsair_pistol_barrage_usage"><![CDATA[
        1AP
    ]]></string>

    <string name="corsair_pistol_barrage_description"><![CDATA[
Perform two free **Shoot** actions with this operative (this
takes precedence over action restrictions). You must select
its fusion pistol for one action and its shuriken pistol for the
other (in any order).\n\n

This operative cannot perform this action while it has a
Conceal order, or during an activation in which it performed the **Shoot** action (or vice versa).
    ]]></string>

    <string name="prowling_raiders_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="prowling_raiders_description"><![CDATA[
You can use the Capricious Flight and Light Fingers firefight ploys for 0CP each if a friendly
**WARRIOR** operative is the specified **CORSAIR VOIDSCARRED** operative.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="warp_fold_usage"><![CDATA[
        1AP
    ]]></string>

    <string name="warp_fold_description"><![CDATA[
**PSYCHIC.** Select two friendly **CORSAIR VOIDSCARRED** operatives visible to and within 5\" of this
operative. Remove them both from the killzone and set them
back up in each others previous locations (in other words,
swap their positions). If one of them performed the **Charge,
Fall Back** or **Reposition** action during this turning point
and the other is ready, the other cannot perform any of those
actions in its activation during this turning point.\n\n

This operative cannot perform this action while within control range of an enemy operative.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="warding_shield_usage"><![CDATA[
        1AP
    ]]></string>

    <string name="warding_shield_description"><![CDATA[
**PSYCHIC**. Select one friendly **CORSAIR VOIDSCARRED** operative visible to and within 6\" of this
operative. Until the start of this operatives next activation,
until it is incapacitated or until it performs this action
again (whichever comes first), the first time an attack dice
inflicts Normal Dmg on that friendly operative, ignore that inflicted damage.\n\n

This operative cannot perform this action while within control
range of an enemy operative.
    ]]></string>




    <!--Faction Rules-->

    <string name="_lore"><![CDATA[

]]></string>

    <string name="_description"><![CDATA[

]]></string>

    <string name="_lore"><![CDATA[

]]></string>

    <string name="_description"><![CDATA[

]]></string>

    <string name="_lore"><![CDATA[

]]></string>

    <string name="_description"><![CDATA[

]]></string>


    <!--Equipment-->

    <string name="_lore"><![CDATA[

]]></string>

    <string name="_description"><![CDATA[

]]></string>

    <string name="_lore"><![CDATA[

]]></string>

    <string name="_description"><![CDATA[

]]></string>

    <string name="_lore"><![CDATA[

]]></string>

    <string name="_description"><![CDATA[

]]></string>

    <string name="_lore"><![CDATA[

]]></string>

    <string name="_description"><![CDATA[

]]></string>



    <!--Ploys-->
    <!--Strategy ploys-->
    <string name="_lore"><![CDATA[

]]></string>

    <string name="_description"><![CDATA[

]]></string>

    <string name="_lore"><![CDATA[

]]></string>

    <string name="_description"><![CDATA[

]]></string>

    <string name="_lore"><![CDATA[

]]></string>

    <string name="_description"><![CDATA[

]]></string>

    <string name="_lore"><![CDATA[

]]></string>

    <string name="_description"><![CDATA[

]]></string>



    <!--Firefight ploys-->
    <string name="_lore"><![CDATA[

]]></string>

    <string name="_description"><![CDATA[

]]></string>

    <string name="_lore"><![CDATA[

]]></string>

    <string name="_description"><![CDATA[

]]></string>

    <string name="_lore"><![CDATA[

]]></string>

    <string name="_description"><![CDATA[

]]></string>

    <string name="_lore"><![CDATA[

]]></string>

    <string name="_description"><![CDATA[

]]></string>

</resources>