<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>


    <!--farstalker-->

    <string name="call_the_kill_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="call_the_kill_description"><![CDATA[
**STRATEGIC GAMBIT** if this operative is
in the killzone. Select one enemy operative to be your mark
for the turning point. Whenever a friendly **FARSTALKER KINBAND** operative is shooting against, fighting against or
retaliating against your mark, that friendly operatives weapons
have the Balanced weapon rule. Whenever your mark is
incapacitated, you can select a new enemy operative to be your
mark for the turning point (and can continue to do so during this
turning point).
    ]]></string>

    <string name="victory_shriek_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="victory_shriek_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever your mark is incapacitated, you can
select one friendly **FARSTALKER KINBAND** operative
within 6\" of this operative. Until the end of the battle, that
operatives weapons have the Balanced weapon rule. Each
friendly operative can only be selected for this rule once per battle.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="energise_usage"><![CDATA[
        1AP
    ]]></string>

    <string name="energise_description"><![CDATA[
Until the end of the turning point or until this operative
has shot with its accelerator bow (whichever comes first),
all profiles of its accelerator bow have the Lethal 5+
weapon rule.\n\n

This operative cannot perform this action while within control
range of an enemy operative.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="kroot_hardy_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="kroot_hardy_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever an attack dice would inflict Critical Dmg on this
operative, you can choose for that attack dice to inflict Normal Dmg instead.
    ]]></string>


    <string name="cold_blooded_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="cold_blooded_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever this operative is shooting against,
fighting against or retaliating against a wounded enemy
operative, this operatives weapons have the Lethal 5+ weapon
rule; if that enemy operative is also injured, this operatives
weapons also have the Rending weapon rule.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="vicious_duellist_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="vicious_duellist_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever this operative is fighting or
retaliating, for each attack dice your opponent discards as a fail,
inflict 1 damage on the enemy operative in that sequence.
    ]]></string>


    <string name="savage_assault_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="savage_assault_description"><![CDATA[
The first time this operative performs the **Fight**
action during each of its activations, if neither it nor the enemy
operative in that sequence is incapacitated, this operative can
immediately perform a free **Fight** action afterwards, but you
cannot select any other enemy operative to fight against during
that action (and only if it is still valid to fight against). This takes
precedence over action restrictions.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="kroot_beast_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="kroot_beast_description"><![CDATA[
This operative cannot perform any actions other than **Charge, Dash,
Fall Back, Fight, Gather, Guard, Reposition, Pick Up Marker** and
**Place Marker**. It cannot use any weapons that are not on its datacard.
    ]]></string>


    <string name="bad_tempered_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="bad_tempered_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever an enemy operative performs the **Fight** action, if
this operative is a valid operative to fight against, you can force them to select
this operative to fight against instead. Whenever an enemy operative ends
the **Charge** action within control range of another friendly **FARSTALKER
KINBAND** operative within 3\" of this operative, if this operative is not within
control range of enemy operatives, this operative can immediately perform a
free **Charge** action (you can change its order to **Engage** to do so), but must
end that move within control range of that enemy operative.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="kroot_gather_usage"><![CDATA[
        1AP
    ]]></string>

    <string name="kroot_gather_description"><![CDATA[
Perform a free **Dash** or **Reposition** action
with this operative. During that move, it can perform a free **Pick Up Marker** or
**Place Marker** action (you can determine control during that action to do so), and any
remaining move distance it had from the Dash or **Reposition** action can be used after it does so.
    ]]></string>


    <string name="long_sight_usage"><![CDATA[
        1AP
    ]]></string>

    <string name="long_sight_description"><![CDATA[
Until the start of this operative’s next activation:\n
\n
• The concealed and stationary profiles of its Kroot hunting rifle have the Lethal 5+ weapon rule.\n
\n
• Whenever it is shooting with its Kroot hunting rifle, enemy operatives cannot be obscured.\n\n

This operative cannot perform this action while within control range of an enemy operative.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="quick_draw_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="quick_draw_description"><![CDATA[
Once per turning point, when an enemy operative is performing the **Shoot**
action and this operative is selected as the valid target (or if it will be a secondary target
from the Blast weapon rule), if this operative is ready, you can interrupt that action to
use this rule. If you do, this operative can immediately perform a free **Shoot** action with
its dual Kroot pistols (focused) against that enemy operative (you can change its order
to **Engage** to do so), but that enemy operative must be a valid target.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="kroot_salvo_usage"><![CDATA[
        Special Weapon Rule
    ]]></string>

    <string name="kroot_salvo_description"><![CDATA[
Select up to two different valid targets that are not within control
range of friendly operatives. Shoot with this weapon against both of them
in an order of your choice (roll each sequence separately).
    ]]></string>


    <string name="kroot_stalker_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="kroot_stalker_description"><![CDATA[
This operative can perform the **Charge** action while it has a Conceal order.
    ]]></string>


    <string name="stealth_attack_usage"><![CDATA[
        2AP
    ]]></string>

    <string name="stealth_attack_description"><![CDATA[
Perform a free **Charge** action with this operative, but do not exceed its Move stat (i.e. do not add
2\"). Then immediately perform a free **Fight** action with this operative. The first time you strike
during that action, you can immediately resolve another of your successes as a strike (before
your opponent).\n\n

This operative cannot perform this action while it has an Engage order, while within control
range of an enemy operative, or if it is not within 1\" of Light or Heavy terrain.
    ]]></string>


    <string name="marked_for_the_hunt_usage"><![CDATA[
        1AP
    ]]></string>

    <string name="marked_for_the_hunt_description"><![CDATA[
Remove your Pech\’ra marker from the killzone (if any).
Then place your Pech\’ra marker visible to this operative, or
on Vantage terrain of a terrain feature that is visible to this
operative. Whenever a friendly **FARSTALKER KINBAND**
operative is shooting an enemy operative that has that marker
within its control range, that friendly operatives ranged
weapons have the Seek Light weapon rule.\n
\n
-At the start of this operatives next activation or if it is
removed from the killzone (whichever comes first), remove
your Pech\’ra marker from the killzone.\n\n

This operative cannot perform this action while within control range of an enemy operative.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="from_the_eye_above_usage"><![CDATA[
        1AP
    ]]></string>

    <string name="from_the_eye_above_description"><![CDATA[
**SUPPORT.** Select one other friendly **FARSTALKER KINBAND** operative visible to and within 6\" of this
operative. Until the end of that operatives next activation, add 1 to its APL stat.\n\n

This operative cannot perform this action while within control range of an enemy operative.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="kroot_ready_for_anything_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="kroot_ready_for_anything_description"><![CDATA[
Once per turning point, during a friendly **WARRIOR** operatives activation, you can use the Meat,
Piercing Shot or Toxin Shot rule (see faction equipment) for
that operative. Doing so does not count for its once per turning point limit.
    ]]></string>



    <!--Faction Rules-->

    <string name="kroot_farstalker_lore"><![CDATA[
Farstalker Kindbands move and fight instinctively,
reacting to developing battlefield conditions with an
inhuman speed of thought.
]]></string>

    <string name="kroot_farstalker_description"><![CDATA[
In the Ready step of each Strategy phase, you
can change the order of up to three friendly
**FARSTALKER KINBAND** operatives that are not
within control range of enemy operatives.\n
\n
Whenever it is your turn to counteract, you can
change the order of one friendly **FARSTALKER
KINBAND** operative that is not within control
range of enemy operatives instead. This still
counts as you counteracting (so activation
alternates back to your opponent afterwards),
but doesn’t count as that friendly operatives
counteraction for this turning point.
]]></string>

    <!--Equipment-->

    <string name="piercing_shot_lore"><![CDATA[
The Kroot make use of many forms of specially crafted
ammunition. Bullets tipped with hardened alloys can
punch through cover and armour alike.
]]></string>

    <string name="piercing_shot_description"><![CDATA[
Once per turning point, when a friendly
**FARSTALKER KINBAND** operative is performing
the **Shoot** action and you select a Kroot rifle,
Kroot scattergun or dual Kroot pistols (focused),
you can use this rule. If you do, until the end
of that action, that weapon has the Piercing 1
weapon rule. You cannot use the Piercing Shot
and Toxin Shot rule during the same action.
]]></string>

    <string name="toxin_shot_lore"><![CDATA[
Kroot toxin bullets contain reservoirs of venom
extracted from various alien fauna, all of which is
incredibly lethal.
]]></string>

    <string name="toxin_shot_description"><![CDATA[
Once per turning point, when a friendly
**FARSTALKER KINBAND** operative is performing
the **Shoot** action and you select a Kroot rifle,
Kroot scattergun or dual Kroot pistols (focused),
you can use this rule. If you do, until the end of
that action, that weapon has the Lethal 5+ and
Stun weapon rules. You cannot use the Piercing
Shot and Toxin Shot rule during the same action.
]]></string>

    <string name="meat_lore"><![CDATA[
Kroot physiologies are far more resilient than their wiry
frames suggest. The ingestion of raw meat only serves to
bolster their regenerative abilities.
]]></string>

    <string name="meat_description"><![CDATA[
Once per turning point, when a friendly
**FARSTALKER KINBAND** operative (excluding
**HOUND**) is activated, if it is not within control
range of enemy operatives, you can use this rule.
If you do, that friendly operative regains up to
D3+1 lost wounds.
]]></string>

    <string name="trophy_lore"><![CDATA[
Kroot Farstalkers seek to cut down the most powerful
of foes. They will aggressively pursue any enemy they
judge worthy and harvest trophies from the corpse.
]]></string>

    <string name="trophy_description"><![CDATA[
Once per battle, during a friendly **FARSTALKER KINBAND** operatives activation (excluding
**HOUND**), before or after it performs an action, if
it is not within control range of enemy operatives,
you can use this rule. If you do, add 1 to that
friendly operatives APL stat until the end of its activation.
]]></string>



    <!--Ploys-->
    <!--Strategy ploys-->
    <string name="cut_thoats_lore"><![CDATA[
Kroot warriors are lethal melee combatants. Their
bladed weapons are capable of tearing through exposed
flesh with ease.
]]></string>

    <string name="cut_thoats_description"><![CDATA[
Add 1 to the Atk stat of friendly **FARSTALKER KINBAND** operatives melee weapons (to a
maximum of 5).
]]></string>

    <string name="rogue_lore"><![CDATA[
Kroot Farstalkers are naturally gifted hunters, using
cover and shadow to their advantage as they close in upon their prey.
]]></string>

    <string name="rogue_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever an operative is shooting a friendly
**FARSTALKER KINBAND** operative:\n
\n
• Ignore the Saturate weapon rule.\n
\n
• If you can retain any cover saves, you can retain one additional cover save, or you can
retain one cover save as a critical success instead. This is not cumulative with improved
cover saves from Vantage terrain.
]]></string>

    <string name="kroot_prey_lore"><![CDATA[
When a Kroot Farstalker has selected their target, the
hunters focus is directed fully towards bringing down
their chosen prey.
]]></string>

    <string name="kroot_prey_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever a friendly **FARSTALKER KINBAND**
operative is shooting during an activation in which
it has not performed the **Charge, Fall Back** or
**Reposition** action, its ranged weapons have the
Balanced and Severe weapon rules; if the weapon
already has the Balanced weapon rule, it has the
Ceaseless and Severe weapon rules instead. Note
that operative is not restricted from performing
those actions after shooting.
]]></string>

    <string name="bound_lore"><![CDATA[
The long, muscular legs of the Kroot allow them to cover
great distances in a single, bounding leap
]]></string>

    <string name="bound_description"><![CDATA[
During each friendly **FARSTALKER KINBAND**
operatives activation, you can ignore the first
vertical distance of 2\" they move during one climb up.
]]></string>



    <!--Firefight ploys-->
    <string name="savage_ambush_lore"><![CDATA[
Kroot Farstalkers are ambush predators, relying upon
stealth, speed and bursts of savage violence to take
down their enemies.
]]></string>

    <string name="savage_ambush_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy during the **Fight** action
when a ready friendly **FARSTALKER KINBAND**
operative that has Light or Heavy terrain within its
control range is selected to fight against. In the
Resolve Attack Dice step of that sequence, you
resolve the first attack dice (i.e. defender instead of attacker).
]]></string>

    <string name="slip_away_lore"><![CDATA[
Lithe and agile, the Kroot melt away from a fight using
the same speed with which they strike.
]]></string>

    <string name="slip_away_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy during a friendly
**FARSTALKER KINBAND** operatives activation,
before or after it performs an action. During that
activation, that operative can perform the **Fall Back** action for 1 less AP.
]]></string>

    <string name="poach_lore"><![CDATA[
Farstalker Kindbands avoid protracted fights, using their
speed and dexterity to advance upon and seize their
objectives as swiftly as possible.
]]></string>

    <string name="poach_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy during a friendly
**FARSTALKER KINBAND** operatives activation.
Until the end of that activation, that operative
does not have to control a marker to perform the
**Pick Up Marker** or mission actions that usually
require this (this takes precedence over that
actions conditions – it only needs to contest
the marker).
]]></string>

    <string name="vengeance_kinband_lore"><![CDATA[
Farstalker Kinbands are bonded by blood. The death of
an ally awakes within the survivors a vengeful fury.
]]></string>

    <string name="vengeance_kinband_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy when a friendly **FARSTALKER KINBAND** operative is
incapacitated by an enemy operative. Until the
end of the battle, whenever another friendly
**FARSTALKER KINBAND** operative is shooting
against, fighting against or retaliating against that
enemy operative, that other friendly operatives
weapons have the Relentless weapon rule. You
cannot use this ploy again during the battle until
that enemy operative is incapacitated.
]]></string>

</resources>