<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>


    <!--Wolf-->

    <string name="lupine_guile_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="lupine_guile_description"><![CDATA[
Once per battle, after rolling off to decide initiative,
if this operative is in the killzone, you can re-roll your dice.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="grizzled_veteran_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="grizzled_veteran_description"><![CDATA[
The first time this operative would be
incapacitated during the battle, it is not incapacitated, has 1
wound remaining and cannot be incapacitated for the remainder
of the action. All remaining attack dice are discarded (including
yours if this operative is fighting or retaliating). You cannot use
the Counterattack firefight ploy or inflict damage as a result of
the Savage Fighters strategy ploy at the end of that action.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="spiritual_chirurgy_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="spiritual_chirurgy_description"><![CDATA[
You can ignore any changes to the stats of
friendly **WOLF SCOUT** operatives (excluding **FENRISIAN
WOLF**) from being injured (including their weapons stats).
Friendly **WOLF SCOUT** operatives (excluding **FENRISIAN
WOLF**) are not affected by enemy operatives Shock and Stun
weapon rules and you can ignore any changes to their APL stat.
Note that friendly operatives have these rules if you select this
operative for the battle (even if it is incapacitated later).
    ]]></string>

    <string name="healing_balms_usage"><![CDATA[

        1AP

    ]]></string>

    <string name="healing_balms_description"><![CDATA[
Select one friendly **WOLF SCOUT** operative within this
operatives control range to regain up to D3+3 lost wounds.\n\n
This operative cannot perform this action while within control
range of an enemy operative.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="storm_eilede_execution_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="storm_eilede_execution_description"><![CDATA[
 Whenever this operative is within your **STORM:**\n
 • It can perform the **Guard** action regardless of the killzone (see close quarters rules, Kill Team Core Book).\n
• It can perform the **Guard** action while it has a **Conceal** order, but if it does, it cannot perform more than one **Shoot** action for the
rest of the turning point (i.e. it cannot Shoot both during the interruption and during counteract).
    ]]></string>

    <string name="hunter_sense_usage"><![CDATA[
        1AP
    ]]></string>

    <string name="hunter_sense_description"><![CDATA[
Select one of the following rules for all profiles of this
operatives instigator bolt carbine to have until the start of its
next activation:\n
• Severe.\n
• Saturate, and whenever this operative is shooting with that
weapon, enemy operatives cannot be obscured.\n\n
This operative cannot perform this action while within control
range of an enemy operative.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="tempest_fury_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="tempest_fury_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever this operative is within your **STORM:**\n
• All profiles of its plasma gun have the Punishing weapon rule.\n
• Its plasma gun (supercharge) does not have the Hot weapon rule.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="fierce_temperament_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="fierce_temperament_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever this operative is within your
**STORM**, its weapons have the Severe weapon rule.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="cast_the_runes_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="cast_the_runes_description"><![CDATA[
After selecting this operative, before the battle, roll three D6 and put them to one side. For each
result of 1-4, you can use the Command Re-roll firefight ploy for OCP once during the turning point
that matches the result. For each result of 5-6, you gain 1CP. For example, if you roll 2, 2 and 5,
you gain 1CP and twice during the second turning point you can use Command Re-roll for 0CP.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="call_the_storm_usage"><![CDATA[

        1AP

    ]]></string>

    <string name="call_the_storm_description"><![CDATA[
**PSYCHIC**. Remove your Storm marker from the killzone (if
any), then place it in the killzone.\n
PSYCHIC. Alternatively, instead of resolving the above
effect, select one friendly **WOLF SCOUT** operative.
Until the start of this operatives next activation, until
it is incapacitated or until it performs this action again
(whichever comes first), whenever that friendly operative
is within your STORM and more than 3\" from the active
operative, it is obscured.\n\n
This operative cannot perform this action while within control
range of an enemy operative.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="wolf_haywire_mine_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wolf_haywire_mine_description"><![CDATA[
This operative is carrying your Haywire Mine marker. It can perform the **Pick Up Marker** action on
that marker, but that marker cannot be placed within another operatives control range (if this
operative is incapacitated while carrying that marker and that marker cannot be placed, it is removed
with this operative).
    ]]></string>

    <string name="wolf_proximity_mine_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wolf_proximity_mine_description"><![CDATA[
The first time your Haywire Mine marker is
within another operative’s control range, remove that marker,
subtract 1 from that operatives APL stat until the end of its
next activation, and inflict 2D3+3 damage on it (or D3+6 if that
marker is within 6" horizontally of your Storm marker); if it is not
incapacitated, end its action (if any), even if that actions effects
are not fulfilled. If it cannot be placed, move it the minimum
amount to do so. Note that this operative is ignored for these
effects (i.e. it cannot set it off or take damage from that marker).
    ]]></string>

    <string name="instinctive_predato_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="instinctive_predato_description"><![CDATA[
This operative cannot perform any actions
other than **Charge, Dash, Fall Back, Fight, Guard** and
**Reposition**. It cannot use any weapons that are not on its
datacard. This operative can perform the **Charge** action while it
has a Conceal order.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="pounce_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="pounce_description"><![CDATA[
Once per battle **STRATEGIC GAMBIT**. If this
operatives APL stat is 2 or more, this operative can perform a
free **Charge, Fall Back** or **Reposition** action. If it does, until
the end of its next activation, subtract 1 from its APL stat and it
cannot perform any of the aforementioned actions.
    ]]></string>

    <!--Faction Rules-->

    <string name="elemental_storm_lore"><![CDATA[
It is said by some battle-brothers that their Chapters
Wolf Scouts take the storm with them. In many cases,
these tempestuous upheavals truly are supernatural,
called into being by accompanying Rune Priest Skjalds.
At other times, Wolf Scouts skilfully time their hunts to
coincide with local atmospheric phenomena or instigate
them with arcane technologies. Wolf Scouts can operate
for extended periods hidden by such storms; using the
cover to mask their movements and confuse the senses
of their prey, their enemies feel they are fighting the
very elements themselves.
]]></string>

    <string name="elemental_storm_description"><![CDATA[
**STRATEGIC GAMBIT**. Remove your Storm marker
from the killzone (if any), then place it in the
killzone. Whenever an operative is within 6\"
horizontally of your Storm marker, it is within
your **STORM**.\n
\n
Each friendly **WOLF SCOUT** operative can
perform the **Charge** action while it has a Conceal
order if it starts and/or ends that action within
your **STORM**.
]]></string>

    <string name="hunting_astartes_lore"><![CDATA[
Wolf Scouts are experienced Space Marines who
are utterly lethal on the hunt. These genetically
modified superhumans are merciless warriors capable
of exploiting strange climatic events to conceal
their approach.
]]></string>

    <string name="hunting_astartes_description"><![CDATA[
During each friendly **WOLF SCOUT** operatives
activation, it can perform either two **Shoot** actions
or two **Fight** actions. If it is two **Shoot** actions:\n
\n
• 1 additional AP must be spent for the second action if both actions are using a plasma gun or
plasma pistol.\n
• You cannot select two PSYCHIC ranged weapons.\n
\n
Each friendly **WOLF SCOUT** operative can
counteract regardless of its order. Whenever
it does so within your **STORM**, you can change
its order first, or change its order instead of
performing an action (for the latter, still treat it as
having counteracted this turning point).
]]></string>



    <!--Equipment-->

    <string name="frost_weapons_lore"><![CDATA[
These blisteringly cold weapons are crafted by a master
Iron Priest and boast lethal edges. Some incorporate
ice kraken fangs while others are shards of energised
diamond, appearing as if forged from purest ice.
]]></string>

    <string name="frost_weapons_description"><![CDATA[
Friendly **WOLF SCOUT** operatives combat
blades have the Lethal 5+ weapon rule, and one
friendly **WOLF SCOUT PACK LEADER** operatives
power weapon has the Lethal 4+ weapon rule
(if any).
]]></string>

    <string name="runic_charms_lore"><![CDATA[
Many pieces of a warriors wargear are artfully inscribed
with runes, but only the enigmatic Rune Priests know
the secrets of etching these more potent charms, which
the Space Wolves believe can ward their very souls.
]]></string>

    <string name="runic_charms_description"><![CDATA[
Once per turning point, when an operative is
shooting a friendly **WOLF SCOUT** operative
(excluding **FENRISIAN WOLF**), at the start of the
Roll Defence Dice step, you can use this rule. If
you do, worsen the x of the Piercing weapon rule
by 1 (if any) until the end of that sequence. Note
that Piercing 1 would therefore be ignored.
]]></string>

    <string name="wolfteeth_necklaces_lore"><![CDATA[
The right to wear one of these fetishes may be
earned in the contests of might held in the Chapters
fortress monastery: the Fang. They recognise the
bearers martial skill, and their capacity to draw upon
great reserves of genetically augmented strength
and perseverance.
]]></string>

    <string name="wolfteeth_necklaces_description"><![CDATA[
Once per turning point, when a friendly **WOLF
SCOUT** operative (excluding **FENRISIAN WOLF**)
is shooting, fighting or retaliating, if you roll two or
more fails, you can discard one of them to retain
another as a normal success instead.
]]></string>

    <string name="talismanic_trophies_lore"><![CDATA[
Thick pelts, skulls and tails adorn these sons of Russ.
These trophies – taken from huge lupine beasts they
have tracked and killed on Fenris – are seen as potent
tokens of luck and protection against malign attacks.
]]></string>

    <string name="talismanic_trophies_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever a friendly **WOLF SCOUT** operative
(excluding **FENRISIAN WOLF**) is fighting or
retaliating, in the Resolve Attack Dice step, you
can subtract 1 from the damage inflicted on it
from one success.
]]></string>



    <!--Ploys-->
    <!--Strategy ploys-->
    <string name="cloaked_storm_lore"><![CDATA[
Wolf Scouts are expert in using the uncanny tempests
around them to their advantage, ensuring their
desperate prey rarely get a clean shot.
]]></string>

    <string name="cloaked_storm_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever an operative is shooting a friendly
**WOLF SCOUT** operative that is within your
**STORM**, you can re-roll one of your defence dice.
]]></string>

    <string name="tempestuous_wrath_lore"><![CDATA[
When roused, the elemental fury of Wolf Scouts is
as ferocious as that of Fenris winter storms or the
crackling lightning of its Season of Fire.
]]></string>

    <string name="tempestuous_wrath_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever a friendly **WOLF SCOUT** operative is
fighting or retaliating, if it is within your **STORM**
or was within your **STORM** at the start of the
activation, its melee weapons have the Balanced
weapon rule.
]]></string>

    <string name="storm_bite_lore"><![CDATA[
Subjected to numbing temperatures, flying debris or the
empyric lash of a Rune Priest Skjald, the Wolf Scouts
enemies struggle to focus their wrath and skill.
]]></string>

    <string name="storm_bite_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever a friendly **WOLF SCOUT** operative is
fighting against an enemy operative that is within
your **STORM**, subtract 1 from the Atk stat of that
enemy operatives melee weapons (to a minimum
of 3).
]]></string>

    <string name="savage_fighters_lore"><![CDATA[
Once their prey have been cornered, the Wolf Scouts
savagely sustain the pressure, ensuring no opportunity
is missed to weaken their quarry.
]]></string>

    <string name="savage_fighters_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever a friendly **WOLF SCOUT** operative
finishes retaliating, if it was not incapacitated, you
can inflict D3+1 damage on the enemy operative
in that sequence.
]]></string>



    <!--Firefight ploys-->
    <string name="acute_senses_lore"><![CDATA[
The heightened acuity of the sons of Russ coupled with
the keen hunters instincts of an experienced Wolf Scout
enable these operatives to pick out their prey no matter
where they hide.
]]></string>

    <string name="acute_senses_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy when a friendly **WOLF
SCOUT** operative performs the **Shoot** action
and you are selecting a valid target. Until the end
of that action, that friendly operatives ranged
weapons have the Range 6\" and Seek Light
weapon rules and enemy operatives cannot
be obscured.
]]></string>

    <string name="wolf_counterattack_lore"><![CDATA[
The greatest hunters know never to waste the chance
to make an unexpected lunge, their prey at its most
vulnerable just as they strike.
]]></string>

    <string name="wolf_counterattack_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy at the end of an enemy
operatives activation, or after an enemy
operative performs the **Fight** action. One friendly
**WOLF SCOUT** operative can immediately
perform a free **Fight** action, but you cannot select
any other enemy operative to fight against during
that action.
]]></string>

    <string name="touched_by_lokyar_lore"><![CDATA[
Independence of spirit is exceptionally strong amongst
Wolf Scouts. Enemies who believe them vulnerably
isolated soon regret tackling these vicious survivalists
]]></string>

    <string name="touched_by_lokyar_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy after rolling your attack dice
for a friendly **WOLF SCOUT** operative (excluding
**FENRISIAN WOLF**), if it is fighting more than 5\"
from other friendly operatives. You can re-roll any
of your attack dice.
]]></string>

    <string name="wolf_trans_lore"><![CDATA[
The genetically modified physiology of the Space
Wolves is capable of resisting wounds that would kill a
lesser being.
]]></string>

    <string name="wolf_trans_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy when an operative is
shooting a friendly **WOLF SCOUT** operative
(excluding **FENRISIAN WOLF**), in the Roll Defence
Dice step. You can retain one of your normal
successes as a critical success instead.
]]></string>

</resources>