<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <!--Celestine-->

    <string name="celestian_shield_usage"><![CDATA[

        Special Weapon Rule

]]></string>

    <string name="celestian_shield_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever this operative is fighting or retaliating with this weapon profile, each of your blocks can be allocated to block two
unresolved successes (instead of one).
]]></string>


    <string name="holy_defender_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive/ Once per turn

]]></string>

    <string name="holy_defender_description"><![CDATA[
Once per turning point, when a friendly
**CELESTIAN INSIDIANT** operative visible to and within 2\"
of this operative is selected as the valid target of a **Shoot** action
or to fight against during the **Fight** action, you can use this rule.
If you do, this operative becomes the valid target or is fought
against (as appropriate) instead (even if it wouldnt normally
be valid for this). If its the **Fight** action, treat this operative
as being within the fighting operatives control range for the
duration of that action. If its the **Shoot** action, this operative is
only in cover or obscured if the original target was.\n
\n
This rule has no effect if its the **Shoot** action and the ranged
weapon has the Blast or Torrent weapon rule.
]]></string>

    <string name="holy_example_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive/ Free firefight ploy

]]></string>

    <string name="holy_example_description"><![CDATA[
Once per turning point, if this operative is **INSPIRING**, you can use a firefight ploy for 0CP if this is the specified
**CELESTIAN INSIDIANT** operative (including Command Re-roll if the attack or defence dice was rolled for this operative).

]]></string>

    <string name="spiritual_mentor_usage"><![CDATA[

        1AP

]]></string>

    <string name="spiritual_mentor_description"><![CDATA[
**SUPPORT.** Select one friendly **CELESTIAN
INSIDIANT** operative visible to and within 6\" of this
operative. That operative becomes **INSPIRING**.\n\n

This operative cannot perform this action while within
control range of an enemy operative, or more than once per
turning point.
]]></string>




    <string name="virge_admonition_icon_bearer_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
]]></string>

    <string name="virge_admonition_icon_bearer_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever determining control of a marker, treat this operatives APL stat as 1 higher. Note this
isnt a change to its APL stat, so any changes are cumulative
with this

]]></string>



    <string name="null_field_usage"><![CDATA[
    Passive
]]></string>

    <string name="null_field_description"><![CDATA[
This operative starts the battle with a null range
of 1\". Whenever an enemy operative is within null range of
this operative, subtract 2\" from the Move stat of that enemy
operative and worsen the Hit stat of its weapons by 1 (this isnt
cumulative with being injured).
    ]]></string>



    <string name="nullifyin_ritual_usage"><![CDATA[

        1AP

    ]]></string>

    <string name="nullifyin_ritual_description"><![CDATA[
Add 1 to this operatives null range (to a maximum of 5\").
Nullification tokens in the marker/token guide are numbered,
so use the numbered token equal to this operatives
null range.\n\n

This operative cannot perform this action while within
control range of an enemy operative, or more than once per
turning point.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="inspirational_pyre_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="inspirational_pyre_description"><![CDATA[
Once per turning point, when this Operative
inflicts damage on an enemy operative with either profile of its
hand flamer but doesnt incapacitate it, you can use this rule. If
you do, you can select one friendly **CELESTIAN INSIDIANT**
Operative within 6\" of this operative to become **INSPIRING**.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="torrent0_usage"><![CDATA[

        Special Weapon Rule

    ]]></string>

    <string name="torrent0_description"><![CDATA[
Torrent 0\" means you cannot select secondary
targets, but this weapon still has the Torrent weapon rule for all
other rules purposes, e.g. the Condensed Stronghold rule (see
Killzone: Volkus, Kill Team Core Book).
    ]]></string>

    <string name="accusing_exorcist_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="accusing_exorcist_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever this operative is **INSPIRING**, the Suspect & Eliminate strategy ploy costs you 0CP if the enemy
operative or marker you select is visible to or within 6\" of this operative.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="speak_of_her_deeds_usage"><![CDATA[

        1AP

    ]]></string>

    <string name="speak_of_her_deeds_description"><![CDATA[
**SUPPORT.** Select an **INSPIRING** friendly **CELESTIAN
INSIDIANT** operative visible to and within 6\" of this
operative. That operative is no longer **INSPIRING**. Then,
select another friendly **CELESTIAN INSIDIANT**
operative visible to and within 6\" of this operative. Resolve
one **BENEDICTION** from the Martyrdom faction rule on
that operative (excluding Exigence).
    ]]></string>

    <string name="zealous_ultimatum_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive / Strategic Gambit / Once per battle

    ]]></string>

    <string name="zealous_ultimatum_description"><![CDATA[
Once per battle **STRATEGIC GAMBIT.** Select one enemy operative within 8\" of this operative and issue
an ultimatum to it. Your opponent must accept or decline that ultimatum (if its a non-player operative, roll one D6: on a 4+, the
ultimatum is accepted, otherwise its declined).\n
\n
If the ultimatum is accepted, whenever this operative is fighting against or retaliating against that enemy operative, add 1 to the
Atk stat of this operatives blessed broadsword. The first time this operative incapacitates that enemy operative while fighting or
retaliating during the battle, add 1 to the Atk stat of this operatives blessed broadsword until the end of the battle. In either case, this
is to a maximum of 5.\n
\n
If the ultimatum is declined, whenever that enemy operative is fighting against or retaliating against a friendly **CELESTIAN
INSIDIANT** operative, subtract 1 from the Atk stat of that enemy operatives weapons.
    ]]></string>


    <string name="celestian_blade_stance_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="celestian_blade_stance_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever this operative is fighting or retaliating,
you can resolve one of your successes before the normal order.
If you do, that success must be used to block.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="simulacrum_nullificatus_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="simulacrum_nullificatus_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever determining control of a marker, treat the total APL stat of enemy operatives
that contest it as 1 lower if at least one of those enemy
operatives is within 3\n" of this operative. Note this isnt a change
to the APL stat, so any changes are cumulative with this.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="devotion_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="devotion_description"><![CDATA[
At the end of each of this operatives activations,
if its **INSPIRING** and it controls an objective marker or
one of your mission markers, one friendly **CELESTIAN
INSIDIANT** operative this operative is visible to and within 6\"
of becomes **INSPIRING**.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="inspired_strike_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="inspired_strike_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever this operative is **INSPIRING**, add 1 to the Critical Dmg stat of weapons on its datacard.
    ]]></string>

    <!--Faction Rules-->

    <string name="martyrdoom_lore"><![CDATA[
Vaunted veterans of the Orders Militant, Celestian
Insidiants hunt witches with extreme prejudice. Those
struck down in the course of their duties become
martyrs, their deaths only serving to harden the resolve
of their surviving sisters.
]]></string>

    <string name="martyrdoom_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever an **INSPIRING** friendly **CELESTIAN
INSIDIANT** operative is incapacitated, before
its removed from the killzone, select one other
friendly **CELESTIAN INSIDIANT** operative that
operative is visible to or within 6" of.

Then, that selected operative gains one
**BENEDICTION** (incapacitated operatives cannot
be selected for a **BENEDICTION**).\n

BENEDICTION   //  EFFECT
\n
Ardour        //    Until the end of the battle, add 1 to that Operatives APL stat, you cant do this with your SUPERIOR
\n
Wrath         //    Until the end of the battle, weapons of that Operative have the Ceaseless rule.
\n
Restoration   //    That Operative regains up to D3+2 lost Wounds.
\n
Exigence      //    That Operative can perform a free Charge or Dash action (cannot move more than 3\"), but it must end that move closer to that incapacitated INSPIRING Operative.
]]></string>


    <string name="weapons_of_the_witch_hunters_lore"><![CDATA[
Celestian Insidiants bear all manner of esoteric
weapons, armour and equipment intended to shield
them from sorcery and impede the ability of their quarry
to channel malefic power.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="weapons_of_the_witch_hunters_description"><![CDATA[
PSYCHIC ranged weapons cannot inflict damage
on friendly CELESTIAN INSIDIANT operatives.
For the effects of PSYCHIC actions, friendly
CELESTIAN INSIDIANT operatives cannot be
selected and are never treated as being within
those actions required distances. Whenever an
operative is within 3\" of a friendly CELESTIAN
INSIDIANT operative:\n\n

• That operative cannot perform PSYCHIC actions or use PSYCHIC additional rules.
• That operative cannot use PSYCHIC ranged weapons.
• PSYCHIC melee weapons have no weapon rules and cannot have Dmg stats higher than 3/4.\n
\n
Some weapons in this teams rules have the Anti-PSYKER weapon rule below.\n

*Anti-PSYKER: Whenever this weapon is being used against an operative that has the PSYKER
keyword, it has the Lethal 5+ weapon rule.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="inspiration_lore"><![CDATA[
Veteran Celestians of the Orders Militant lead by
example, inspiring their sisters by throwing themselves
into the heaviest fighting against the deadliest
of enemies.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="inspiration_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever a friendly CELESTIAN INSIDIANT operative:\n
\n
• Incapacitates an enemy operative that has a Wounds stat of 6 or more, that friendly
operative becomes INSPIRING.\n
• Performs the Charge action, before it moves, it becomes INSPIRING.\n
\n
Whenever a friendly CELESTIAN INSIDIANT
operative is INSPIRING, weapons on its datacard
have the Severe weapon rule.
    ]]></string>


    <!--Equipment-->

    <string name="psyk_out_grenades_lore"><![CDATA[
Powerful psyk-out grenades are particularly potent
against psykers.
]]></string>

    <string name="psyk_out_grenades_description"><![CDATA[
This equipment allows you to select two utility
grenades from the utility grenades equipment
(see universal equipment) and they must all be
stun grenades. If you also select that equipment
as normal, you cannot select any stun grenades
(i.e. to give you more than two). Whenever an
operative takes a stun test as a result of a friendly
**CELESTIAN INSIDIANT** operative performing
the **Stun Grenade** action, if the result is a 3+,
also inflict damage on that first operative equal
to the dice result halved (rounding up). If that
first operative has the **PSYKER** keyword, inflict
damage on it equal to the dice result instead.
]]></string>

    <string name="vocifera_mortis_lore"><![CDATA[
Upon the death of its bearer, this device transmits
a sombre requiem across the squad’s vox-channel,
broadcasting the sisters martyrdom.
]]></string>

    <string name="vocifera_mortis_description"><![CDATA[
Once per battle, when an **INSPIRING**
friendly **CELESTIAN INSIDIANT** operative is
incapacitated, you can use this rule. If you do,
for the Martyrdom faction rule, the other friendly
**CELESTIAN INSIDIANT** operative you select
can be one that isn’t visible to or within 6\" of
that operative.
]]></string>

    <string name="saintly_relics_lore"><![CDATA[
The witch hunters carry a variety of devotional esoterica
believed to shield them from harm, enabling them to
continue their holy duties.
]]></string>

    <string name="saintly_relics_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever an attack dice would inflict damage on
a friendly **CELESTIAN INSIDIANT** operative, you
can use this rule. If you do, roll one D6, or two D6
if that operative is **INSPIRING**: if any result is a 6,
ignore the damage inflicted from that attack dice.
You cannot ignore more than one attack dice per
action and two attack dice per battle this way.

]]></string>

    <string name="auto_flagellator_lore"><![CDATA[
The most devout of Celestian Insidiants may bear
beneath their power armour instruments of selfflagellation. At times of great import, these devices
inflict agonising pain upon the body, focusing the mind
and spirit and driving the recipient to inspirational acts
of zealotry.
]]></string>

    <string name="auto_flagellator_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever a friendly **CELESTIAN INSIDIANT**
operative is activated, you can use this rule. If
you do, roll one D6 and inflict damage on that
operative equal to half the result (rounding
up); on a 4+, that operative also becomes
**INSPIRING**. You cannot make more than one
friendly operative **INSPIRING** using this rule per
turning point.
]]></string>



    <!--Ploys-->
    <!--Strategy ploys-->
    <string name="suspect_eliminate_lore"><![CDATA[
Ruthless in their pursuit of the witch, Celestian
Insidiants are swift to condemn those they suspect of
heresy. Protestations of innocence are treated with the
callous disregard they deserve.
]]></string>

    <string name="suspect_eliminate_description"><![CDATA[
Select one enemy operative or marker. If you
select an enemy operative, that operative and
each other enemy operative visible to and within
2\" of it gains one of your Suspicion tokens until
the end of the turning point. If you selected a
marker, each enemy operative contesting that
marker gains one of your Suspicion tokens until
the end of the turning point.\n\n

Whenever a friendly **CELESTIAN INSIDIANT**
operative is shooting against or fighting against
an operative that has one of your Suspicion
tokens, that friendly operatives weapons have
the Punishing weapon rule.
]]></string>

    <string name="wrathful_determination_lore"><![CDATA[
Once the Celestian Insidiants have detected the spoor
of sorcery, they will pursue their targets through hails
of fire.
]]></string>

    <string name="wrathful_determination_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever an operative is shooting a friendly
**CELESTIAN INSIDIANT** operative that has
an **Engage** order, you can re-roll one of your
defence dice.
]]></string>

    <string name="suffering_sacrifice_lore"><![CDATA[
Battlefield veterans all, Celestian Insidiants are inured
to pain. Injuries serve only to focus their martial prowess
and stoke their zealous rage.
]]></string>

    <string name="suffering_sacrifice_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever a wounded friendly **CELESTIAN
INSIDIANT** operative is shooting against, fighting
against or retaliating against an enemy operative,
its weapons have the Balanced weapon rule.
]]></string>

    <string name="holy_resilience_lore"><![CDATA[
Faith is the greatest of the Celestian Insidiants many
weapons. So long as it remains unbroken, they may
shrug off even the most crippling of injuries and remain
in the fight.
]]></string>

    <string name="holy_resilience_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever an **INSPIRING** friendly **CELESTIAN
INSIDIANT** operative is fighting or retaliating,
Normal and Critical Dmg of 4 or more inflicts 1
less damage on that friendly operative.
]]></string>



    <!--Firefight ploys-->
    <string name="glory_to_the_martyrs_lore"><![CDATA[
There is no greater inspiration than the glorious death
of a martyr.
]]></string>

    <string name="glory_to_the_martyrs_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy when a friendly **CELESTIAN
INSIDIANT** operative is incapacitated while
fighting or retaliating. You can strike the enemy
operative in that sequence with one of your
unresolved successes before its removed
from the killzone. If that enemy operative is
incapacitated as a result, that friendly operative
becomes **INSPIRING** before its removed from
the killzone and you can resolve the Martyrdom
faction rule.
]]></string>

    <string name="faith_fury_lore"><![CDATA[
Divine rage empowers these warriors to cleave through
multiple foes.
]]></string>

    <string name="faith_fury_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy when a friendly **CELESTIAN
INSIDIANT** operative is fighting and you strike
the enemy operative in that sequence with a
critical success. After resolving that strike, also
inflict D3 damage on each other enemy operative
visible to and within 2\" of that friendly operative
in an order of your choice (roll separately for
each). Note that the friendly operative would
become **INSPIRING** if any enemy operatives with
a Wounds stat of 6 or more are incapacitated as a
result of this damage.
]]></string>

    <string name="unshakeable_pursuit_lore"><![CDATA[
Neither fatigue nor terrain can keep a Celestian Insidiant
from their quarry.
]]></string>

    <string name="unshakeable_pursuit_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy during a friendly
**CELESTIAN INSIDIANT** operatives activation,
before or after it performs an action. Until the
end of that operatives activation, you can ignore
any changes to its Move stat. If that operative
is **INSPIRING**, add 1\" to its Move stat until the
end of that activation. If that operative becomes
**INSPIRING** by performing the Charge action,
you can use this ploy before it moves to gain the
additional movement (this takes precedence over
stats not changing during an action).
]]></string>

    <string name="fervent_hate_lore"><![CDATA[
The Celestian Insidiants embody the hatred and
paranoia of their creed.
]]></string>

    <string name="fervent_hate_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy after rolling your attack dice
for a friendly **CELESTIAN INSIDIANT** operative, if
its shooting against, fighting against or retaliating
against an enemy operative that doesnt have
the **IMPERIUM** keyword. That friendly operatives
weapons have the Ceaseless weapon rule
until the end of that sequence; if that enemy
operative also has the **CHAOS** and/or **PSYKER**
keyword, that friendly operatives weapons have
the Relentless weapon rule until the end of that
sequence instead.
]]></string>

</resources>