<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>


    <!--Tempestus-->

    <string name="tempestus_veteran_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="tempestus_veteran_description"><![CDATA[
Once per battle, you can either use a
firefight ploy for 0CP if this is the specified **TEMPESTUS
AQUILON** operative, or the Command Re‑roll firefight ploy
for 0CP if this is the operative the attack or defence dice was
rolled for.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="aquilon_command_usage"><![CDATA[
        1AP
    ]]></string>

    <string name="aquilon_command_description"><![CDATA[
**SUPPORT**. Select one other friendly **TEMPESTUS
AQUILON** operative (excluding **SERVO‑SENTRY**)
visible to and within 6\" of this operative. Until the end of that
operatives next activation, add 1 to its APL stat.\n\n

This operative cannot perform this action while within control range of an enemy operative.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="tempestus_grenadier_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="tempestus_grenadier_description"><![CDATA[
This operative can use frag, krak, smoke and stun
grenades (see universal equipment). Doing so does not count
towards any limited uses you have (i.e. if you also select those
grenades from equipment for other operatives). Whenever this
operative is using a frag or krak grenade, improve the Hit stat of
that weapon by 1.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="tempestus_salvo_usage"><![CDATA[
        Special Weapon Rule
    ]]></string>

    <string name="tempestus_salvo_description"><![CDATA[
Select up to two different
valid targets that are not within control
range of friendly operatives. **Shoot**
with this weapon against both of them
in an order of your choice (roll each
sequence separately).
    ]]></string>

    <string name="gunfight_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="gunfight_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever an enemy operative within 8\" of this operative shoots this
operative, keep track of each attack dice that is discarded as a fail. After the action,
before incapacitated operatives are removed (including this one, if relevant), this
operative can perform a free *Shoot* action (you can change its order to **Engage** to do
so), but it can only target that enemy operative with its hot‑shot laspistols (focused),
and you only roll a number of attack dice equal to the opponents discarded attack dice
plus one (to a maximum of four).
    ]]></string>

    <string name="sniper_vantage_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="sniper_vantage_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever this operative is on Vantage terrain
and is shooting an operative that has an Engage order and is at
least 2\" lower than it, all profiles of its hot‑shot long‑las have the
Severe weapon rule.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="knife_fighter_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="knife_fighter_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever this operative is fighting, after
resolving your first attack dice during that sequence, you can
immediately resolve another (before your opponent).
    ]]></string>

    <string name="dynamic_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="dynamic_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever this operative performs the **Shoot** or
**Fight** action, it can immediately perform a free **Dash** action
afterwards. It can do so even if it is performed the **Charge**
action during this activation, but can only use any remaining
move distance it had from that **Charge** action (to a maximum
of 3\").
    ]]></string>

    <string name="tempestus_machine_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="tempestus_machine_description"><![CDATA[
This operative cannot perform any actions other
than **Dash, Fall Back, Reposition** and **Shoot**. It cannot
retaliate, assist in a fight or use any weapons that are not on
its datacard.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="turret_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="turret_description"><![CDATA[
This operative can perform two **Shoot** actions during
its activation.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="rapid_insertion_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="rapid_insertion_description"><![CDATA[
**STRATEGIC GAMBIT** in the first turning
point. Each friendly **TEMPESTUS AQUILON TROOPER**
operative wholly within your drop zone can immediately perform
a free **Reposition** action, but must end that move wholly within
3\" of your drop zone
    ]]></string>

    <string name="swift_landing_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="swift_landing_description"><![CDATA[
When this operative lands, you can set it up
within 4\" horizontally of one of your Drop markers, taking
precedence over the normal distance requirement.
    ]]></string>

    <!--Faction Rules-->

    <string name="drop_insertion_lore"><![CDATA[
Aquilons are trained since childhood for expertise, with Fornite strategies they drop into the battlefield
ready to wipe the enemies of the empire.
]]></string>

    <string name="drop_insertion_description"><![CDATA[
When setting up a **TEMPESTUS AQUILON** kill
team before the battle, the first third of your
kill team must be set up as normal. Each third
thereafter can be set up above: place them to
one side instead of in the killzone. For each third
that is set up above, you must set up the whole
third in this way (not some of them), then place
one of your Drop markers wholly within your
drop zone.\n
\n
As a **STRATEGIC GAMBIT** in the first and second
turning point, you can move your Drop markers
up to 4\" horizontally. In a killzone that uses the
close quarters rules (e.g. Killzone: Tomb World),
this can be measured and moved through
Wall terrain.\n
\n
In the Firefight phase, friendly **TEMPESTUS
AQUILON** operatives set up above are activated
as normal. When you do, you can either expend
or land that operative. If it lands, set it up in the
killzone in a location it can be placed as follows
(it is no longer set up above):\n
\n
• Within 3\" horizontally of one of your Drop markers, or wholly within your drop zone.\n
• Not within control range of enemy operatives
(unless you’re setting up a PRECURSOR operative, which can be set up within control
range of an enemy operative).\n
• With no part of its base underneath Vantage terrain.\n
• With an order of your choice.\n
\n
The operative is treated as performing the
**Reposition** action (spend the AP accordingly),
then continue its activation as normal. It is
obscured until the end of the next activation
or the end of the turning point (whichever
comes first).\n
\n
Less than half of your operatives can be set up
above by the end of the first turning point. In
other words, by the end of the first turning point,
more than half of your operatives must have been
set up in the killzone during the battle.\n
\n
When readying your operatives during the second
and third turning points, remove one of your
Drop markers. This means operatives still set up
above are incapacitated at the end of the second
turning point.
]]></string>

    <string name="grav_chute_lore"><![CDATA[
Grav‑chutes employ gravitic repulsion fields to allow
their wearers to drop at a swift but measured pace and
land safely, no matter from what height they fall.
]]></string>

    <string name="grav_chute_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever a friendly **TEMPESTUS AQUILON**
operative is dropping, ignore the vertical distance.
]]></string>



    <!--Equipment-->

    <string name="tempestus_daggers_lore"><![CDATA[
Awarded to each warrior of the Militarum Tempestus
upon their induction to the ranks, these weapons double
as a symbol of regimental pride.
]]></string>

    <string name="tempestus_daggers_description"><![CDATA[
Friendly **TEMPESTUS AQUILON **operatives
(excluding **SERVO‑SENTRY**) have the following
melee weapon:
]]></string>

    <string name="aquilon_combat_stimms_lore"><![CDATA[
The use of Munitorum‑approved combat stimulants is
standard practice amongst the Tempestus Aquilons,
who may have to remain alert and fighting for days at
a time.
]]></string>

    <string name="aquilon_combat_stimms_description"><![CDATA[
You can ignore any changes to the Move stat of
friendly **TEMPESTUS AQUILON** operatives from
being injured.
]]></string>

    <string name="drop_agury_lore"><![CDATA[
Prior to the commencement of hostilities, this region
has been subjected to thorough augur scans by orbiting
warships or hovering servo‑skulls, the resultant
intelligence inloaded to the Tempestors slate monitron.
]]></string>

    <string name="drop_agury_description"><![CDATA[
Once per battle, when a friendly **TEMPESTUS
AQUILON** operative that is set up above is
activated, before expending or landing that
operative, you can move one of your Drop
markers again. However, it cannot be moved
closer to your opponents drop zone.
]]></string>

    <string name="remote_overseer_lore"><![CDATA[
Be it a high‑flying observer aircraft or a specialist team
of lexmechanicae employing tactical augur banks,
monitoring officers provide wider strategic insight as the
firefight rages.
]]></string>

    <string name="remote_overseer_description"><![CDATA[
Once per battle, after rolling off to decide initiative, you can re‑roll your dice.
]]></string>



    <!--Ploys-->
    <!--Strategy ploys-->
    <string name="sudden_offensive_lore"><![CDATA[
Tempestus Aquilons are skilled at dropping swiftly into
combat and catching their enemies unawares.
]]></string>

    <string name="sudden_offensive_description"><![CDATA[
Count the number of friendly **TEMPESTUS
AQUILON** operatives that are not incapacitated,
then halve the result (rounding up) to give
you x. Until the end of their activation, friendly
**TEMPESTUS AQUILON** operatives weapons
have the Balanced weapon rule if they are the
first friendly operatives activated this turning
point equal to x. For example, if you have five
operatives, the first three friendly operatives
activated will benefit.
]]></string>

    <string name="maintain_momentum_lore"><![CDATA[
Once the assault begins, the Aquilons sustain the
pressure, keeping their enemies reeling and off balance
]]></string>

    <string name="maintain_momentum_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever a friendly **TEMPESTUS AQUILON**
operative is shooting against or fighting against a
ready enemy operative, that friendly operatives
weapons have the Severe weapon rule.
]]></string>

    <string name="eye_above_lore"><![CDATA[
Airborne servo‑skulls and spotter aircraft keep the
Aquilons appraised of up‑to‑the‑minute tactical data.
]]></string>

    <string name="eye_above_description"><![CDATA[
Select one enemy operative. That operative and
each other enemy operative within 3\" of it gains
one of your Detected tokens until the end of the
turning point. Whenever an enemy operative that
has one of your Detected tokens:\n
\n
• Is shooting a friendly **TEMPESTUS
**AQUILON operative, you can re‑roll one of
your defence dice.\n
\n
• Is fighting or retaliating against a friendly
**TEMPESTUS AQUILON** operative, one of
your blocks can be allocated to block two
unresolved successes (instead of one).
]]></string>

    <string name="drop_secure_lore"><![CDATA[
Priority tactical objectives must be secured to ensure
victory is absolute.
]]></string>

    <string name="drop_secure_description"><![CDATA[
Select one marker.\n
\n
• Until the Ready step of the next Strategy
phase, when determining control of that
marker, treat the total APL stat of friendly
**TEMPESTUS AQUILON** operatives that
contest it as 1 higher if at least one friendly
**TEMPESTUS AQUILON** operative contests
that marker. Note this is not a change to the APL
stat, so any changes are cumulative with this.\n
\n
• Whenever a friendly **TEMPESTUS
AQUILON** operative is within 3\" of that
marker, add 1 to the Atk stat of its melee
weapons (to a maximum of 4).
]]></string>



    <!--Firefight ploys-->
    <string name="hot_drop_lore"><![CDATA[
Aquilons are trained to drop into the thick of fighting,
engaging a surprised enemy as they land.
]]></string>

    <string name="hot_drop_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy after rolling your attack dice
for a friendly **TEMPESTUS AQUILON** operative
that is wholly within your opponents territory, or
either landed or dropped from Vantage terrain at
least 2\" higher than the killzone floor during this
activation. If the target is within 6\" of it, you can
re‑roll any of your attack dice.
]]></string>

    <string name="adjust_coordinates_lore"><![CDATA[
As the firefight flows and develops, so those Aquilons
still descending adjust their trajectories in response.
]]></string>

    <string name="adjust_coordinates_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy when a friendly
**TEMPESTUS AQUILON** operative lands. You
can set it up within 5\" horizontally of one of
your Drop markers, taking precedence over the
normal distance requirement. It cannot perform
the **Dash, Shoot** or **Fight** actions during this
turning point.
]]></string>

    <string name="tempestus_exemplars_lore"><![CDATA[
The training and conditioning of the Tempestus Aquilons
allows them to stay focused on their mission, even
during the most ferocious firefights.
]]></string>

    <string name="tempestus_exemplars_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy during a friendly
**TEMPESTUS AQUILON** operatives activation
(excluding **SERVO‑SENTRY** and any operative
that has an APL stat higher than 2). During that
activation, that operative can perform the **Pick
Up Marker**, **Place Marker** or a mission action for
1 less AP.
]]></string>

    <string name="progena_lore"><![CDATA[
As graduates of the Schola Progenium, these warriors
are not only conditioned to follow their orders with
unquestioning precision, but are also driven by a zealous
dedication to the Imperial Cult that helps them to shrug
off pain and fear.
]]></string>

    <string name="progena_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy when a friendly
**TEMPESTUS AQUILON** operative (excluding
**SERVO‑SENTRY**) is activated. It regains up to 2D3
lost wounds, and during that activation you can
ignore any changes to its APL stat.
]]></string>

</resources>