<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>


    <!--Sanctifiers-->

    <string name="lead_the_procession_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="lead_the_procession_description"><![CDATA[
In each turning point after the first, whenever this operative is an **ORATOR** and performs the **Charge**,
**Fall Back** or **Reposition** action during its activation, you can use this rule before it moves. If you do, determine each other
friendly **SANCTIFIER** operative that is benefitting from the **SERMON** and is visible to this operative (or vice versa). After this
operative ends that action, each of those friendly **SANCTIFIER** operatives can immediately perform a free **Charge, Fall Back**
or **Reposition** action in an order of your choice (choose separately for each), but each cannot move more than 3\" and must end
that move in a location where they are still benefitting from the **SERMON**. If this operative is incapacitated before this rule is fully
resolved, e.g. from the **Guard** actions interruption (see close quarters rules, Kill Team Core Book), do not remove it from the killzone
until this rule has been resolved.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="commanding_declamation_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="commanding_declamation_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever an enemy operative
would perform an action during an activation or counteraction
while visible to and within 6\" of this operative, you can use this
rule. If you do, roll one D6: if the result is higher than that enemy
operatives APL stat:\n
• It cannot perform that action during that activation/
counteraction (the AP spent on it isn’t refunded). If it is a
counteraction, that counteraction ends.\n
• You cannot use this rule again during the battle.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="cherub_usage"><![CDATA[
    Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="cherub_description"><![CDATA[
• Whenever determining control of an objective marker, treat
this operatives APL stat as 1 lower. Note this is not a change
to its APL stat, so any changes are cumulative with this.\n
• Whenever this operative has a **Conceal** order and is in cover,
it cannot be selected as a valid target, taking precedence
over all other rules (e.g. Seek, Vantage terrain) except being
within 2\".\n
• This operative cannot use any weapons that are not on its
datacard, or perform unique actions other than **Incentivise**
    ]]></string>

    <string name="sanctifier_fly_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="sanctifier_fly_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever this operative is performing the **Charge, Fall
Back** or **Reposition** action, it can **FLY**. If it does, do not move
it. Instead, remove it from the killzone and set it back up wholly
within a distance equal to its Move stat horizontally of its original
location (in a killzone that uses the close quarters rules, e.g.
Killzone: Tomb World, this distance cannot be measured over or
through Wall terrain). Note that it gains no additional distance
when performing the Charge action. It must be set up in a
location it can be placed, and unless it is the **Charge** action, it
cannot be set up within control range of an enemy operative.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="incentivise_usage"><![CDATA[
        1AP
    ]]></string>

    <string name="incentivise_description"><![CDATA[
**SUPPORT**. Select one other friendly **SANCTIFIER**
operative (excluding **CONFESSOR, DEATH CULT
ASSASSIN, MIRACULIST** and **ORATOR**) visible to and
within 2\" of this operative. Until the end of that operatives
next activation, add 1 to its APL stat.\n\n
This operative cannot perform this action while within control
range of an enemy operative.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="twin_torrent_usage"><![CDATA[
        Special Weapon Rule
    ]]></string>

    <string name="twin_torrent_description"><![CDATA[
Select up to two different valid targets that
are not within control range of friendly operatives. Shoot with
this weapon against both of them in an order of your choice (roll
each sequence separately). Torrent 0\" means you cannot select
secondary targets, but this weapon still has the Torrent weapon
rule for all other rules purposes, e.g. the Condensed Stronghold
rule (see Killzone: Volkus, Kill Team Core Book).
    ]]></string>

    <string name="sanctification_rack_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="sanctification_rack_description"><![CDATA[
This operative can perform the
**Sanctification Orb** action (see faction equipment). Doing so
in this manner does not count towards the once per turning point
limit (i.e. if you also select that equipment for other operatives)
    ]]></string>

    <string name="sanctifier_blade_stance_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="sanctifier_blade_stance_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever this operative is fighting or retaliating,
you can resolve one of your successes before the normal order. If
you do, that success must be used to block.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="trained_assasin_usage"><![CDATA[

        1AP

    ]]></string>

    <string name="trained_assasin_description"><![CDATA[
Change this operatives order.\n\n
This operative cannot perform this action while within control
range of an enemy operative.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="schola_progenium_disciplinarian_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="schola_progenium_disciplinarian_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever a friendly
**SANCTIFIER** operative is within 6\" of this operative, you can
ignore any changes to that operatives stats from being injured
(including its weapons stats).
    ]]></string>

    <string name="null_skull_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="null_skull_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever an enemy operative is within 4\" of this
operative, that enemy operatives APL stat cannot be added
to (remove all positive APL stat changes it has). If an enemy
operative thats more than 4\" from this operative has a positive
APL stat change and your opponent spends its final AP to move
that operative within 4\" of this operative, this can cause your
opponent to have spent more AP than its APL stat – this is
permitted in this situation.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="merciless_castigation_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="merciless_castigation_description"><![CDATA[
The first time this operative performs the
**Fight** action during each of its activations, if neither it nor the
enemy operative in that sequence is incapacitated, this operative
can immediately perform a free **Fight** action afterwards, but you
cannot select any other enemy operative to fight against during
that action (and only if it is still valid to fight against). This takes
precedence over action restrictions.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="fanatical_retribution_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="fanatical_retribution_description"><![CDATA[
If this operative is incapacitated during
the **Fight** action, you can strike the enemy operative in that
sequence with one of your unresolved successes before this
operative is removed from the killzone.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="wreathed_usage"><![CDATA[

        Special Weapon Rule

    ]]></string>

    <string name="wreathed_description"><![CDATA[
This operative can perform the **Shoot** action with
this weapon while within control range of an enemy operative.
Do not select a valid target. Instead, this operative is always the
primary target, but only shoot against secondary targets and they
cannot be in cover or obscured (in other words, determine Blast
from this operative, but this operative is not affected).
    ]]></string>

    <string name="miracle_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="miracle_description"><![CDATA[
The first time this operative would be incapacitated
during the battle, it is not incapacitated, has 1 wound remaining
and cannot be incapacitated for the remainder of the action.
All remaining attack dice are discarded (including yours if this
operative is fighting or retaliating), then this operative can
immediately perform a free **Dash** or **Fall Back** action (for the
latter, it cannot move more than 3\"), even if it is performed an
action that prevents it from performing those actions.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="holy_relic_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="holy_relic_description"><![CDATA[
If this operative has a holy relic, it is always
benefitting from the **SERMON**.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="spread_the_word_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="spread_the_word_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever this operative
is more than 6\" from other friendly operatives, its weapons have
the Severe weapon rule.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="defend_the_faith_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="defend_the_faith_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever this operative controls an objective marker, it is benefitting from the **SERMON**.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="sanctifier_cult_icon_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="sanctifier_cult_icon_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever determining control of a marker within 4\" of
this operative, treat the total APL stat of friendly
**SANCTIFIER** operatives that contest it as 1 higher if at least
one friendly **SANCTIFIER** operative contests that marker.
Note this is not a change to the APL stat, so any changes are
cumulative with this.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="imperial_cult_devotion_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="imperial_cult_devotion_description"><![CDATA[
Once per turning point, when a ready
friendly **SANCTIFIER** operative is incapacitated while visible
to and within 6\" of this operative, you can use this rule. If you do,
before that operative is removed from the killzone, it can perform
one free action (excluding **Fight**), and you can change its order
to do so. It is then removed from the killzone as normal.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="conversion_field_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="conversion_field_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever an operative more than 6\" from
this operative is shooting a friendly **SANCTIFIER** operative
within 6\" of this operative, improve that friendly operatives Save
stat by 1.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="sanctifier_medikit_usage"><![CDATA[

        1AP

    ]]></string>

    <string name="sanctifier_medikit_description"><![CDATA[
Select one friendly **SANCTIFIER** operative within this
operatives control range to regain up to 2D3 lost wounds.\n\n

This operative cannot perform this action while within control
range of an enemy operative.
    ]]></string>

    <!--Faction Rules-->

    <string name="blaze_lore"><![CDATA[
Only in holy fire can deviance be absolved. With flamer
and burning hands the faithful purge the malignant taint
of heresy.
]]></string>

    <string name="blaze_description"><![CDATA[
Some weapons in this teams rules have the Blaze
weapon rule below.\n
***Blaze**: If you inflict damage with any critical
successes, the operative this weapon is being
used against gains one of your Blaze tokens (if it
does not already have one). Whenever an operative
that has one of your Blaze tokens is activated,
inflict D3 damage on it. Then that operatives
controlling player selects one of the following:\n
\n
• Roll one D6: on a 3+, remove that token.\n
• Subtract 1 from the operative’s APL stat until the end of that activation to remove that token.
]]></string>

    <string name="ministorum_sermon_lore"><![CDATA[
A mighty orator booms out an impassioned sermon.
The fire and brimstone words inflame the zeal of their
followers, enabling them to shrug off wounds and
remain in the fight.
]]></string>

    <string name="ministorum_sermon_description"><![CDATA[
**STRATEGIC GAMBIT**. Select one friendly
**SANCTIFIER** operative. If a friendly **CONFESSOR
operative has not been incapacitated, you must
select it. Until you use this **STRATEGIC GAMBIT**
again during the battle, that operative has the
**ORATOR** keyword. \n
Whenever a friendly **SANCTIFIER** operative is
within 3\" of a friendly ORATOR operative (or 6\"
if the **ORATOR** is a **CONFESSOR**), that friendly
**SANCTIFIER** operative is benefitting from
the **SERMON**.\n
Whenever a friendly **SANCTIFIER** operative
is activated within 3\" of a friendly **ORATOR**
operative (or 6\" if the **ORATOR** is a **CONFESSOR**),
that friendly **SANCTIFIER** operative is benefitting
from the **SERMON** until the end of that activation
(i.e. even if it then moves more than the distance
requirement from the ORATOR operative).\n
Whenever a friendly **SANCTIFIER** operative
is benefitting from the **SERMON**, Normal and
Critical Dmg of 4 or more inflicts 1 less damage
on it.
]]></string>

    <!--Equipment-->


    <string name="sanctification_orbs_lore"><![CDATA[
These spherical devices contain flammable oils. They
shatter, ignite and detonate upon impact with their
target, coating the foe in burning liquid.
]]></string>

    <string name="sanctification_orbs_description"><![CDATA[
Once per turning point, one friendly **SANCTIFIER**
operative (excluding **CHERUB, DEATH CULT
ASSASSIN** and **MIRACULIST**) can perform the
following unique action:
]]></string>

    <string name="sanctification_orb_usage"><![CDATA[
        1AP
]]></string>

    <string name="sanctification_orb_description2"><![CDATA[
Select one enemy operative visible to and
within 6\" of this operative. That operative
and each other enemy operative within 1\"
of it takes a doused test. For an operative to
take a doused test, roll one D6: on a 3+, it
gains one of your Doused tokens.\n
*Whenever a friendly **SANCTIFIER** operative
is shooting an operative that has one of your
Doused tokens with a weapon that has the
Blaze weapon rule, that weapon also has the
Seek weapon rule.\n
*After a friendly **SANCTIFIER** operative uses
a weapon that has the Blaze weapon rule
against an enemy operative that has one
of your Doused tokens, remove that token
(even if the Seek weapon rule was not used).\n\n
This operative cannot perform this
action while within control range of an
enemy operative.
]]></string>


    <string name="sanctifiers_purity_seals_lore"><![CDATA[
Affixed to clothing, armour and wargear by way of wax
seals, these pieces of parchment are inscribed with holy
prayers and blessings.
]]></string>

    <string name="sanctifiers_purity_seals_description"><![CDATA[
Once per turning point, when a friendly
**SANCTIFIER** operative is shooting or fighting,
if you roll two or more fails, you can discard
one of them to retain another as a normal
success instead.
]]></string>

    <string name="ecclesiarchy_texts_lore"><![CDATA[
The orators of the Adeptus Ministorum carry with them
many a fiery prayer and excoriating psalm scribed on
tattered vellum, designed to inspire their allies and
diminish the foe.
]]></string>

    <string name="ecclesiarchy_texts_description"><![CDATA[
In the Ready step of each Strategy phase, roll
3D6: if the result is less than the remaining
wounds of a friendly **ORATOR** operative, you gain
1CP. Note that this is done before the Gambit
step, so if there is not a valid **ORATOR** operative,
you cannot use this rule during that turning point
(e.g. during the first turning point).
]]></string>


    <string name="imperial_cult_symbols_lore"><![CDATA[
Whether carved from stone or wrought in solid gold,
blessed religious symbols bestow upon their bearers
both fortune and favour.
]]></string>

    <string name="imperial_cult_symbols_description"><![CDATA[
Once per turning point, when an operative is
shooting a friendly SANCTIFIER operative that is
benefitting from the **SERMON**, when you collect
your defence dice, you can use this rule. If you
do, change one of the attackers retained critical
successes to a normal success (any weapon rules
they have already resolved are not affected, e.g.
Piercing Crits).
]]></string>



    <!--Ploys-->
    <!--Strategy ploys-->
    <string name="sanctifiers_the_emperor_protects_lore"><![CDATA[
The most dedicated adherents to the Imperial Creed
believe that the Emperor protects. They hurl themselves
into battle, confident that their faith will shield them.
]]></string>

    <string name="sanctifiers_the_emperor_protects_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever an operative is shooting a friendly
**SANCTIFIER** operative that is benefitting from
the **SERMON**, you can re-roll any of your defence
dice results of one result (e.g. results of 2).
]]></string>

    <string name="fervent_brawl_lore"><![CDATA[
With the intolerant diatribes of the priesthood ringing in
their ears, the Sanctifiers fight with a tireless fury.
]]></string>

    <string name="fervent_brawl_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever a friendly **SANCTIFIER** operative
that is benefitting from the **SERMON** is fighting or
retaliating, its melee weapons have the Ceaseless
weapon rule.
]]></string>

    <string name="zealous_persecution_lore"><![CDATA[
The longer that heresy is allowed to persist, the more
indelible the mark it leaves. It must be scoured swiftly
and without mercy.
]]></string>

    <string name="zealous_persecution_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever a friendly **SANCTIFIER** operative is
fighting during an activation in which it performed
the Charge action, its melee weapons have the
Lethal 5+ weapon rule.
]]></string>

    <string name="rally_the_flock_lore"><![CDATA[
An orators voice booms above the thunderous din of
combat, drawing the faithful back into formation
]]></string>

    <string name="rally_the_flock_description"><![CDATA[
Each friendly **SANCTIFIER** operative (excluding
**ORATOR**) that is benefitting from the **SERMON**
can immediately perform a free **Dash** or **Fall
Back** action in an order of your choice (choose
separately for each and, for the latter, it cannot
move more than 3\"). Each that does so must end
that move closer and visible to (or vice versa) a
friendly **ORATOR** operative. You cannot use this
ploy during the first turning point.
]]></string>



    <!--Firefight ploys-->
    <string name="rosarius_lore"><![CDATA[
A sacred symbol of office, the Rosarius contains a
powerful conversion field generator capable of turning
aside incoming blows
]]></string>

    <string name="rosarius_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy when an attack dice
inflicts Normal Dmg on a friendly **SANCTIFIER**
operative. Ignore that inflicted damage.
]]></string>

    <string name="ardent_eradication_lore"><![CDATA[
For those who stand against the Imperial faith there is
only one punishment: death.
]]></string>

    <string name="ardent_eradication_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy after rolling your attack
dice for a friendly **SANCTIFIER** operative, if it is
shooting against or fighting against an enemy
operative that is within 3\" of a friendly **ORATOR**
operative (or 6\" if the **ORATOR** is a **CONFESSOR**).
You can re-roll any of your attack dice.
]]></string>

    <string name="redeemed_through_fire_lore"><![CDATA[
There are few more blessed deaths than fiery
martyrdom. Such a sacrifice stokes smouldering resolve
in the hearts of fellow Sanctifiers.
]]></string>

    <string name="redeemed_through_fire_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy when a friendly
**SANCTIFIER** operative that has a weapon with
the Blaze weapon rule is incapacitated, before it is
removed from the killzone. Each enemy operative
visible to and within 2\" of it gains one of your
Blaze tokens (if it does not already have one).
]]></string>

    <string name="unwavering_devotion_lore"><![CDATA[
Low ranking Sanctifiers will gladly hurl themselves into
the path of bullet or blade if doing so will preserve their
blessed superiors and ensure victory.
]]></string>

    <string name="unwavering_devotion_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy when a friendly
**SANCTIFIER ORATOR** or **SANCTIFIER
MIRACULIST** operative is selected as the valid
target of a **Shoot** action or to fight against
during the **Fight** action. Select one other friendly
**SANCTIFIER** operative (excluding **CONFESSOR,
MIRACULIST** and **ORATOR**) visible to and within
3\" of that first friendly operative to become
the valid target or to be fought against (as
appropriate) instead (even if it would not normally
be valid for this). If it is the **Fight** action, treat
that other operative as being within the fighting
operatives control range for the duration of
that action. If it is the **Shoot** action, that other
operative is only in cover or obscured if the
original target was.\n
This ploy has no effect if it is the **Shoot** action
and the ranged weapon has the Blast or Torrent
weapon rule.
]]></string>

</resources>