<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>


    <!--Kasrkin-->

    <string name="tactical_command_usage"><![CDATA[
        0AP
    ]]></string>

    <string name="tactical_command_description"><![CDATA[
Select one friendly **KASRKIN** operative, then select one
**SKILL AT ARMS** for that operative to have until the Ready
step of the next Strategy phase. This can be in addition to
any **SKILL AT ARMS** it already has, but they cannot be
the same.\n
Alternatively, instead of resolving the above effect, if your
Clearance Sweep marker is in the killzone, you can remove it
and place it again.\n\n
This operative cannot perform this action while within control
range of an enemy operative.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="veteran_leadership_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
    ]]></string>

    <string name="veteran_leadership_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever this operative is in the killzone
and you use the **SKILL AT ARMS STRATEGIC GAMBIT**,
you can select one additional **SKILL AT ARMS**.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="kasrkin_medic_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="kasrkin_medic_description"><![CDATA[
The first time during each turning point that another friendly **KASRKIN** operative would be incapacitated while visible
to and within 3\" of this operative, you can use this rule, providing neither this nor that operative is within control range of an enemy
operative. If you do, that friendly operative isnt incapacitated, has 1 wound remaining and cannot be incapacitated for the remainder
of the action. After that action, that friendly operative can immediately perform a free **Dash** action, but must end that move within
this operatives control range. Subtract 1 from this and that operatives APL stats until the end of their next activations respectively,
and if this rule was used during that friendly operatives activation, that activation ends. You cannot use this rule if this operative is
incapacitated, or if its a **Shoot** action and this operative would be a primary or secondary target.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="kasrkin_medikit_usage"><![CDATA[
        1AP
    ]]></string>

    <string name="kasrkin_medikit_description"><![CDATA[
Select one friendly **KASRKIN** operative within this
operatives control range to regain up to 2D3 lost wounds.
It cannot be an operative that the Medic! rule was used on
during this turning point.\n\n
This operative cannot perform this action while within control range of an enemy operative.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="melta_mine_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="melta_mine_description"><![CDATA[
This operative is carrying your Melta Mine marker. It
can perform the **Pick Up Marker** action on that marker, and
whenever it performs the Place Marker action on that marker,
it can immediately perform a free **Dash** action. That marker
cannot be placed within an enemy operatives control range (if
this operative is incapacitated while carrying that marker and
that marker cannot be placed, its removed with this operative).
    ]]></string>

    <string name="proximity_mine_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="proximity_mine_description"><![CDATA[
The first time your Melta Mine marker is within
another operatives control range, remove that marker and inflict
2D6+3 damage on that operative; if it isnt incapacitated, end
its action (if any), even if that actions effects arent fulfilled. If
it cannot be placed, move it the minimum amount to do so. Note
that this operative is ignored for these effects (i.e. it cannot set it
off or take damage from that marker).
    ]]></string>

    <string name="blast_padding_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="blast_padding_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever an operative is shooting this operative
with a weapon that has the Blast or Torrent weapon rule
(excluding weapons that have a sweeping profile), you can re-roll
one of your defence dice. In addition, this operative isnt affected
by the x\" Devastating x weapon rule (i.e. Devastating with a
distance) unless they are the target during that sequence.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="reconnoitre_killzone_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="reconnoitre_killzone_description"><![CDATA[
 The Relocate strategy ploy costs you 0CP if this operative is the selected friendly **KASRKIN** operative
    ]]></string>

    <string name="kasrkin_auspex_scan_usage"><![CDATA[
        1AP
    ]]></string>

    <string name="kasrkin_auspex_scan_description"><![CDATA[
Until the start of this operatives next activation or until its incapacitated (whichever comes first), whenever an enemy operative
is within 8\" of this operative, that enemy operative is being scanned. Whenever a friendly **KASRKIN** operative is shooting an
enemy operative that is being scanned, that enemy operative cannot be obscured.\n\n
This operative cannot perform this action while within control range of an enemy operative.
    ]]></string>

    <string name="camo_cloak_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="camo_cloak_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever an operative is shooting this operative:\n
• Ignore the Saturate weapon rule.\n
• If you can retain any cover saves, you can retain one additional cover save, or you can retain one cover save as a critical success
instead. This is not cumulative with improved cover saves from Vantage terrain
    ]]></string>

    <string name="kasrkin_adaptive_equipment_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive

    ]]></string>

    <string name="kasrkin_adaptive_equipment_description"><![CDATA[
You can do each of the following once per turning point:\n
• One friendly **KASRKIN TROOPER** operative can perform the Smoke Grenade action.\n
• One friendly **KASRKIN TROOPER** operative can perform the Stun Grenade action.\n
The rules for these actions are found in universal equipment. Performing these actions using this rule does not count towards their
action limits (i.e. if you also select those grenades from equipment).
    ]]></string>

    <string name="battle_comms_usage"><![CDATA[
        1AP
    ]]></string>

    <string name="battle_comms_description"><![CDATA[
Select one other friendly **KASRKIN** operative. Until the end of that operatives next activation, add 1 to its APL stat (to a
maximum of 3 after all APL stat changes have been totalled).\n\n
This operative can perform this action twice during its activation, but cannot perform this action while within control range of an
enemy operative.
    ]]></string>

    <!--Faction Rules-->

    <string name="skill_at_arms_lore"><![CDATA[
The Kasrkin go where they are needed. Battle-hardened,
uncompromising and equipped with the best weapons
available, these elites pursue their objectives
with professionalism, hard-won experience and
rigid determination.
]]></string>

    <string name="skill_at_arms_description"><![CDATA[
**STRATEGIC GAMBIT.** Select a **SKILL AT ARMS** for
friendly **KASRKIN** operatives to have until the
Ready step of the next Strategy phase.
]]></string>

    <string name="light_em_up_lore"><![CDATA[
Establishing overlapping fields of fire as they advance,
the Kasrkin react to any enemy movement with a lethal
volley of fire.
]]></string>

    <string name="light_em_up_description"><![CDATA[
Friendly **KASRKIN** operatives ranged weapons have the Severe weapon rule.
]]></string>

    <string name="strike_fast_lore"><![CDATA[
Kasrkin pride themselves upon their physical fitness
and can cover ground swiftly, even when carrying heavy
combat gear.
]]></string>

    <string name="strike_fast_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever a friendly **KASRKIN** operative is
performing the Reposition action, add 1\" to its
Move stat.
]]></string>

    <string name="ice_in_your_veins_lore"><![CDATA[
All Cadians are subjected to a lifetime of war. Those
chosen to join the ranks of the elite Kasrkin are amongst
the hardiest.
]]></string>

    <string name="ice_in_your_veins_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever a friendly **KASRKIN** operative is
fighting or retaliating, or an operative is shooting
it, the first time an attack dice inflicts Normal
Dmg of 3 or more on this operative during that
sequence, that dice inflicts 1 less damage on it.
]]></string>

    <string name="for_cadia_lore"><![CDATA[
All Kasrkin strive to uphold the honour of their
dead homeworld.
]]></string>

    <string name="for_cadia_description"><![CDATA[
Add 1 to the Atk stat of friendly **KASRKIN**
operatives melee weapons (to a maximum of
4). Whenever a friendly **KASRKIN** operative
is fighting, the first time you strike during that
sequence, inflict 1 additional damage.
]]></string>

    <string name="rapid_fire_lore"><![CDATA[
Ruthlessly drilled and murderously efficient, Kasrkin lay
down hails of high-powered fire against the foe.
]]></string>

    <string name="rapid_fire_description"><![CDATA[
Each friendly **KASRKIN** operative that does not
perform an action in which it moves during
its activation can perform two **Shoot** actions
(excluding Guard) during that activation, but a
bolt pistol, hot-shot lasgun or hot-shot laspistol
must be selected for both of those actions.
]]></string>


    <!--Equipment-->

    <string name="foregrip_lore"><![CDATA[
Fitted under the barrel of the gun, this foregrip helps
stabilise the bearers weapon, improving its handling at
close range.
]]></string>

    <string name="foregrip_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever a friendly **KASRKIN** operative is
shooting an operative within 3\" of it, ranged
weapons on its datacard (excluding weapons
that include pistol in their name, e.g. hot-shot
laspistol, all profiles of a plasma pistol, etc.) have
the Accurate 1 weapon rule.
]]></string>

    <string name="long_range_scope_lore"><![CDATA[
This weapon is fitted with a marksmans scope, enabling great accuracy even at long range.
]]></string>

    <string name="long_range_scope_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever a friendly **KASRKIN** operative is
shooting an operative more than 6\" from it, that
friendly operatives hot-shot weapons have the
Saturate weapon rule.
]]></string>

    <string name="relics_of_cadia_lore"><![CDATA[
Small personal effects remind the Kasrkin of their
homeworld, those they have lost, and that which they
fight for.
]]></string>

    <string name="relics_of_cadia_description"><![CDATA[
Once per turning point, when a friendly
**KASRKIN** operative is shooting, fighting or
retaliating, if you roll two or more fails, you can
discard one of them to retain another as a normal
success instead.
]]></string>

    <string name="kasrkin_combat_daggers_lore"><![CDATA[
When close combat is required, the Kasrkin turn to their
combat daggers in order to silence the enemy.
]]></string>

    <string name="kasrkin_combat_daggers_description"><![CDATA[
Friendly **KASRKIN** operatives have the following
melee weapon:
]]></string>



    <!--Ploys-->
    <!--Strategy ploys-->
    <string name="elimination_pattern_lore"><![CDATA[
Having already outmanoeuvred the foe, the Kasrkin
attempt to fell their target in a single volley.
]]></string>

    <string name="elimination_pattern_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever a friendly **KASRKIN** operative is
shooting with a hot-shot weapon against an
operative that cannot retain any cover saves or
is being scanned (see **RECON-TROOPER**), that
weapon has the Piercing Crits 1 weapon rule, or
Piercing 1 instead if it is a hot-shot volley gun.
]]></string>

    <string name="engage_from_cover_lore"><![CDATA[
Kasrkin are used to being outnumbered and outgunned,
using cover to avoid incoming fire as they engage.
]]></string>

    <string name="engage_from_cover_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever an operative is shooting a friendly
**KASRKIN** operative thats in cover, you can
re-roll one of your defence dice.
]]></string>

    <string name="clearance_sweep_lore"><![CDATA[
The Kasrkin advance steadily towards their objectives,
clearing the battlefield of enemies quadrant
by quadrant.
]]></string>

    <string name="clearance_sweep_description"><![CDATA[
Place your Clearance Sweep marker in the
killzone. Whenever a friendly **KASRKIN**
operative within 5\" horizontally of that marker is
shooting an operative also within 5\" horizontally
of that marker, that friendly operatives weapons
have the Ceaseless weapon rule. In the Ready
step of the next Strategy phase, remove
that marker.
]]></string>

    <string name="relocate_lore"><![CDATA[
The Kasrkin are always on the move, advancing swiftly
across the battlefield to take up new firing positions.
]]></string>

    <string name="relocate_description"><![CDATA[
Select one friendly **KASRKIN** operative that is
more than 3\" from enemy operatives. That
operative, and each other friendly **KASRKIN**
operative that is both within 3\" of that operative
and more than 3\" from enemy operatives, can
immediately perform a free **Dash** action in an
order of your choice. You cannot use this ploy
during the first turning point.
]]></string>



    <!--Firefight ploys-->
    <string name="seize_the_initiative_lore"><![CDATA[
Kasrkin squads are bold and decisive, acting with speed
and clarity even in the confusion of battle.
]]></string>

    <string name="seize_the_initiative_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy at the start of the Firefight
phase. One friendly **KASRKIN** operative can
immediately perform a 1AP action for free, but it
cannot move during that action. You cannot use
this ploy if you are the player with initiative.
]]></string>

    <string name="cover_retreat_lore"><![CDATA[
Should a Kasrkin soldier need to retreat, their allies may
lay down a withering barrage of covering fire.
]]></string>

    <string name="cover_retreat_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy when a friendly **KASRKIN**
operative performs the **Fall Back** action while
visible to and within 6\" of another friendly
**KASRKIN** operative that is not within control
range of enemy operatives. After that friendly
operative has finished moving, but before
that **Fall Back** action ends, that other friendly
operative can immediately perform a free **Shoot**
action (you can change its order to **Engage** to
do so).
]]></string>

    <string name="neutralise_target_lore"><![CDATA[
Designating an exposed enemy operative as a priority
target, this operative levels their weapon and fires a
volley of rounds.
]]></string>

    <string name="neutralise_target_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy after rolling your attack dice
for a friendly **KASRKIN** operative, if it is shooting
an operative that either cannot retain any cover
saves or is being scanned (see **RECON-TROOPER**).
You can re-roll any of your attack dice.
]]></string>

    <string name="give_no_ground_lore"><![CDATA[
Hardened by a lifetime spent defending the Imperium
from the horrific denizens of the Eye of Terror, the
Kasrkin demonstrate unwavering discipline in the face
of the enemy.
]]></string>

    <string name="give_no_ground_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy during a friendly **KASRKIN**
operatives activation, or at the end of the
Firefight phase. Select one of your mission
markers or an objective marker. Until the end of
that activation or until the start of the next turning
point respectively, if the total APL of friendly
**KASRKIN** operatives that contest that marker
is 2, and the total APL of enemy operatives
that contest it is the same, friendly **KASRKIN**
operatives control that marker.
]]></string>

</resources>