<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <!--Death Korps-->


    <string name="deathkorps_bruiser_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive/ Firefight Phase

]]></string>

    <string name="deathkorps_bruiser_description"><![CDATA[

        Once per turning point, when this Operative is fighting or
                 retaliating, in the Resolve Attack Dice step, you can ignore the damage
                 inflicted on it from one normal success.\nIf this Operative is incapacitated
                 during the FIGHT action, you can strike the enemy Operative in that sequence
                 with one of your unresolved successes before this Operative is removed from the
                killzone.

]]></string>


    <string name="deathkorps_confidant_secondincommand_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive/Firefight phase

]]></string>

    <string name="deathkorps_confidant_secondincommand_description"><![CDATA[

        If a friendly WATCHMASTER Operative is incapacitated, you can use this rule. If you
                           do, until the end of the battle, this Operative can issue a GUARDSMAN ORDER as a
                          STRATEGIC GAMBIT(even though its not a WATCHMASTER operative).

]]></string>


    <string name="deathkorps_confidant_directive_usage"><![CDATA[

        Strategic Gambit

]]></string>

    <string name="deathkorps_confidant_directive_description"><![CDATA[

        Whenever this Operative is activated, if you havent used the Second in Command rule
                           during the battle, you can select one other ready friendly DEATH KORP Operative visible
                           and within 6\" of it. When this operative is expended, activate that other friendly
                           Operative before your opponent activates(if that Operative is a TROOPER, ignore its
                           Group Activation rule).

]]></string>


    <string name="deathkorps_medic_usage"><![CDATA[

        Pasive/ Firefight Phase

]]></string>

    <string name="deathkorps_medic_description"><![CDATA[

        The first time during each turning point, when another friendly DEATHKORPS Operative
                 would be incapacitated while visible and within 3\" of this operative, you can use this rule if
                 neither this nor the other friendly Operative is within control range of an enemy Operative
                .If you do, that friendly operative isnt incapacitated, has 1 wound remaining and cannot be
                 incapacitated for the remainder of the action.\nAfter that action, that friendly Operative can
                 inmediately perfrom a free Dash action, but must end that move within this Operatives control range
                . Substract 1 from this and the other Operatives APL stats until the end of their next activations
                , if this rule is used during that other Operative activation, its activation ends.\n
                You cannot use this rule if this operative is incapacitated, or if its a Shoot action and this
                 Operative would be a primary or secondary target.

]]></string>


    <string name="deathkorps_medikit_usage"><![CDATA[

        1 AP

]]></string>

    <string name="deathkorps_medikit_description"><![CDATA[

        Select one friendly DEATHKORPS Operative within this Operatives control range
                 to regain up to 2D3 lost wounds. It cannot be used on an Operative which benefit from the
                 rule Medic! this turning point.\n\nThis Operative Cannot perform this action while within
                control range of an enemy Operative.

]]></string>



    <string name="deathkorps_sapper_mine_usage"><![CDATA[

        Pasive/ Firefight Phase

]]></string>

    <string name="deathkorps_sapper_mine_description"><![CDATA[

        This Operative is carrying your Mine marker. It can perform the
                 Pick Up Marker action on that marker, and whenever it performs the Place
                 Marker action on that marker, it can perform a free Dash action.

]]></string>


    <string name="deathkorps_sapper_detonate_usage"><![CDATA[

        Special Weapon Rule

]]></string>

    <string name="deathkorps_sapper_detonate_description"><![CDATA[

        Dont select a valid target, shoot against each operative within 2"
             of your Mine marker, unless heavy terrain is wholly intervening between that
             Operative and that marker. Each valid target cannot be in cover or obscured
            . Roll for each Operative.\nThis weapon cannot be selected if your Mine marker
             is not in the killzone, after shooting this weapon the Mine marker is removed
             from the killzone. In a killzone that use close quarter rule, this weapon has
             Lethal 5+ weapon rule.

]]></string>

    <string name="deathkorps_spotter_usage"><![CDATA[

        1 APL/ Firefight Phase

]]></string>

    <string name="deathkorps_spotter_description"><![CDATA[

        **SUPPPORT.** Select one  enemy Operative visible to this Operative. Once
                           during this turning point, when a friendly DEATH KORPS Operative within
                           3\" of this operative is shooting that enemy Operative, you can use this effect
                          . If you do:\nThat friendly operatives range weapons have the Seek Light weapon rule.
                          \nThat enemy operative cannot be obscured.\n\nThis Operative CANNOT perform
                           this action while within control range of an enemy Operative.

]]></string>


    <string name="deathkorps_trooper_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive/ Firefight Phase

]]></string>

    <string name="deathkorps_trooper_description"><![CDATA[

        Whenever this Operative is expended, you MUST then activate another
                           ready friendly DEATH KORP TROOPER Operative(if able) before your
                           opponent activates. When that operative is expended, your opponent then
                           activates as normal(you cannot activate more than two Operatives before
                           your opponent with this rule).

]]></string>


    <string name="deathkorps_veteranguardsmen_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive/ Firefight Phase

]]></string>

    <string name="deathkorps_veteranguardsmen_description"><![CDATA[

        Whenever this Operative is activated, it can receive one
                           GUARDSMAN ORDER.

]]></string>


    <string name="deathkorps_veteran_bionics_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive/ Firefight Phase

]]></string>

    <string name="deathkorps_veteran_bionics_description"><![CDATA[

        Normal Dmg of 3 or more inflicts 1 less damage on this
                           Operative.

]]></string>


    <string name="deathkorps_vox_relayorders_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive/1 APL

]]></string>

    <string name="deathkorps_vox_relayorders_description"><![CDATA[

        Once per turning point, when this operative receives a GUARDSMAN ORDER
                          , if its not within control range of an enemy Operative, it can relay that
                           order. All friendly DEATH KORPS Operatives in the killzone receive that order,
                           this Operative then loses 1 APL until the end of its next activation.

]]></string>


    <string name="deathkorps_vox_signal_usage"><![CDATA[

        1 APL/ Firefight Phase

]]></string>

    <string name="deathkorps_vox_signal_description"><![CDATA[

        SUPPPORT. Select one other friendly DEATH KORPS Operative visible
                           and within 6\" of this Operative. Until the end of that Operatives
                           next activation, add 1 to its APL stat.\n\nThis Operative CANNOT perform
                           this action while within control range of an enemy Operative.

]]></string>


    <string name="deathkorps_watchmaster_adaptive_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive/Firefight phase

]]></string>

    <string name="deathkorps_watchmaster_adaptive_description"><![CDATA[

        If this Operative doesnt issue a Guardsman Order as a Strategic Gambit,
                           you can use the Inspirational Leadership Firefight ploy for 0CP during this
                           Operatives activation.

]]></string>


    <string name="deathkorps_watchmaster_bring_usage"><![CDATA[

        Strategic Gambit

]]></string>

    <string name="deathkorps_watchmaster_bring_description"><![CDATA[

        If this Operative is in the killzone. Select one enemy operative. Whenever a friendly
           DEATH KORP Operative is shooting, fighting or retaliating against that enemy Operative
          , that friendly Operatives weapons have the Punishing weapon rule.

]]></string>


    <string name="deathkorps_zealot_theemperor_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive/Firefight Phase

]]></string>

    <string name="deathkorps_zealot_theemperor_description"><![CDATA[

        Whenever an Operative is shooting this Operative, you can re-roll any of
                           your defence dice

]]></string>


    <string name="deathkorps_zealot_uplifting_usage"><![CDATA[

        Passive/ Firefight Phase

]]></string>

    <string name="deathkorps_zealot_uplifting_description"><![CDATA[

        SUPPPORT. Whenever a friendly DEATH KORPS Operative is within 3"
                           os this Operative, that friendly Operatives weapons have the
                           Severe weapon rule.

]]></string>

    <!--Faction Rules-->

    <string name="guardsman_orders_lore"><![CDATA[
The soldiers of the Death Korps of Krieg are
unquestioningly loyal to their officers, following barked
orders with a speed and efficiency that is the envy of
many other regiments.

]]></string>

    <string name="guardsman_orders_description"><![CDATA[
STRATEGIC GAMBIT and SUPPORT. A friendly
DEATH KORPS WATCHMASTER operative
can issue a GUARDSMAN ORDER. Whenever it
does, select one GUARDSMAN ORDER for all
friendly DEATH KORPS operatives within 6\" of it
to receive.\n
\n

Whenever a friendly operative receives a
GUARDSMAN ORDER, apply its rules until the end
of the turning point. Operatives cannot benefit
from more than one GUARDSMAN ORDER at
once; they only benefit from the most recent
order they received during the turning point.\n
\n
-TAKE AIM!\n
Ranged weapons of operatives that received
this order (excluding mortar barrage and remote
detonator) have the Ceaseless weapon rule.\n
\n
-FIX BAYONETS!\n
Melee weapons of operatives that received this
order have the Ceaseless weapon rule.\n
\n
-DIG IN!\n
Whenever an operative is shooting
a friendly operative thats received this order, if
you can retain any cover saves, you can re-roll
any of your defence dice results of one result (e.g.
results of 2).\n
\n
-MOVE! MOVE! MOVE!\n
Whenever an operative thats received this order
is performing the Reposition action, add 1\" to its
Move stat.
]]></string>

    <!--Equipment-->
    <string name="chronometer_lore"><![CDATA[
Krieg combat operations are performed to strict
schedules. Synchronised chronometers ensure
operatives adhere to the time frames laid down
by command.
]]></string>

    <string name="chronometer_description"><![CDATA[
Once per battle **STRATEGIC GAMBIT** in the first
or second turning point. Each friendly **DEATH
KORPS** operative wholly within your territory
can immediately perform a free **Dash** action in an
order of your choice, but each that does so must
end that move closer to an opponents drop zone
or killzone edge.\n
\n
You cannot use this **STRATEGIC GAMBIT** and
the Regroup strategy ploy during the same
turning point.

]]></string>

    <string name="comm_beads_lore"><![CDATA[
Vox-casters and receivers allow Death Korps soldiers
to remain in contact even as they are separated in the
confusion of battle.
]]></string>

    <string name="comm_beads_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever a friendly **DEATH KORPS
WATCHMASTER** or friendly **DEATH KORPS
CONFIDANT** operative issues a **GUARDSMAN
ORDER**, you can use this rule. If you do, instead
of each friendly **DEATH KORPS** operative within
6\" of it receiving that order, you can select one
friendly **DEATH KORPS** operative to receive
that order.
]]></string>

    <string name="hand_axes_lore"><![CDATA[
Issued primarily as tools rather than weapons, these
sharp-bladed axes can be utilised in melee should close
confines prevent the use of bayonets.
]]></string>

    <string name="hand_axes_description"><![CDATA[
Friendly DEATH KORPS operatives have the
following melee weapon:
]]></string>

    <string name="gas_bombardment_lore"><![CDATA[
Calling for artillery support, the Death Korps request
a chemical barrage, knowing full well that even
enviro-sealed uniforms will not protect them from the
poisonous fumes.
]]></string>

    <string name="gas_bombardment_description"><![CDATA[
Once per battle **STRATEGIC GAMBIT**. Place
your Gas marker in the killzone; it cannot be
placed underneath Vantage terrain. Whenever
an operative is within 3\" of that marker, subtract
1 from its APL stat. In the Ready step of the next
Strategy phase, remove that marker. Note that
an operatives APL stat is only changed while its
within 3\" of that marker. If it moves more than
3\" from that marker, its APL stat is no longer
changed by this rule.
]]></string>
    <!--Ploys-->

    <!--Stategy ploys-->
    <string name="siege_warfare_lore"><![CDATA[
Death Korps infantry are at home in the dreadful grind of
siege warfare, repelling their foes with overlapping fields
of withering fire.
]]></string>

    <string name="siege_warfare_description"><![CDATA[
Friendly **DEATH KORPS** operatives ranged
weapons have the Saturate and Accurate 1
weapon rules.
]]></string>

    <string name="take_cover_lore"><![CDATA[
Used to fighting in the close confines of trenches and
tunnels, Krieg soldiers make excellent use of whatever
meagre cover they can find.
]]></string>

    <string name="take_cover_description"><![CDATA[
Whenever an operative is shooting a friendly
**DEATH KORPS** operative, if you can retain any
cover saves, improve that friendly operatives
Save stat by 1.
]]></string>

    <string name="clear_the_line_lore"><![CDATA[
Should the enemy break through, the soldiers of Krieg
are disciplined enough to retain their composure and
repel the foe.
]]></string>

    <string name="clear_the_line_description"><![CDATA[
Friendly **DEATH KORPS** operatives melee
weapons have the Accurate 1 weapon rule.
Whenever a friendly **DEATH KORPS** operative is
fighting wholly within your territory, or whenever
its retaliating, its melee weapons also have the
Severe weapon rule.
]]></string>

    <string name="regroup_lore"><![CDATA[
Even in the confusion of combat, the Death Korps of
Krieg retain their focus, returning to formation as they
destroy the enemy with accurate las fire.
]]></string>

    <string name="regroup_description"><![CDATA[
**SUPPORT.** Select one friendly **DEATH KORPS**
operative thats more than 3\" from enemy
operatives. Each other friendly **DEATH KORPS**
operative within 5\" of that operative and not
within control range of enemy operatives can
immediately perform a free **Dash** action in an
order of your choice, but each that does so must
end that move closer to that operative. Note that
a Comms Device from universal equipment only
affects the second distance of this rule.\n
\n
You cannot use this ploy and the Chronometer
faction equipment **STRATEGIC GAMBIT** during
the same turning point.
]]></string>
    <!--Firefight ploys-->

    <string name="inspirational_leadership_lore"><![CDATA[
The greatest officers lead by example, issuing orders
with calm precision even as they cut down their foes.
]]></string>

    <string name="inspirational_leadership_description"><![CDATA[
**SUPPORT**. Use this firefight ploy during a friendly
**DEATH KORPS WATCHMASTER** or **DEATH
KORPS CONFIDANT** operatives activation,
before or after it performs an action. It issues a
**GUARDSMAN ORDER**.
]]></string>

    <string name="combined_arms_lore"><![CDATA[
Precisely coordinated fire is capable of taking down
even the most potent of enemies.
]]></string>

    <string name="combined_arms_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy after rolling your attack dice
for a friendly **DEATH KORPS** operative, if its
shooting an enemy operative thats been shot by
another friendly **DEATH KORPS** operative during
this turning point. You can re-roll any of your
attack dice.
]]></string>

    <string name="in_life_shame_lore"><![CDATA[
The Cult of Krieg demand sacrifice in the name of
the Emperor, so those who are yet to give their lives
must atone by achieving ever greater feats upon
the battlefield.
]]></string>

    <string name="in_life_shame_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy when a friendly **DEATH
KORPS** operative is activated and given an
Engage order. It receives every **GUARDSMAN
ORDER**. This takes precedence over the normal
rule that operatives cannot benefit from more
than one **GUARDSMAN ORDER** at once.
]]></string>

    <string name="in_death_atonement_lore"><![CDATA[
All soldiers of Krieg are destined to die in battle. The
Cult of Sacrifice teaches that in death they will earn
forgiveness for the sins of their forebears.
]]></string>

    <string name="in_death_atonement_description"><![CDATA[
Use this firefight ploy when a ready friendly
**DEATH KORPS** operative is incapacitated, if it
isnt within control range of enemy operatives.
Before its removed from the killzone, it can
immediately perform one free action and you
can change its order to do so. Note that friendly
operative is injured for the duration of that action.
]]></string>

</resources>