<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <!--/Keywords-->

    <string name="keyword_accurate">
        <![CDATA[You can retain You can retain X Accurate results as normal successful before rolling dice.]]>

    </string>
    <string name="keyword_balanced">
         <![CDATA[ You can re-roll one attack die.]]>

     </string>
    <string name="keyword_blast">
    <![CDATA[The target you select for a shoot action becomes the Primary target, and every other operative
    within X Blast distance and visible to the Primary Target becomes the Secondary targets
    (Regardless of their order).
    Resolve the shoot action for the Primary target, then roll another
    shoot action for every Secondary Target (You have to roll dice for every valid target) if the
    Primary target was Obscure and/or in cover, the Secondary targets will have those modifiers as well.]]>
    </string>
    <string name="keyword_brutal">
         <![CDATA[ Your opponent can only parry with critical successes.]]>
     </string>
    <string name="keyword_ceaseless">
       <![CDATA[You can re-roll all attack dice showing the same result(Ex: all dice with a result of 2)]]>
    </string>
    <string name="keyword_concealed_position">
        <![CDATA[ This weapon can be used once while Concealed without changing order.]]>
     </string>
    <string name="keyword_devastating">
        <![CDATA[Critical hits inflict immediate damage equal to the Devastating value, the dice are
        not discarded.
        If theres Range associate with the keyword, inflict that damage
        each other operative in that distance.]]>
    </string>
    <string name="keyword_heavy">
        <![CDATA[An operative cannot use this weapon if it moved during its activation,
        and it cannot move after performing a Shoot action with this weapon.

        If marked Heavy (Reposition), Reposition is the only movement action
        allowed that still permits shooting in the same activation.

        An operative cannot use Guard with a Heavy weapon if these conditions are not met.]]>
    </string>
    <string name="keyword_hot">
        <![CDATA[After an operative shoots with this weapon, roll one D6, if the result
         is equal or greater than the Hit stat nothing happens, if the roll is less than
         the Hit stat, duplicate the value and deal that amount of damage to the friendly
        operative who made the shoot action.

         If you hit multiple targets, Ex: Blast. Still roll only one D6.]]>
    </string>
    <string name="keyword_lethal">
        <![CDATA[Your successes equal or greater to Lethal x value are Critical successes.]]>
    </string>
    <string name="keyword_limited">
        <![CDATA[After an operative uses this weapon x number of times, it cannot use this weapon
                again, if it hits multiple targets, Ex: Blast/Torrent. still treat it
                as only one use.]]>
    </string>
    <string name="keyword_obscure">
        <![CDATA[Whenever an Operative Shoot another Operative while this is Obscure, all Critical
                successes will become Normal successes, any rule around Critical success is ignored
                (Ex: Devastating, Piercing Crits, Punishing).]]>
    </string>
    <string name="keyword_psychic">
        <![CDATA[This action or weapon is a psychic attack.]]>
    </string>
    <string name="keyword_piercing">
        <![CDATA[The defender picks one less dice based on the Piercing X value.]]>
    </string>
    <string name="keyword_piercing_Crits">
        <![CDATA[The defender picks one less dice based on the Piercing Crits X value, if you score a
        Critical success.]]>
    </string>
    <string name="keyword_punishing">
        <![CDATA[If you retain any critical successes, you can change one failed dice into one success
        normal attack.]]>
    </string>
    <string name="keyword_range">
        <![CDATA[Only operatives within X inches can be targeted.]]>
    </string>
    <string name="keyword_relentless">
        <![CDATA[You can re-roll all attack dice.]]>
    </string>
    <string name="keyword_rending">
        <![CDATA[Convert one normal hit into a critical when retaining a critical.]]>
    </string>
    <string name="keyword_saturate">
        <![CDATA[The defender cannot retain cover saves.]]>
    </string>
    <string name="keyword_seek_light">
        <![CDATA[For the purpose of selecting a valid target for a shoot action, you can
                 select operatives in Conceal if they are being cover by light terrain. This
                 does not prevent Cover Saves if any.]]>
    </string>
    <string name="keyword_seek">
        <![CDATA[For the purpose of selecting a valid target for a shoot action,
        you can select operatives in Conceal. This does not prevent any Cover Saves if any.]]>
    </string>
    <string name="keyword_severe">
        <![CDATA[If you do not make any Critical success, you can change one Normal success
                 into a Critical success, any rule such as Devastating or Piercing Crits X is
                applied accordingly, but it cannot be combine in any way with the rules Punishing
                 or Rending, Ex: You cant just have 2 free Crits lmao.]]>
    </string>
    <string name="keyword_shock">
        <![CDATA[The first time you strike with a Critical success, discard one of your
                 opponents unresolved Normal success, if the opponent has no more Normal
                 Successes, discard one of its Critical successes if any.]]>
    </string>
    <string name="keyword_silent">
        <![CDATA[This weapon can be used while having a Conceal order.]]>
    </string>
    <string name="keyword_stun">
        <![CDATA[If you retain any Critical success with this weapon, the enemy operative loses 1 Apl
        until the start of its next activation.]]>
    </string>
    <string name="keyword_torrent">
        <![CDATA[Select one valid target, this will be the Primary target, then select any
                 number of secondary targets if they are valid as well and, if they are within
                 Torrent X value range of the Primary objective. You cant select enemy targets
                 in Control range of a friendly operative.
                Shoot this weapon against all of them, roll separately for each.]]>
    </string>


</resources>