<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <!--AOD-->
  <string name="heroic_leader_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive/Once per turning point
]]></string>

        <string name="heroic_leader_description"><![CDATA[
        You can do one of the following:\n
            \n
            -Use a Firefight ploy for 0CP if this is the specified **ANGEL OF DEATH** (excluding Command Re-roll).\n
            \n
            -Use the Combat Doctrine strategy ploy when you activate a friendly **ANGEL OF DEATH** Operative if this Operative is in the killzone and isnt within control
            range of an enemy Operative (pay its CP cost as normal). Note that you cannot do so if you have already used that ploy during this turning point.\n
            \n
            -Used the Adjust Doctrine Firefight ploy for 0CP if this Operative is in the killzone and isnt within control range of enemy Operatives.
]]></string>

      <string name="iron_halo_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive/Once per battle
]]></string>

        <string name="iron_halo_description"><![CDATA[
       When an attack dice inflicts Normal Dmg on this Operative, you can ignore that inflicted damage.
]]></string>

          <string name="assault_doctrine_warfare_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
]]></string>

        <string name="assault_doctrine_warfare_description"><![CDATA[
       You can do each of the following once per battle:\n
       \n
            -Whenever you would use the Combat Doctrine strategy ploy and then select Assault, if this Operative is in the killzone, it costs you 0CP.\n
            \n
            -Whenever you would use the Combat Doctrine strategy ploy and then select Tactical, if this Operative is in the killzone, it costs you 0CP.
]]></string>


     <string name="intercessor_doctrine_warfare_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
]]></string>

        <string name="intercessor_doctrine_warfare_description"><![CDATA[
       You can do each of the following once per battle:\n
       \n
            -Whenever you would use the Combat Doctrine strategy ploy and then select Devastator, if this Operative is in the killzone, it costs you 0CP.\n
            \n
            -Whenever you would use the Combat Doctrine strategy ploy and then select Tactical, if this Operative is in the killzone, it costs you 0CP.
]]></string>

          <string name="chapter_veteran_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
]]></string>

        <string name="chapter_veteran_description"><![CDATA[
       At the end of the Select Operative step, if this Operative is selected for deployment, select one additional **CHAPTER TACTIC** for it to have for the battle.
            Unlike the primary or secondary, you dont have to select the same one for each battle.
]]></string>

         <string name="aod_grenadier_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
]]></string>

        <string name="aod_grenadier_description"><![CDATA[
       This Operative can use frag and krak grenades (see universal equipment). Doing so doesnt count towards any limited uses you have. Whenever its doing so,
            improve the Hit stat of that weapon by 1.
]]></string>

         <string name="aod_camo_cloak_usage"><![CDATA[
        Passive
]]></string>

        <string name="aod_camo_cloak_description"><![CDATA[
       Whenever an Operative is shooting this Operative, ignore the Saturate weapon rule. This Operative has the Stealthy **CHAPTER TACTIC**. If you selected that **CHAPTER TACTIC**
            , you can do both of its options (retain two cover saves - one normal and one critical success).
]]></string>

         <string name="aod_optics_usage"><![CDATA[
 1AP
]]></string>

        <string name="aod_optics_description"><![CDATA[
       Until the start of this Operatives next activation, whenever its shooting, enemy Operatives cannot be obscured.\n\n

            This Operative cannot perform this while within control range of an enemy Operative.
]]></string>


    <!--Faction Rules-->

    <string name="astartes_lore"><![CDATA[
        These genetically modified superhumans are made for one purpose: war.
]]></string>

        <string name="astartes_description"><![CDATA[
        During each friendly **ANGEL OF DEATH** Operatives activation, it can perform either two **Shoot* actions or two **Fight** actions. If its two
            **Shoot** actions, a Bolt weapon must be selected for at least one of them, and if its a Bolt Sniper Rifle or Heavy Bolter, 1 additional AP must be
            spent for the second action if both actions are using that weapon.\n\n

            Each friendly **ANGEL OF DEATH** Operative can counteract regardless of its order.
]]></string>

        <string name="chapter_tactics_lore"><![CDATA[
        Each Space Marine Chapter is a martial brotherhood with its own combat philosophies, suited to the unique skills and temperaments of its battle-brothers.
            These tenets of war may be clothed in esoteric rituals built up over thousands of years, but remain as brutally effective as when they were first laid down.
]]></string>

        <string name="chapter_tactics_description"><![CDATA[
        When selecting your kill team, select a Primary and secondary **CHAPTER TACTIC** for friendly **ANGEL OF DEATH** Operatives to gain for the battle. Multiple instances
            of the same **CHAPTER TACTIC** arent cumulative.\n\n

            If you are playing a series of games or a tournament, you must select the same **CHAPTER TACTIC** for every battle, you can still change the secondary with the Adaptive
            Tactics strategy ploy.\n\n

                        ---1.AGGRESIVE\n
            This operatives melee weapons have the Rending weapon rule.\n
                        ---2.DUELLER\n
            Whenever this Operative is fighting or retaliating, each of your normal successes can block one unresolved critical success (unless the enemy has the Brutal weapon rule).\n
                        ---3.RESOLUTE\n
            You can ignore any changes to this Operatives APL stat and it isnt affected by enemy Operatives Shock weapon rule.\n
                        ---4.STEALTHY\n
            Whenever an Operative is shooting this Operative, if you can retain any cover saves, you can retain one additional cover save, or you can retain one cover save
            as critical success instead. This isnt cumulative with improved cover saves from Vantage terrain.\n
                        ---5.MOBILE\n
            *This operative can perform the **Fall Back** action for 1 less AP.\n
            *This operative can perform the **Charge** action while within control range of an enemy Operative, and can leave that Operatives control range to do so 
            (but then normal requirements for that move apply).\n
                        ---6.HARDY\n
            Whenever an Operative is shooting this Operative, defence dice results of 5+ are critical successes. Whenever this Operative is retaliating, the first
            time an attack dice inflicts Normal Dmg of 3 or more on this Operative during that sequence, that dice inflicts 1 less damage on it.\n
                        ---7.SHARPSHOOTER\n
            Whenever this Operative is shooting during an activation in which it hasnt performed the **Charge, Fall Back** or **Reposition** action, its bolt weapon has the Acurrate 1
            and Severe weapons rules.\n
                        ---8.SIEGE SPECIALIST\n
            This Operatives ranged weapons have the Saturate weapon rule. Whenever this Operative is fighting or retaliating, enemy Operatives cannot assist.\n
]]></string>

  
    <!--Equipment-->

        <string name="purity_seals_lore"><![CDATA[
        Awarded by the Chapters Chaplains, purity seals are inscribed with blessings and inspire the bearer to fight with increased vigour.
]]></string>

          <string name="purity_seals_description"><![CDATA[

        Once per turning point, when a friendly **ANGEL OF DEATH** Operative is shooting, fighting or retaliating, if you roll two two or more fails, you
            can discard one of them to retain another as a normal success instead.

]]></string>

  <string name="chapter_reliquaries_lore"><![CDATA[
        Many Space Marines bear macabre relics taken from the bodies of their fallen. Those who bear these inspirational items fight all the harder to honour
    the sacrifice of their battle-brothers.
]]></string>

          <string name="chapter_reliquaries_description"><![CDATA[
        You can use the Wrath of Vengeance firefight ploy for 0CP if the specified friendly Operative has an **Engage** order
]]></string>

  <string name="tilting_shields_lore"><![CDATA[
    As well as displaying company colours and personal heraldry, a Space Marines tilting plate serves to protect the bearer in the press of melee combat.
]]></string>

          <string name="tilting_shields_description"><![CDATA[
    Once per turning point, when a friendly **ANGEL OF DEATH** Operative is fighting or retaliating, after your opponent rolls their attack dice, but before re-rolls, you can use 
            this rule. If you do, your opponent cannot retain attack dice results of less than 6 as critical successes during that sequence (ex. Lethal, Rending or Severe).
]]></string>

  <string name="auspex_lore"><![CDATA[
    Auspexes come in many forms. These scanning devices can detect motion, analyse atmospheric conditions and reveal heat signatures.
]]></string>

          <string name="auspex_description"><![CDATA[
    Once per turning point, when a friendly **ANGEL OF DEATH** Operative performs the **Shoot** action, and you are selecting a valid target, you can use this rule.
            If you do, until the end of the activation/counteraction, enemy Operatives within 8\" of that friendly Operative cannot be Obscured.
]]></string>
  

    <!--Ploys-->
    <!--Strategy ploys-->
    
 <string name="combat_doctrine_lore"><![CDATA[
   Space Marines hold the teachings of the Codex Astartes in highest esteem, employing its flexible combat doctrines to annihilate their enemies.
]]></string>

<string name="combat_doctrine_description"><![CDATA[
    Select one **COMBAT DOCTRINE** from those presented below. Whenever a friendly **ANGEL OF DEATH** Operative is x, its weapons have the Balanced weapon rule. X is the 
     **COMBAT DOCTRINE** you selected.\n\n
    - **DEVASTATOR DOCTRINE:** Shooting an Operative more than 6\" from it.\n
    - **TACTICAL DOCTRINE:** Shooting an Operative within 6\" of it.\n
    - **ASSAULT DOCTRINE:** Fighting or retaliating.
]]></string>

     <string name="no_fear_lore"><![CDATA[
   Space Marines possess extraordinary courage and are utterly unflinching in the face of terrifying horros and overwhelming odds.
]]></string>

<string name="no_fear_description"><![CDATA[
    You can ignore any changes to the stats of friendly  **ANGEL OF DEATH** Operatives from being injured.
]]></string>

     <string name="adaptive_tactics_lore"><![CDATA[
   There are few more tactically flexible warriors than the Adeptus Astartes. Supplementing the teachings of the Codex Astartes with their own experience, 
         Space Marines may adjust their strategies at a moments notice.
]]></string>

<string name="adaptive_tactics_description"><![CDATA[
    Change your secondary **CHAPTER TACTIC**. Note this ploy only lasts until the end of the turning point.
]]></string>

     <string name="indomitus_lore"><![CDATA[
   This is the Era Indomitus. The Imperium wages galaxy-spanning crusades to drive back the horrors that plague it, and the battle-brothers of the Adeptus Astartes 
         are spurred on by this righteous purpose.
]]></string>

<string name="indomitus_description"><![CDATA[
    Whenever an Operative is shooting a friendly **ANGEL OF DEATH** Operative, if you roll two or more fails, you can discard one of them to retain another as a normal success instead.
]]></string>


    
    <!--Firefight ploys-->

 <string name="adjust_doctrine_lore"><![CDATA[
   Adeptus Astartes kill teams adapt their strategies on the fly to overcome the foe. Swifly traded hand signals and abrupt vox exchanges herald a shift in doctrine.
]]></string>

<string name="adjust_doctrine_description"><![CDATA[
    Use this Firefight ploy during a friendly **ANGEL OF DEATH** Operatives activation, before or after it performs an action. If you have used the Combat Doctrine 
    strategy ploy during this turning point, change the **COMBAT DOCTRINE** you selected.
]]></string>

     <string name="transhuman_physiology_lore"><![CDATA[
   The genetically modified physiology of a Space Marine is capable of resisting wounds that would kill a lesser being.
]]></string>

<string name="transhuman_physiology_description"><![CDATA[
    Use this Firefight ploy when an Operative is shooting a friendly **ANGEL OF DEATH** Operative, in the Roll Defence Dice Step. You can retain one of your normal successes as a critical
    success instead.
]]></string>

     <string name="shock_assault_lore"><![CDATA[
   The Adeptus Astartes strike with exceptional speed and strength, the roar of chainswords and brutal assaults spelling death for their foes.
]]></string>

<string name="shock_assault_description"><![CDATA[
    Use this Firefight ploy when a friendly **ANGEL OF DEATH** Operative is performing the **Fight** action during an activation in which it performed the **Charge** action,
    at the start of the Resolve Attack Dice step. Until the end of that action:\n\n

    -Its melee weapon has the Shock weapon rule.
    -The first time you strike during that sequence, inflict 1 additional damage (to a maximum of 7).
]]></string>

     <string name="wrath_of_vengeance_lore"><![CDATA[
   When roused to anger, a battle-brother of the Adeptus Astartes may be spurred to acts of extraordinary strength and athleticism.
]]></string>

<string name="wrath_of_vengeance_description"><![CDATA[
    Use this Firefight ploy when a friendly **ANGEL OF DEATH** Operative is counteracting. It can perform an additional 1AP action for free during that action, but both actions must be different.
]]></string>
    

</resources>
